(Sparkle~)
Vtuber Self Introduction Q&A
(Yaaay~)
Well, then. Let's go!
Ready, set!
What's your name?
Valentine Melori (LN-FN)
How would you liked to be addressed?
Melo-chan!
What type of VTuber are you?
A Tech Wizardess VTuber
When's your birthday?
July 31st
How old are you?
Take a guess~ (Y2K)
What's your gender?
I'm a female. (Transgender)
How tall are you?
168cm (iroha, wordplay)
Where are you from?
It's a secret.
What's your charming point?
Being in chill-mode.
I know this is sudden, please do an impression!
Bi-... big bwothwer?
*Different vibes, but you still get it right?
Where are you active?
On YouTube!
What's your starting greeting?
Kon-Melo!
What's your ending greeting?
Otsu-Melo!
What're your fan emojis?
💫 🪄　（Sparkling Bling~!）
What's your Live hashtag?
Don't have one yet.
What's your fanart hashtag?
#JankyMelori
What's your fan name?
Fellow Apprentices
What's your favorite color?
Pink (#FFAAFF)
What's your hobby?
Information Technology.
What are you good at?
Causing bugs
In a phrase, confess your love!
I... I LOVE YOU!
What's your favorite food?
Ramen.
What's your favorite drink?
Tea.
What's your favorite manga?
Flying Witch!
What's your favorite anime?
GochiUsa (Is The Order A Rabbit?)
What's your favorite game?
Genshin Impact
What's your favorite music?
Anything goes for me.
What're your weakness?
My Japanese (knowledge).
Who do you admire?
IRyS!
What's your dream?
Money!
Lastly, got any words for everyone? Let's go!♪
"Ta'da! I got a story to tell,
Care to give it an ear?"
Be sure to check out Melori's channel~
Let's play together someday!
(Yaaay~)
See yaaa~