Eyyy~
Hello, hello!
KonMelo, KonMelo, KonMelo!
Hello, hello, how y'all doing?
Happy Halloween in Japanese time, that is.
Y'all doing fine?
Well, I'm not sure about myself though.
Because…
I'm gonna be turning the lights off.
So, it's going to be a
little bit crazy, so…
Ahem.
I have not streamed any horror games
before, but I wanna start somewhere.
If I were to describe how I'm
feeling, it's kind of a mixed feeling.
Because I bought this
game through donators.
Big shoutout to
PapayaUriah, Chi, and Koeil.
For donating to me on Ko-fi.
Right, without further ado,
let's get right into the game.
Phew
I'm getting so nervous right now.
Because it's like, I'm half expected and
half not expected, that kind of thing.
Here goes nothing.
So, here we go.
Begin.
So…
We're the investigator.
A recorder.
Okay, cool.
What do we have here?
So, I assume this investi- this
guy came over here for a trip.
Excerpt from Grandfather's document.
"Aogami today".
"The repeated landslides, ghost
sightings, and reports of missing persons
have led to a steady decline in
Aogami's population over the years.
As residents refuse to
live in such a cursed town.
They say the town of Aogami has been beset
by landslides throughout its history.
This could be due to excessive
deforestation or weak soil.
But the residents of old Aogami
believed
that it was the anger of the mountain spirits."
Who's that?
Yes, yes, yes, coming.
What the fuck?
What the shit?
The door just…
Anyone back here?
No?
Okay.
Somebody's calling.
FWURGH!
Oy, Jesus.
Who is it?
UWARGH!
Okay.
Who was that?
Where is this?
It's a school.
"The Rumor of the Art Prep Room.
They say that a long time ago, a female
student who was obsessed with painting
something no one else could…
used her own…
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
The lights.
The lights are flickering.
I don't understand one thing.
What is with the amount of leftover
school bags and papers in Aogami High?
What's going on there?
Whoa.
That little jitter.
That little jitter really
had me for a second...
More leftover bags.
What's going on?
Okay,
this is dark.
What happened here?
Uh, excuse me, miss?
What are you doing in
the middle of the night?
At school...?
Doko [Where]?
Where you at?
I hear dialogues.
What do you mean by "you
won't know until you hear it"?
Whoa!
It opened itself.
What's this?
That's them!
WURGHH!
Okay.
Okay, what the fuck?
Dare [Who]?
Okay...
Holy fuck.
Okay, that-
Uh, 'scuse me?
Uh, who could you be?
Okay.
Okay!
Whoa.
What?
Wait, wha-?
What happened here?
Why-
Why are we caved in?
It happened again!
Jesus...
Oh no, things are turning
a little sideways now.
Oh.
More and more of the
building is going down.
Oh no...
UWARH!
Okay!
What...
What...?
What- What was that?
What was that???
Oy
Even more of the back is gone!
Are we able to open this door?
Uhhh.
Uhhh...
Okay...
I suppose we're supposed to approach her.
Uh, miss?
Uhhh.
UWARRGGGHH!!!!
Okay.
Wait.
What are we expecting?
No one?
Who
the fuck-
Don't tell me
She's there...
Wait, what???
We're not home anymore.
Where do you think this is?
It's a school.
Bags, briefcases...
I just realized that there's a
picture of a shrine in every room.
What is going on?
Scattered chairs and tables...
Okay.
Alright.
It's just a game.
It's just a game, Mel.
Someone's crying...
Oh no, there's no lights.
There's no lights to this one.
You!
It's you again!
What are you doing here?
Why are you here?
What are you in here for?
What's your purpose???
Why?
Blood...
It's the paint tool.
'Kay.
UWERGH!
That-
Whoa.
What's this, a massacre?
What is going on here?
Okay.
It sounds like she ran away.
Why is this door left open?
What?
Wh-
Who was it?
What is it?
I heard steps.
It's-
complete darkness.
We're at a shrine.
And her again.
That girl.
That girl from earlier.
Is this the same girl?
Doesn't look like it though.
Hm?
What...
really happened?
Now that I think about it.
Wait!
I see a leg!
Something's not right.
Did you see that?
There was a leg over there!
Like, in the corner!
Like-
Somebody-
Somebody was here!
Why did my bathroom open?
Wha-?
It's them again.
What...
the hell?
Wait!
That girl!
That girl in the background!
She disappeared!
Where's this coming from?
What did I do?
Who is it this time?
Wait.
Wha-?
We're in a train now...
Okay.
A very normal…
train.
I suppose?
What?
What's going on over there?
Why is there some hitting sounds going on?
What's sparking there?
What?
UWARGHHH!!!
Oh my God...
I was-
I was not expecting anyone, really...
"I see you don't do well
with horror after that?"
I- I- I guess so.
I guess you can put it that way.
But…
It's kinda the-
There's kinda a reason why I-
I- I- I hesitated when I-
When I hesitated when-
When being suggested a horror game.
So this game kinda is
going to prove my point.
Oh, we're supposed to follow her!
Okay, we're supposed to follow the...
"MelLUL A little girl pushes you down."
Oi!
Oi oi oi oi oi!
Careful with your wording, alright?
Th' train's stopping.
Light's goes out.
It's her again!
That-
That girl from the beginning.
No, not the beginning.
Th- Th- The second girl.
That we see in the game.
She's gone.
Uhhh.
She's slamming the window...
Could she be-
Yuka?
Uhhh.
Ano [umm]...UGHH!
Okay.
Alright.
I-
I guess it could be vital to the story.
I guess.
There's-
There's two more person here.
Uh.
Ano [umm]...
Su-
Sumimasen [Excuse me].
The slamming stopped.
We're back in…
Aogami High School.
Again.
A couple of girls.
Okay.
There's another person.
Uwah!
Ow, my eyes.
That was-
That flashbang though.
Wait.
Another girl missing.
From that picture earlier.
That we saw earlier.
That picture.
Also, where's my flashlight?
What happened to my flashlight?
My flashlight's gone.
Oh no.
Oh no, it's getting darker in here now.
We're supposed to use the
camera flash, I suppose,
To find out where-
What we're supposed to look at.
It's you again!
Uh!
Yuka-san?
What???
We're in the trains again.
How much film do we have?
What the heck?
How many rolls of film do we have?
Just- Just to pull off
this amount of flash.
Woah-
Who-
Who in the world was that?!
Who are you?!
Tell me!
What business do you have here?!
It's almost like this
guy is going through-
Five stages of grief.
UWARGHHH!!!
Who the fuck are you?!
Flashlight.
UWARGHHH!!!
Who-
Wait...
The camera's gone!
We're back to our flashlights.
Yuka?
She's getting closer!
And closer!
Yu-...
UWERH!!!
What?!
Wait!
What's going on?
You?
Her?
Hueh?
It's repeating itself!
Wha-
Hueh?
Nani (what)?
What's going on???
UWARGHHH!!!
What the fuck?!
Who's that dude?!
Wha-
We're at the shrine again.
Who-
Who's that?
Who are you?!
UWERGHHH!!!
Oh, Namo Amitabha!
Hm?
Eh?
Ending 1, 404 not found.
Wait, there's multiple
endings to this game?
Archives.
There's more to this.
She's the-
She's the painter girl!
Whuoa!
What the fuck is this visual?
Holy crap.
So there's more to this, hold on.
So that's the first ending.
So will we actually-
Will we actually find a different ending?
If we actually start the
game again right now.
Are we expected to have a-
A different-
UERGH!
Okay, it's that-
It's that-
It's that scene earlier.
Maybe we are on the wrong chapter...
Presumably...
Had we not done certain things
that we're supposed to do,
will it take us to a different end?
"You will keep unlocked
archives and chapters."
"Delete current inventory?"
Okay.
Let's try running the whole game
with the knowledge of the inventory.
Wait- Oh my god, I went
to press "Continue",
I'm supposed to press
"Chapters" or something.
Oh wait, wait, wait.
Since we're in game,
maybe we can see our
inventories from here.
What was in our inventory the whole time?
Oh, so that's-
So the notes are the inventory.
So we got the first ending.
Still getting me confused right now.
What part are we missing?
'right.