Previously on Hololive Error.
Let's try to get the second ending.
Oh it's about god fucking damn time.
"Note from a certain-"
She's here.
Lights went out and I heard steps.
Who the fuck are you?!?!
Right?
WARGH?!
Woah!
What is she doing here?
Okay, it's different now.
What is it this time?
Oh no.
So this is everything together in one place.
What's going on?
This is a whole lot different than the first run.
And there's a note here.
UWARGH!
This is way different than I thought.
Woah.
Was this all...
just a dream?
She's here.
Woah.
Okay, fuck me, that.
I still don't understand.
I'm gonna relax, clear my head.
This is not the end yet.
So today, the goal is going to be, we're gonna try to complete the third ending.
I hope this goes well.
So a while ago, I read up on the internet about
which chapter I should be in to get the third ending.
But I kind of read halfway and I thought,
"maybe I shouldn't do this".
Maybe I should go legit.
There was a tip that I read before I closed the tab though.
The tip says, investigate everything.
Like just discover, pick up everything.
When they meant everything, they meant everything.
Okay.
Best wishes to myself for this.
Here we go.
Apparently you're allowed to walk back.
So if you do walk back, you might be able to find hints that might help.
So I'm gonna try to strive for that.
I've went two runs and I completely forgot about it.
Also one thing I did notice.
The man.
Us.
We're walking in such a hilarious motion.
Are you seein' thing?
Now let's do the final sanity check.
I did get all the picture though.
Thumbs up.
Nice.
For a second, I actually thought I saw a note here.
Cause I saw something like a little boxy thingy.
I don't even know why it still gets me.
But I do know that the aesthetics of this place has turned into…
Past time Aogami.
Ah, there she is.
So the goal is to pick up every single note.
Right.
So this is the note that she dropped.
Chat: "Still we getting ending three so it doesn't matter here."
I forgot about that as well.
I swear I've forgotten about everything about my first and second run.
After one sleep.
The moment I sleep, I just completely forgot about the endings.
About everything I need to know about the lore of the game.
Now we walk up to her and she's gonna crawl up to us like…
BLBLBLBLBLBLBLBL.
Like Spider-Woman.
"Imagine the one voicing the guy is Yagoo"
YAGOO: Hello everyone.
Yagoo.
YAGOO: I am Motoaki Tanigo, CEO of COVER Corporation.
Chat: "To be fair, the model in the game is kinda eh.
But the story motive is pretty good."
Yeah, the model is pretty eh.
But, you know, Shino's model.
Pretty much is Tokino Sora but still.
Hella cute though.
Actually cute.
Chat: "Wait till you see the cutscene of ending three.
The model there is so weird."
Why is it?
No, actually you know what?
Don't tell me anything.
That's what I wanna know but don't tell me.
Just yet.
Chat: "It should turn bloody first."
Yeah, the room should turn bloody first.
And here we are.
This is where it begins.
The crazy part is I'm actually kinda scared.
Even though I went through this path for like two, three times now.
And the chair should come out.
Just going wild.
And then there she is.
Spazzing out.
I still think it's kinda impressive, you know, when they make people spaz out.
Okay, we're allowed to go through there.
We're not-
Do not go to the art room.
Yeah, the room stops turning bloody.
What if I stop and go back?
Now that I have gone-
Chat: "go all the way to the end and then turn back."
But...
Okay, you know what?
Let's have one last look before we actually do go to the dead end.
I think.
See, I told you she's there.
Look at her.
What did I tell you?
Oh my god, I fucking called it.
Oh my god, that laugh though.
That smile and everything.
"If only I had the courage to stop them from back then,
none of this would have ever happened...
It's my fault...
they're all.
Right, now let's try...
So the next thing we have to take note of is Yuka's note.
Oooh okay, landslide happens again.
And they're all running.
Probably because of murder.
Murder~
Conductor: That's what a murderer...
MURDER
That one little detail I noticed...
Uhh, Cover Corp, you might want to take a little look at this.
Unless that's intentional.
Because the chair is in contact with the ground.
That table is in contact with the ground with the black part.
That chair.
That's black part of the table.
But this isn't in contact with anything.
It's floating literally.
Slight little oversight, but okay.
Look at her, she's so cute.
Wait, hold up!
That's a completely different line.
Because because because usually she would say back to the time where.
Let's look at the corner to top right corner.
Because we're expecting a...
She's there!
She's there.
Not.
Why did you forget about that part?
Why did I forgot about that part?
Holy shit, it's so neatly tidy.
Also, I would never think of...
I did not expect that one.
What the heck?
Yo, yo, yo, yo, yo, I think we ought to walk back and figure out what's up.
Hold on.
There's more.
Yo, yo, yo, we got it.
We ought to walk back.
All right.
Yo, yo, yo, yo, yo, yo, yo, yo.
Chat: "In the end is a walking simulator."
I know, right?
At one point it is.
It's everyone.
We are getting ending three.
Let's go.
Okay.
Oh.
It's her.
Woah!
Whoa, okay.
I forgot about that.
I legit do.
I legit forgot about it.
Okay.
Yep.
It's the chaos part.
Where everything goes wrong.
Then the landslide.
There's a note.
Oh, my God.
Jesus Christus...
Woah! Already.
Okay.
I haven't walked.
I just noticed the guys clock has 10:10 on it.
Oh, it's the dude.
This is ending three.
What is it?
Wait.
Woah!
Okay.
I guess so.
There it is.
The third ending.
Do we have everything?
We're missing one note.
Where is that note?
What?
Yo, no, we can't…
We got all the visuals, but one note.
One note!
One freaking note!
Are you joking?
Where the hell am I missing that one note from?
Hold on.
It's been between…
Chat: "Did you get the one note from the pinning board around chapter 6 or 7?
It's like near the newspaper on the pinning board."
Wait, I didn't…
Wait, I didn't even notice!
Was there?
Around 6 or 7, right?
Let's head back.
That pinning board.
I don't see a note here.
There's no note on that one either.
And there's Pekora.
There's no note on here either.
Okay, we're well after that.
Don't see a note here.
There's one thing I have questions about.
What's the dude have to do with Aogami school?
Like, that dude is not us, right?
Even that.
That dude comes up.
It's so wack.
Chat: "That creepy dude could be ehmm... our grandfather?"
Oh, maybe.
Yeah, that could be.
Thinking about that.
That could be.
Because he could be dead.
he might have gotten the same curse.
The same…
The Aogami curse.
Woah, okay.
For a serious good second, I thought there was something.
It's that note!
That note that you're talking about!
"As part of the investigation, I was able to interview a resident about rumors surrounding the woods around us.
The story starts about two generations ago.
Even back then, Aogami was plagued by landslides, natural disasters, and other misfortunes.
In response, the residents at the time performed ritual human sacrifices in the woods near Aogami.
Even today, rumors profilerate about those woods.
With people saying they hear screaming in the night or see ghosts wandering in the area.
Might those human sacrifices be the root cause of all the paranormal happenings in this town?
Either way, I've decided to pay the woods a visit myself."
That could be the answer.
Let's check the inventory.
"Supernatural phenomenon #1"
It is!
Yup, it is!
We got them!
All of them!
Okay, let's try to complete them then.
Hmm.
These three endings really leave me still questioning.
Yup.
All papers obtained.
Chat: "Either way, it would be pretty worth it."
Yeah, actually, it is worth playing.
It is worth playing.
Because, look at that!
We just completed two days worth of Halloween.
Which is…
Technically Halloween in my time and then Halloween in the Western time.
Right.
So.
How is everyone?
How are y'all feeling?
What do you guys think?
Is Hololive Error something that you would find yourself enjoying?
I actually enjoy making the stream.
Like, legit.
I legit do enjoy making the stream.
It's not just Hololive Error in general, but just any kind of stream to be honest.
Yeah, I'm hoping to bring way more stuff to improvements.
But if there's anything that I want to dedicate to the most, it would be to thumbnails.
I'm gonna be doubling down on my efforts on thumbnails to hopefully be able to promote my stream a lot better.
And for people to notice my stream a lot more.
But…
With that aside, I'm gonna see what I can do to significantly shorten the time
of my workflow while keeping the same level of quality.
But before that, here's a little surprise.
If you know Hololive enough, then you probably know this by now.
I kind of searched around where I was at and I found this.
I found Curry Meshi.
I found it.
The very thing that Hololive has been promoting for a while.
I got extremely curious, so I bought it without knowing what I'm going to expect.
So I'm gonna have it for dinner tonight.
Like, hear this...
Are you hearing this?
This?
Yeah, I actually got it.
I'm gonna have this after the stream, so…
This could be a very good celebration for myself,
especially when it has something to do with Hololive for no reason.
Okay, okay.
Right, so how am I gonna be scheduling my streams from here on point?
I'm not gonna be doing big streams that often.
I'll be doing a couple of little streams here and there.
But this is enough to stall and give me enough time to make highlights of my own.
The important part is to be able to balance between making highlights for my highlights channel.
And yeah.
That's it.
I'm so glad to have pushed myself to pull shits like this off on stream.
Like, the little details on stream, like the effect, the VFX.
The acting on...
on section C.
I don't know, what do you call that section C?
The alternate scene C or something?
Part C is what some stream addresses as.
All that little detail, including the poster as well.
To be honest, I…
Right, I forgot to mention.
I would like to thank those 20 Twitter likes that I got for that part 1 poster.
That part 1 poster is currently the most liked post on all of my Twitter.
I…
Even though it's just 20, it's still…
In a matter of just a couple of days, hitting 20 likes is kind of monumental for me.
And…
I don't know what to say.
View count really isn't my focus.
What really matters is, did I enjoy the game?
To which I answer, yes!
Yes I hella do!
It just leaves me a little bit wondering at times.
Phew.
Right, if you guys haven't already, be sure to follow.
Follow me on Twitch, Twitter, subscribe on YouTube.
Follow me on Gank.
Yup, Gank is a social media apparently.
On top of being a donation platform, it's also a social media.
Follow me on Gank as well.
And yeah.
I'll catch you guys.
I'll catch you guys on Wednesday.
Peace.
OtsuMelo deshita [It's been ya girl, Mel].
See ya!
I'm free.