Is it bad to say that I'm...
...I got too impatient?
Umm...
Bleh~!
Hehehe he he he~
I'm sorry... I'm sorry! XD
It is still in the works.
I'm so so so god damn sorry. ><
I WILL be back
Give me a little... more time, I guess.
Oh! Also,
you can also check out my Ko-fi!
My, umm...
my Ko-fi currently has my latest Unity renders.
Because I was just figuring out how to use Unity.
That's how I got my tongue... (fweh)... coming out.
Like, look-at-dat!
Blaeh~!
Aeh~
rAeh~
aEh~ (laughing)
Also, my cheeks can now puff.
Like, watch!
Watch this! Okay?
Hold on... lemme just...
Watch this... okay?
You see this? You see this?
Mmph~
Hph~
Hm~
Pop~
Pop! pu~ pop! pu~ pop! pu~
Pop~ Pop~ Pop~ Pop~ Pop~ Pop~ Pop~ Pop~ Pop~ Pop~
Hhhh hahaheheugh heugh heeeeeeugghh~
Hah heugh heugh heugh heuggg~
Ehg hagh hah heugh~
Okay... (catches breath)
Auhh I'm playing around too much XD
Okay! (catches breath again)
I'll be back! I promise!
Catch ya next time!