Melori Valentine
23F (MTF)
Tech Wizardess VTuber
I tried to cover ISEGYE IDOL - LOCKDOWN
Entirely created on an iPhone!
i eodum soge gathyeo do
Even if I'm stuck in the dark.
i siganeul beorigo domangga boryeogo haedo
Even if we try to run away from this very moment.
i giri makhyeodo nal mageul su eopseul geoya neon
Even if I'm held back, you won't be able to stop me, no.
Oh, drop it. Get up and lockdown!
Stop, you gotta lockdown.
Burn it up now, we keep that movin'.
Try, you gotta pipe down.
Turn it up now we still that groovy.
Lockdown, you better watch out!
Burn it up now, we keep that moving.
Try, you gotta pipe down.
All my enemies are lockdown.
Don't forget to like, comment, and subscribe! ^~^