Man, that's a lot of assignments to work on.
Oh, well hello.
Didn't see you there.
How are you doing?
Glad to hear.
So, what brings you here?
Feeling a little bored?
Wanted to hear a little bit of what I'm working on?
Well, you see, I've been really busy on assignments these days,
so there isn't really much about me.
Do you wanna sit around and watch me type?
Great.
Glad to hear.
Good.
Good little junior.
You sure you wanna stick around?
I mean, all I'm doing is just mostly typing out manuscripts and stuff.
Alright.
Suit yourself.
Right, let's see.
This file.
Hmm.
That particular folder.
Oh, dang it.
Need to type my freaking password again.
Oh fuck.
My finger slipped.
Sorry about that.
I shouldn't be swearing, considering I'm your senior.
Ah, there we go.
Finally got it.
Right, let's see.
This folder.
Hmm.
Do you wanna have a look?
What's that?
Don't like being touched around your ears?
Hmm.
Here, let me tease you a little.
Okay, for real.
Here, have a look.
Have a look at the document.
Really?
Cool.
Alright, time to get back to focusing.
It's gonna get really distracting if I keep talking.
Here we go.
Oh, here we go.
You know, I'm not often a multitasker.
Because sometimes I get really distracted when I'm typing while I'm talking.
But I can sometimes manage it a little.
What's that?
Oh, how long will it take?
I'm...
not really too sure.
This is a crazy long document.
I mean, considering that this is a pretty big major.
So, I mean, it's not the final year thing, you know.
But it is still pretty big, you know.
That kind of document.
How did I do last time?
Well umm,
average, I guess.
I mean,
I'm just able to get away with certain scores, I guess.
Oh, speaking of average scores.
I don't think I should be teaching you that as a senior,
but I got a really interesting way to...
to score well in exams with barely any studying.
So if you try to take in the piece of information and try to make it a little…
How do I say this?
Interesting in your way?
Somehow you end up becoming really, really curious.
And it makes you want to read up a little more.
Yeah, that's kind of my trick to how I'm able to balance between work and play.
I mean, I'm sure you've seen me playing at the arcade a couple of times
and going on a couple of parties with some friends.
I'm not just moping around all the time, you know.
I'm just taking studies a little smarter because, you know,
one might struggle to pass an examination if they get really, really, really stressed out.
I've heard from a good number of people when they say life is a race.
I could agree to some extent, but not everything is a race, don't you think?
Sometimes you just gotta slow it down a little.
Take a step back, do it at your pace, and you'll notice what you're missing.
Don't you think?
Great.
Good, Junior.
*pat pat pat pat pat pat*
I gotta get back to typing.
Silly me.
Here we go.
Hmm, this is an interesting document.
How should I put it?
Do you have any idea?
I'm just kidding.
No, I'm not gonna put so much pressure on you.
You're just my junior.
I mean, you're not in the same class as me yet, but I'm happy to get to know you sooner.
I mean, eventually, I might have to guide you on some certain subjects.
Don't you think?
Oh.
Hmm.
Something's not a little right with the document right here.
Right here.
Hmm.
Yeah.
I'm not particularly good with English either.
I mean…
I'm not ESL, as one might say, but…
I'm not too sure.
It's just that my English knowledge is just slowly falling, slipping away.
I'm not really too sure.
Maybe, I don't know if this happens with other people,
but it feels like my English knowledge slowly slips away.
Maybe it's because I've been learning other languages a little too much.
Or maybe I've been thinking on other languages.
Yeah, maybe that might be the case.
I should probably brush up on my English as well.
I'm gonna quickly save it real quick, so I don't lose the document.
Some people do tend to lose their document to accidentally closing the program, crashing computers, and stuff like that.
Yeah.
I'm not letting that happen.
Phew.
What a mouthful.
That's like two paragraphs about that, yeah.
Hmm?
Oh, yeah.
I should be working about like…
20 pages of that.
Currently I'm on page…
19?
Is that 19?
Sorry, I'm having a hard time looking.
I'm having some bad eyesight right now.
Gotta zoom it in.
Hmm, yeah.
It is 19.
Alright.
I got one more page to go.
Why the limit?
I don't really know.
Maybe…
I'm not really too sure.
You gotta ask the department for that.
The education department.
They said something about like,
Oh, you gotta write up to 20 pages of that.
That should be the limit.
They didn't say anything about, you know…
They didn't say anything about…
Writing how many words onto a 20-page document.
So while others have written theirs in font size 12,
I've written mine in font size 14.
I don't think you should follow my example for that, but…
I've been able to get away with that.
Because…
It's still a readable document.
It's still a very acceptable document.
I got pretty much high schools with that anyways.
But seriously, don't follow my example.
Someday, the education department may just…
I don't know.
Catch up to my tail.
Oh, oh.
It's been quite a while.
You have not drank…
You have not drank water.
Would you like to have some?
Oh, you have your own?
It's okay.
Drink up, drink up.
You gotta…
You gotta hydrate.
Excuse me.
Pardon me.
I drank a little too fast.
Hmm.
Yeah, I should take it easy.
I mean, I just said it earlier.
Not everything is a race.
See?
You're not so bad after all.
Good junior.
You have paid attention so far.
So…
I gotta be honest.
You did an amazing job.
I'm sure you'll be able to influence someone…
Under your wing as well.
Alright, let's get this document done.
So we can get out of here and…
I don't know, chill.
How did I type all this?
Without reading up on anything?
Oh, silly you.
Haven't you paid attention from earlier?
I did tell you that…
That I digest all my information from…
By making it interesting.
That's how I remember all of everything.
Because without a curious mind, you can't really get anything in.
Because you…
Once you feel like you're…
You're being forced to learn a certain thing…
You end up not enjoying it.
Which then…
Also means you're gonna have a hard time remembering it.
So…
I've decided to make it…
Interesting.
Even for myself.
Even if it seems boring from the outside.
Though,there are times where I do need to look up…
Look up online about…
About what I've missed.
But…
But the joy is…
In actually understanding what's going on.
Hmm...
Oh…
A typo.
Same spot, right?
Alright, let's review the whole document.
Let's see…
Page 1…
Page 2…
Right, page 3…
Page 4…
Page 5…
Page 6…
No, no, no, no, no.
That didn't look right.
Let me just fix that real quick.
Let me fix that.
That seriously did not look right at all.
Where to start?
Hm, right here.
Oh!
Looking good.
Right, page 6 looking good.
Page 7…
four-…
Oh!
No, no, no, no, no.
No, I gotta fact check that one real quick.
Mm-mm-mm.
No wonder something fell off with that.
Okay, I gotta fix that.
I gotta fix that.
Right.
Hm!
Anyway,
Throw this whole paragraph out of the way.
Boop!
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
Hehe.
Ah…
Okay, yeah, that looks fine.
Right.
14's looking clean.
Hm, that didn't flow right.
Well, I started page 19 anyways, so…
I've worked on this document since like…
days ago, so it didn't flow right.
Let me just quickly correct that.
Maybe I should make a sentence flow from…
from like, here, all the way to…
here.
you think so?
Good idea.
Actually, hold on.
Wait, right here.
Doesn't it look a little off?
Like, from here to here.
Hm.
Yeah, you're right.
I should correct that real quick.
How should I type it?
Looking by the previous paragraph, it would be…
like this.
hm.
Yeah.
Thank you so much.
Thank you so much, lil Junior.
Good.
But still, my bad.
I should be the senior here.
I shouldn't be asking tips from juniors.
But, you know.
Why is it so important?
It's just…
We're humans after all.
We all make mistakes anyways, so…
Right, let's go to it.
The whole of 19…
20…
Oh shoot, I forgot to do the conclusion.
Silly me.
Oh no.
Okay, we gotta get this up.
Right now.
Hm.
And… dot!
And save.
Don't forget to save.
Alright, we gotta get this printed.
Wait.
Ah, dang it.
We're at the end of this library.
God dang it.
Ah, I gotta walk so freaking far
just to get to the printer.
Fine, I'll get it.
Let me just send it to the printing server.
Right…
now.
Okay.
I'll grab the paper.
But first, thank you so much, Junior.
I mean…
If you feel free to wait for me outside if you wanna…
I don't know.
Grab some food with me before we go home.
Catch you later.
See ya.