This video is sponsored to you by SD Maid SE.
More on that at the end of the video.
Android phones.
In case you didn't know about Android phones,
they are quite a versatile operating system.
Now before we get into anything,
I gotta make it clear that I don't
take sides between iOS and Android.
Because in my opinion, both of
them have its own pros and cons.
And even though I use an iPhone 12 Pro Max
as my tracking camera and my daily driver,
I still think there's a
lot in Android to discover.
Now, with that said.
There's one thing that I have to address
that has been left alone for a very very
long time on my Android secondary driver,
the Galaxy Note 10+.
Yeah, there may be some flaws.
Some of the flaws happen to be
a bit of hiccuping going on.
Don't get me wrong, Chino
is really really adorable.
And on top of that, Samsung
has decided to discontinue
security updates for the Galaxy Note 10+,
which also means this phone
is no longer secure and it
could be subject to security vulnerabilities
after being left alone for a long time.
Usually a general user would
just buy a brand new phone,
but I don't get that kind of
luxury and I don't got that money,
at least for now.
So, let's install a custom Android OS.
Now you may be wondering to yourself:
"Oh Mel, how do you do this?"
"I've never heard, I've
never tried this before. Oh~"
Now don't worry.
It may be quite simple once
you get the hang of it,
but it can get a little complicated since
things are different from device to device,
which in this case the Galaxy Note 10+,
happens to be in the middle of what's being
crazy much of a hassle and what's not a hassle.
So as your tech wizardess girl,
I've done my prior research about this.
Now, the Galaxy Note 10+, is particularly
one of those phones that are,
at least according to the community,
possibly a difficult one to handle,
considering how they're using
a completely different chip,
at least for the international variants,
that is not the Snapdragon chip,
but rather Samsung's in-house Exynos chip,
which means things can be a little bit
different from the usual Qualcomm Snapdragon.
However, I've done some digging
around and I found two custom OSes
that are currently actively being
maintained by the community right now.
However, there are more other different
flavors of custom Android ROMs,
but it's very subjective to the maintainers
to see whether they would take the initiative
to keep a ROM for a specific model up to date,
which in the case of the Galaxy Note 10+,
it's kind of sad to hear that there's
only two that's currently being
actively maintained right now,
or three for that matter.
So let's get through, let's
get through each of them.
We're going to the first step right
now, which is selecting the ROM.
Now the first ROM that I'm gonna go
through right now is called PixelOS,
which is trying to become a Google Pixel,
for non-Google Pixel pretty much,
which is kind of interesting actually.
Before we get into that,
we're gonna understand what is AOSP.
So AOSP basically means
Android Open Source Project,
which is a project made by
Google that allows people
to create completely custom
versions of Android of their own.
Think of it like Android for tinkers,
that is separated from the
proper manufacturer-made ones.
Even though they may be separate,
doesn't necessarily mean
the quality can be subpar.
If the team is right, and they're all dedicated,
I'm sure there are great
features coming along with that.
There's also a huge slew of ROMs out there that
you can find that are tailored to specific cases.
It's the same as when you're looking
for different distros of Linux.
Where each distro of Linux is
dedicated for specific cases,
and you can pick to whichever is your liking,
and you can customize it if
you have the know-how to.
However, Pixel OS makes this a little
bit simpler for small tinkerers like me
that are looking to just change things a little,
but not do things insanely dramatically.
I just want a really neat, well-maintained OS,
and stick with it, with the added
benefit of my current situation.
Which in this case, Samsung's
One UI is ridiculously bloated.
If you didn't know, there's a
couple of webpages that talked
about how many bloatwares Samsung
has in their operating systems,
which is batshit insane in my opinion.
So if you want to clean
Android OS without the bloat,
usually Android Open Source
Projects are amazing for that.
Now there might be some
more questions in your mind.
Isn't that the same as rooting?
No, they are not.
Rooting is a completely different
process for a different purpose.
Rooting is like, for you
iPhone users, jailbreaking.
Which is to break open the
limits of what the OS can do,
most of the time involving using exploits,
to achieve customizability that are
beyond what the stock software can do.
But rooting can be done even on your current OS.
You don't need to be on a specific OS to root.
Thus why the topic I'm covering
right now is completely unrelated.
Right, getting back to Pixel OS,
it basically tells Android OS into thinking
that everything that it's got is a Pixel,
even though you're actually not on a Pixel.
Which is kind of an interesting
project in my opinion.
This is admittedly one of the closest to
a pure Google system that you can find.
However, this comes with a whole
lot of Google's own bloatware.
Like say you don't want Google Meet.
With Pixel OS, I doubt that's possible.
Which then this thing comes in.
It's called crDroid, which is
a fork of an already existent,
very well popular Android open
source project called LineageOS.
So on top of what's available on
this really really clean LineageOS,
they added a few customizability
that might tailor to your taste.
All that with very minimal Google bloat.
And considering how it is based on LineageOS,
whenever LineageOS releases
a weekly security update,
they can push it downstream and push these
security updates to crDroid users as well.
And there's also a whole slew of customizability
that you won't otherwise see
on most other OSes honestly.
In my opinion, crDroid is amazing when you want
great customizability with very little footprint.
Right, now that I've introduced you
to two different custom Android ROMs,
let's get into how we get into installing it.
Now like I said, each phone
may vary by step significantly.
Which in this case, having a Samsung phone
means you'll be patching your firmware
completely differently from what a
traditional Android phone would usually use,
which is using a command line
called Android Debug Bridge.
However, for Samsung phones, they
decided to take a different approach
and use a firmware updater called Odin.
Now, if you don't know what
Odin is, I don't blame you.
It is actually a leaked
software from Samsung's labs
that is used to perform updates
directly into the phone by cable.
These are actually meant for developers things,
but with the program leaked,
it basically unlocked a whole slew of
customizability for the Samsung phones.
And you can find Odin in this XDAForums.
Please click on the ones in my description,
do not Google Search it because
you might find fakes at some point.
This thread is the real one, be sure
to bookmark it once you go there.
Now the leaker has a couple of patches for
Odin as well that bypasses a couple of things,
but to me in my case, I
don't really put use to it.
So I'll probably be using the original version.
And once you got Odin, the next thing you need
to have is this Samsung Android USB driver.
Because if you don't have it, you might not
be able to see your devices on your computer.
Right now that we're here, let's get
to PixelOS's Galaxy Note 10+ page.
And we're gonna download the latest build
of their ROMs and a copy of the recovery.
For PixelOS, you're going to need to get the
recovery from this very thread right here,
right down here for your respective devices.
If you're using crDroid, you can also do so here.
However, if you want the latest
weekly updates from LineageOS,
click on download older versions, to which
it'll take you to the page on SourceForge.
And as you can see on the file names, they are
sorted by versions and by their build dates.
The latest ones are usually security
updates that came downstream from LineageOS.
If you want the absolute latest security
updates from LineageOS, you get them here.
Otherwise, you can just get their recommended
build, which is a little bit older,
that has the December 2023
update, as of the time of filming.
And don't forget to grab
the recovery for it as well.
So for each ROMs, the two things you
need is the ROM itself and the recovery.
However, for crDroid and LineageOS,
you're going to need one more thing.
You see, some Android projects did not
want to deal with legal issues with Google.
So in turn, they do not include
Google Play Services in their ROMs.
So if you wish to have Google Play Services,
you would have to download one extra thing,
which is GApps, which is usually
provided by the ROM provider
as a separate link to where
you have to download from.
So some of the older Android
versions would have OpenGApps,
and then the more recent ones would
have MindTheGaps or MindTheGApps.
Heh, see what they did there?
So you gotta keep an eye on the version
number, architecture, and the build date.
So say for example, I'm going to
install Android 13 from crDroid.
Then you have to match it
right here on its name, 13.
Following that is the architecture
of your mobile device.
Now if you don't know about the architecture
of your mobile device, it's fine.
LineageOS wiki has infos about it.
And if you just scroll down even a tiny
bit from say the Galaxy Note 10+ site,
you would see a section called
architecture and there's your answer.
So now we know that the Galaxy Note
10+ uses ARM64 for its architecture,
which means now we put them all together,
Android 13, ARM64, and there's no other builds,
so this is the latest then.
Then we click download.
Once we've obtained all the files that we need,
then you'll end up with these sets of stuff.
However, if you only have one OS
each, you would only need these two.
This, and that's it, three stuff, or four.
However, if you have one OS only,
you would only want the said OS and Odin,
or which LineageOS's case or crDroid,
you're gonna also need MindTheGApps as well.
Alright, shall we get into flashing?
Not that kind of flashing.
Whatever you're thinking, no.
Okay, first and foremost, we
gotta do a really important thing.
We gotta head to the settings, scroll all
the way down, and click [About Phone].
Go to [Software Information], and
click the [Build Number] seven times.
One, two, you'll count down down
here as you can see, as you click.
If you happen to have PIN set on your
device, you would also need that as well.
Right, now with Developer Mode turned on,
let's go back to the front of the settings,
and you see there's one more
entry called [Developer Options].
We click into that, and we
scroll down a teeny tiny bit,
and you see right here, right where
my tip is at, [OEM unlocking].
We're gonna need to unlock that because
we're making modifications to our systems.
Some devices, even though you're
not touching the bootloader,
still wants you to unlock the bootloader in
order to make modifications to your system.
So it's always best to turn it on.
However, if you do run into a very rare case
where this option is completely missing,
please do refer to this guide, where it
tells you to set your date seven days behind.
Otherwise, if you still can't find it,
you probably have to reinstall the
stock firmware that you're currently on.
Right, after you've went through
your PIN, it would tell you:
"Warning: Device protection features will not work
on this device while this setting is turned on."
That's fine because we're not going
to be using this OS anymore anyways.
Right, now with that enabled, all we
have to do is say goodbye to this.
Oh, you weren't expecting goodbye?
Well then, do your backups right now.
You are going to say goodbye
to this instance of your phone.
You're going to say hello to
a brand new operating system.
Okay, now that you've backed up everything,
and you're about to say goodbye to this OS,
we're gonna shut it down.
Good night.
Now that we turned the phone off, what we need
is a USB cable that corresponds to your phone,
which in my case, I got a type-c cable.
Now this step varies significantly
depending on phone models.
Some phones would have different combinations,
some phones would have different steps.
You're going to need to find
a step on how to enable Odin,
at least for the Samsung devices,
which in the case of Galaxy Note 10+,
what you have to do is press
the plus and minus volume key,
the up and down key, volume key,
which I could kind of just
mash it with my my hands
and stick the USB device, uh USB cable in.
It should turn down with a
completely different screen like this.
"Warning, a custom OS can cause critical
problems in the phone and installed applications.
If you want to download a custom
OS, press the volume up key."
Now there is a second layer of
of unlocking that we have to do.
We have unlocked the bootloader,
but we haven't really unlocked
the bootloader proper.
So what we have to do is actually
press and hold the volume up key,
as what it says right here.
It would ask you whether you
want to unlock your bootloader.
We will definitely need this because
otherwise we will not be able to install
custom Android OSes on Samsung phones.
So like it says, like it says volume up to yes,
we're going to press volume up.
Now it says this phone's bootloader is unlocked
and its software integrity can't be verified.
Very well, that's exactly what we need.
But considering how the phone rebooted
itself and erased all the data,
we need to jump back to that same
screen that we were at earlier.
And that's because Samsung requires you
to activate your device for
some weird fucking reason.
That means you have to go through all
the freaking setup all over again.
So all you need to do is connect to the
internet and skip through all the setup.
When you head back to the [Developer Settings],
you'll see that your
bootloader is already unlocked.
Right, what we need to do now is
to get this phone into Odin mode.
And to do that, I'm going to
press these two buttons together
and stick in the USB to get back to this screen.
Volume up to continue.
Now what we want to do is
select the recovery image
that we just downloaded from
Google Drive and press on start.
Once that's done, immediately press
the power and the volume up key
until you see the recovery screen.
Now before we do any flashing,
we're going to make sure that we have
formatted all the data and factory reset.
We're going to make sure that we're
cleaning up the entirety of the drive
because we don't want any leftovers from
Samsung OneUI to be affecting our process.
Right, what we want to do next is to head
down to [Apply update] and [Apply from ADB].
This puts this phone on ADB sideload.
And what does this mean?
Is that we have to get onto terminal
and you're going to need a binary
called ADB or Android Debug Bridge.
If you don't have it, you gotta get it.
And put it somewhere convenient
where your terminal can see
or add it into your environment path.
Right, to make sure that the ADB can
actually see the device right now,
we're going to type [adb devices]
and then we get to see the device right there.
And what we want to do is type [adb sideload]
and we got to copy the firmware file name in its
whole including the zip file, including the [.zip]
and paste it in and press enter.
This should ship the ROM file into the recovery
and that should be our first step
into a brand new operating system.
Alright, once that's done, we're going
to press [Factory reset] once more,
but this time only [Factory reset/Format data].
And then finally, we can reboot.
Now every time we boot, it's going to give us
the warning of the bootloader being unlocked,
but we need to keep it unlocked
considering how we're using a custom OS that is
well outside of Samsung's own operating system.
When it boots up, it goes through a
lot of the first time setup stuff,
so don't panic when it takes quite
long to start on its first boot.
Usually it would take up to 10 to 15 minutes.
If you're lucky, it would take shorter than that.
So in the meantime, go ahead and have a cup of tea
or grab some snacks while you wait
for this to finish booting up.
Hey, here we are.
By the way, we're completely
through the flashing process now,
so we can just unplug the
device if we feel like it.
And now this is going to be
your proper operating system,
so just run through the setup
the way you usually would.
"Set up using another device?" Nah, I'm good.
"Getting your phone ready."
"This may take a few minutes."
"Set up a PIN?" Later.
And there you have it. PixelOS.
And as you can see, the sets of applications
that are here are very, very bare bones,
and that's expected of PixelOS.
Now say you don't want PixelOS, how
do we install crDroid or LineageOS?
Or say you want a different operating
system for this Samsung phone.
We're gonna run through this
whole process once again.
Right, now that we know how to install
Pixel OS onto the Galaxy Note 10+,
we're gonna do the same with
crDroid, just with one extra step.
They're not all too different, so we should
be able to follow the exact same steps.
So starting, we're gonna need Odin as usual,
and we're gonna need our recovery.
So what you want to do is
rename it to [recovery.img].
Add it into a tar archive using your favorite
archive tool, say for example 7-zip or WinRAR.
With that, we would have the resulting .tar file.
Now what you want to do is click on
AP in Odin, and open [recovery.tar].
Now that we got it all prepped
up, let's take the phone.
Remember these usual steps.
Volume up and down, and USB in.
Oi!
And we should get that same old
screen that we just had some time ago.
Here, let me just get it zoomed in so
you can see it real clearly like that.
And what we want to do is as usual,
if we have already unlocked the bootloader,
then we should just press volume up.
And now it should consider being connected.
As we can see on Odin, we
have something connected.
And now we just have to push
it in into the device that way.
It should be relatively fast
and it should not take long.
And now that we've done that, we're gonna press
our power button up to get into the recovery.
There are times where you end up screwing up and
you end up booting back into your Android OS.
That's perfectly fine.
So what you want to do is get the phone back down,
and what you want to do is press the
volume up key and the power button.
If fuck all doesn't work, you can always
open up the [Developer options] once again.
Head down to [USB debugging] and turn it on.
Now that we're there, we're
gonna open up our terminal.
Plug in the device and type
the following: [adb devices]
because what we want to do is check
if it can find the said device.
And usually it would just ask you
if you would allow USB debugging.
That usually is a good signal that it works.
And now that we tried it again, you can see
that now the device has been shown as [Device].
We can now jump straight into the recovery
without pressing these stupid combinations.
By typing [adb reboot recovery], press enter,
and this should take the device
straight to the recovery.
Now that we're on crDroid recovery,
what you want to do is do the usual wipe
and clean up that we have done before.
So [Format data], format
everything, clean everything up.
We don't want any traces from
the previous installation,
because different ROMs can result in
different ways of implementing shit.
They're all not exactly the same, so
we're gonna need to format everything,
clean them all up, and prep
this thing for flashing.
Once we've done all three of them,
we're gonna now hit to [Apply update]
and [Apply from ADB] once more.
Now that we're here, we're gonna
do a really important step.
[adb sideload], and what you
want to do is take the ROM file,
which if your terminal is already in the directory
where your desired folder is
at, you could just put the name.
Otherwise, you're gonna need to
drag the file in and press enter.
Now that it's done, we still got one more step.
Like I said earlier, some ROMs do
not include Google Play services
and other Google require
stuff for Google Play to work,
so we're gonna need to install that as well.
So if you remember that we've
downloaded this MindTheGApps zip,
now it's the time we're gonna sideload this
on top of the ROM that we've just installed.
So we're gonna click [Apply update]
and click [Apply from ADB] once more.
At this point, it should be
relatively self-explanatory.
[adb sideload], and the file, and we press enter.
This should install MindTheGApps
and do all the job for us.
Now that it's done, what do we want
to do is just reboot the system now.
We're done here. You're finally on crDroid.
Now if you remember from the video earlier,
it does take a while for
crDroid to finish booting up.
And here we are now. We're finally on crDroid.
Now we just have to run
through the setup like usual.
Once you've gone through all the
setup, there's only one button.
Start.
And here we are. We're finally now on crDroid.
I wouldn't say the cleanest, but it is
relatively clean of an operating system.
What I really like a lot personally about
crDroid is that they have extra stuff
that you can change that are mostly cosmetics.
However, as cosmetic as they are, they can make
your phone feel kind of unique to yourself.
Some of which are functional,
or say for example, you want to unlock
higher frame rates for certain games.
You have an option for that.
Or you could also have unlimited photo storage
that mimics the benefits
that Pixel XL usually have.
And there's a whole slew of other different
kind of quality of life improvements
that I personally like that you don't
get from its upstream, namely LineageOS.
So I'm definitely going to be daily
driving the crDroid personally.
And there you have it.
We finally breathed new life to an Android device
that we could have otherwise thrown as e-waste.
Now if you do enjoy this video, be sure
to press the like button, subscribe,
and be sure to check out all the
resources I have in the description below
for where you need to download these files.
And I hope you enjoy one of
my first few tech videos.
And with that said, thank
you all so much for watching.
See you guys next time.
Otsu-Melo deshita! (It's been Mel here.)
See ya!
And with that out of the way, time
to tell you about our sponsor.
Tired of slowness and long loading?
Want to make more space for your stuff?
Well, SD Maid SE is here to help.
SD Maid SE is a junk cleaner made
by an indie developer named Darken.
Some apps tend to leave leftover files we
don't need after we're done using them.
That's where SD Maid SE comes in to help.
Now you can do that manually, but time is money.
With SD Maid SE, you can
automate a good deal of that,
and leave precious times to the
things that really matter the most.
Unlike other system junk cleaners,
SD Maid SE does not collect any
form of personally identifiable info
that could be sold to scummy
data miners for profit.
Nor does it bombard you with a
fuckton of ads that waste your time.
Like I said, time is money!
SD Maid SE heavily relies on the generosity
of the community to stay alive and going.
App improvements happen with
the help and contribution
from the great community in GitHub and Discord.
So if there's any bug with
the app, you're never alone.
What are you waiting for?
Get your phone cleaned with SD
Maid SE on the Google Play Store
or GitHub in the description below.
Oh, maybe I should clean my phone screen too.
With that, thanks to Darken
Development for encouraging me
to walk forward in content creation.
Catch you next time!