She's not really back, is she?
That is, by the way of MeloriTensei,
who has previously announced hiatus,
but has never announced that she's back!
Which is pretty evident with her battery replacement stream.
Sometimes, we wonder if she really is back!
However, we have exclusive information from The Tech Wizardess herself.
And thus, we'll hand it over to Mel herself.
Take it away!
Thanks, FalseMel.
First up, I got a brand new logo!
What do you think? Do you think it looks good?
Do you think it looks good-y good-y good-y?
(chuckle)
I mean, we got a little, like a circle-y looking thing.
and a galaxy in the ring.
Kinda give out that Michael Jackson vibe, don't ya think?
Lemme know in the (*comments) below.
(Oops, said "description" by habit XD)
And with that aside, I got a brand new links page!
Which is currently hosted on https://pincushion.etersia.moe/@MeloriTensei/ The reason why I'm moving out of my Carrd
is because I wanna bring up more customizability
without having to worry about the element count limit.
So with that addition, it has given me more space to add a few social medias.
(Beep beep, unnecessary NSFW warning)
Including PCPartPicker
(Ahh~)
And a steamy social media~
Whatever happens there stays there.
Don't bring it over to YouTube.
And without the limit, allows me to add even more contexts onto each of the sections.
Say, for example, the donations section. More on that later. And if you're wondering where I got the template from
Do check out LinkStack, it's a whole new server that lets you selfhost this kind of thing.
Check it out on GitHub.
With that aside, I've also decided to return to Ko-Fi and Throne for my donation platform.
And with that said, I've also enabled PayPal as my donation option for PayPal balance users.
To those using cards, please use Stripe (the one that is not PayPal) as an option.
Because, then more money will get to me. Because PayPal takes a little bit more for transaction fees that will be taken off me.
And I've also included that context in the notes section as well, in case you forgot.
And with moving back into Ko-Fi, it also mean I'm going to start making some more 3D wallpapers.
Very occasionally, however.
If you got any ideas, send them down in the (*comments) below.
(Really Mel, "description" again?)
and with more wallpapers, I've also decided to up the quality.
Which also means I'm moving out of Blender,
and to use Unity to make these wallpapers instead.
Because I think Unity is much more close to the aesthetics that my current model is.
However, I got plans to do something even more exciting.
Which is Unreal Engine 5. However, I'm waiting for colliders for this model to be fixed on in UE5 first before I can make wallpapers out of UE5.
More on that in the future.
And speaking of fixing my model, I've added a couple of additions to my model
that are very minute. You might have seen this in my [Got Impatient] video
Where my mouth can puff, and I can stick my tongue out.
In addition to that, I could also move my mouth sideways.
Although, very very little.
Now onto a different topic, I've heard your concerns.
"Uhh Mel? When's your Discord server? Do you have a Discord server? I wanna keep in touch with you."
While I understand, however moderation is a daunting task for me.
Especially for someone who's doing everything on the channel, from top to bottom, all by myself.
So, I've been waiting for a moderator to be able to assist me on that.
However, if you've watched the recent streams,
you might have noticed that I may have found a moderator.
And I'm going to appoint them as my moderator for my Discord server.
And I'll eventually work on the Discord server when I finally have time to work on it.
While it doesn't mean that the Discord server is coming instantly,
it may take months, it may take even half a year.
But rest assured it is going to be in the works.
And speaking of "being in the works", I've decided to step out of Twitter and Instagram.
Because of great concerns of the wildly changed TOS on Twitter.
While it would be quite devastating to lose network on the community on Twitter,
I've also decided to step out of it for various other reasons, to which I wish to not disclose.
"Uhh, Mel. Where would the updates come (from) then?"
Glad you asked.
The updates are going to be now on YouTube Community Post and Bluesky for English.
And I also wanted to practice my Japanese skills a little bit.
So, I've also started writing a couple of important update posts, in full Japanese, on Misskey as well.
Do check those out on the page I mentioned earlier.
And on top of that, I've also decided to start mainly streaming on YouTube.
Albeit now that I'm on YouTube, I'm gonna be making lesser streams and more videos.
Because I honestly think making streams are quite taxing on me.
Especially for someone who has been doing everything alone.
While I'm not going to fall behind on the stream quality,
I am going to drop the frequency (*and) keep focusing on videos.
So hopefully you would keep in touch with me for future videos.
But it's not like I'm gonna stream once in a long while either,
I'm gonna try to keep the stream frequency of once a week,
Hopefully most of the time.
And with that said, I wanted to also expand my coverage
for certain interesting communities I may reach out to.
So, I've added localization to my channel in Chinese and Japanese.
Though, I won't be adding subtitles to those languages just yet.
But they are in consideration, someday when I do have a translator that could help me on that.
And with all the changes mentioned,
I'm gonna take a short management hiatus
so I can rebuild my PC and actually get certain actual parts in (to the PC).
and tidy up the spaghetti town level cable management on my desk setup.
I'm really really sorry for more delays but this is gonna take
probably two to three weeks.
I'm gonna be managing more than just what I mentioned of the two.
I'll probably be taking care of tidying up my channels and everything, and my OBS.
To make sure everything stays up to date and none of which are abandoned.
And after all that, I'm really really sorry for the constant delays.
I hope to manage way better in the coming future and push more content out.
Though, with that said, while I'm gone, there's gonna be one video that I'm gonna be pushing out.
It's gonna be my very very first video that I've properly edited in 2024.
Here's a trailer, check it out!
So, how do you think? Do you think it looks good? Lemme know in the comments below.
Back to you, FalseMel!
Thank you so much, Mel!
And that is all for today's episode!
As always, press like and subscribe if you want more content out of me.
And there'll be more.
MeloriTensei 2024 for you, soon!