Well hey, look who's home.
It's your good ol' little PC-kun.
(Grunts) Come on in.
(Home is where the circuits rest.)
God dammit, I've missed you for so long.
(A connection reestablished, a home coming complete.)
Right, let's get her rolled in,
and let's get her installed.
It's been a while.
Hey guys, it's ya girl, MeloriTensei,
and let's get straight to the devlog for August 2024.
So one of the greatest good news is
that the PC's not dead anymore, as you can see.
I am finally back.
Ey, I'm on VRChat and I'm finally doing VRChat things.
I don't, uh, to be honest, I don't really know.
So to those who haven't watched my mousemat video,
here's the short form of what happened.
I sent the computer to the technician
and it took them 9 days to figure out what went wrong.
So basically what went wrong is that,
so the PSU has been pretty worn out
and it has been involved in a really massive accident many many years ago
that surprisingly slipped past my mind.
It's a long time ago, naive Melori accidentally mismatched power supply cables
and that caused some brrrrrrrrrrrrrr magic smoke.
And I thought what broke is probably just my GPU
and I didn't think of it too much.
But I didn't expect that it even blew up
the power supply safety feature as well.
So, the safety feature for the PSU is pretty busted.
And add salt to injury, the warranty for the PSU is pretty void
because naive Mel opened up the power supply to clean the fan.
So, the warranty is more or less void
because we don't have legislations here defending against
the warranty sticker here.
So, I pretty much have no choice but to accept defeat more or less.
However, with a little bit of money to gather around,
special thanks to my Ko-fi donators.
Thank you all so so so so much for giving me even the slightest bit of money
that allows me to be able to afford at least a power supply
that can hold me off for at least
probably a year or two and keep going with content creation.
So, I thank you very very very very much.
But with that said, I'm still looking forward
to get a properly decent power supply
and you can check out my Throne for the actual power supply
that I'm looking forward to upgrade to.
I'll show that on the screen and feel free to donate
if you would like to keep me alive
for a little bit longer, I guess.
But yeah, speaking of setups however,
I have decided that I kinda wanna try
messing around with ASMRs a little more.
So although the view count isn't that much
in comparison to all my other videos,
I still kinda wanna adventure into various different kinds of triggers and
in ASMRs and maybe start to get into the more serious ASMR stuff.
However, I don't really have a 3Dio or any binaural mics of the sort
so please do check out my Throne because I do plan to pick up a binaural mic.
However, I don't have the funds for it
so if you would like to fund my ASMR journey,
feel free to check that out there.
But for the time being, I'm using the Razer Seiren
to make up some of the ASMR stereo vibes, I guess,
and there are still plenty of things to think about.
So namely setup, I'm recently kinda working on getting comfortable
with the setup with my laptop recording setup to be able to record ASMRs in
and I kinda settled to NOT record them in my studio room ever.
This one right here.
Because if you have watched my ASMR trigger test video,
*bonk*
you would realize that that room is actually my bedroom.
Fuck's sake. This table sucks. (lmao)
And even that, with the air conditioner on,
it's making quite some noise so I don't think it would make sense
to record in a studio room with the computer fan going like crazy.
So, plenty of improvement has to be done,
including getting something to display my laptop
so I'll be able to control my OBS from there,
while keeping the laptop outside the room
so there won't be jet engine noises.
Right, getting onto MeloriTensei's video.
So what's next for MeloriTensei's video now that the PC is back?
So, I currently got a huge backlog of videos
that I planned to make but did not manage to
because the PC went poof.
So, now I'm gonna try to catch up to all of them.
And as of recording this video,
I have successfully done a few tasks
that I have mentioned in the [YT] Community Posts.
Please do keep an eye on my Discord and Community Posts
for more updates for some of the behind the scenes stuff.
But as for my videos, I'm planning to make some stream highlights
for contents that I've been wanting to make for quite a long time.
So, gaming stream highlights, namely one of them,
because recently I found myself to be burning out
a little teeny tiny bit and I've been running...
kind of,
I wouldn't say out of ideas,
more like kind of out of feasible methods to achieve
some of these ideas I have in my head.
So I kind of need more breathing room to create some of the ideas out
and hopefully ensure the quality stays pretty much the same
throughout the videos in the past to the present
or maybe even better.
I'm trying to make it better, not worse.
So hopefully you would spare me some more time for some of the tech videos,
be a little patient with me because there's a lot of prep work going on
and it's a little bit hard to prep these days.
So hopefully I can fill up that gap
with some gaming stream highlights.
Not to mention, I kind of do want to expand my videos
to not just tech but also some gaming highlights
so it can cater to the general audience and gaming fans I guess,
on top of just tech fans because laser focusing
on a certain demographic is not exactly my favorite thing
to do all the time.
However, I don't really have that much choice.
Not to mention, I do kind of enjoy gaming.
So, think of it as like an addition to my channel, I guess.
That way, this should allow my channel to continue breathing
while still having content pumping out every week,
all while still giving me breathing room for research
for the tech videos that I'm planning to make eventually
and also slide into one of the weeks.
Also to prevent future burnouts, I'm temporarily suspending
this "sussy site" that I have mentioned in my previous devlog
because recently I've found myself not being able to catch up
to whatever work I want to do on that site.
Not to mention, it's not my primary focus to do "more than usual",
spicy content just yet
and I think, to myself,
something spicy is just something's on the side, I guess.
Not exactly my regular thing.
So I hope those who are looking forward to those sites
be a little patient with me.
And speaking of being patient with me,
I thank you all very very much for being patient with me
because in the past weeks I've been working on compiling editing assets
so it would be far easier for me to search for editing assets
for videos that I'll be making in the future.
However, it has been getting really really taxing on me mentally
because of the sheer size of the assets I've collected.
So, I've only collected 75% of the first pack
but I hope I can make good use of it still myself
but my ultimate goal however is to make sure that I can gather all the assets
and I have, at least, 95% not needing to search
on the internet for assets anymore
and hopefully I can distribute it out so it would help future editors
and aspiring editors as well, not just myself.
I hope I'll be able to make it available for download when it's ready.
Now, if you're wondering why I didn't pull through
with doing 100% of all packets,
it's because there were 3 packs and they were massive.
And not to mention I'm feeling really guilty recently
for being on a hiatus for too long
and not pumping out any kind of content.
It's kind of killing my algorithm recently
and I don't really want to be forgotten.
So I decided to put a pause on sorting out assets for now
but I'll keep doing over time as I'm editing videos.
Right, getting onto the more uplifting news now.
I've said in my previous devlog
that I'll eventually be working on making my channel accessible
to Chinese viewers and Japanese viewers.
So as my first step, I've started opening up my Crowdin page.
So you can check out this website if you do want to volunteer
translating my subtitles into those languages.
That way, you would help upcoming viewers
to check out contents that I would be offering.
And I would also continue to commit making English subtitles
for all of my videos.
So this is not going to stop
and I'm going to keep making subtitles
because I want to make sure that all my viewers can kind of
get what I'm saying without relying on auto subtitles
because auto subtitles do suck a whole lot.
Currently on my Crowdin page, I've only covered 90% of my channel
at the moment because I've reached the free tier limit,
the word count of 60,000 words.
So once both languages have been translated completely,
I will delete those source files and I'll take the translations
and then put up the latest videos in as well.
So, people can translate those videos as well.
Now, if you're wondering how the hell would I get proofreaders
so I can make sure that the translation stays accurate,
I don't really have any plans for now,
but I'm looking forward to proofreaders who are looking to proofread
the translations that will be submitted to it's own page.
I'll be looking forward to getting applications for proofreaders
that are looking to proofread the translations on the Crowdin page
through my business email.
Do check out my PinCushion down in the description below
for the business email.
My only simple requirements for becoming a proofreader
is to prove that you have a substantial evidence
that you're proficient in the language that you're applying for,
all without losing the vibes and the meaning that I'm saying.
Now, you don't need to submit your certifications or your degree or anything
because certification to me don't really matter.
True skill matters instead.
However, please do not submit ChatGPT-looking-ass submission
because I won't be entertaining those
because AI outputs just don't reflect
the actual vibes that us humans give out when we're speaking.
So that's it, I bid y'all good luck down in the description below.
Now for one last brighter news, I've updated my Throne wishlist
so there's far more items now in my wishlist.
You have more choice in gifting me gifts that I have on my wishlist.
However, I've only added a small handful of stuff,
namely studio improvements like sound proofing panels
and random stuff that I want.
However, something still feels missing.
So please let me know in the comments below,
let me know what suggestions I should add into my wishlist
and if I should go balls to the walls to the things that I want.
However, there is one tiny roadblock you may think to yourself.
"If I donate to the Throne,
wouldn't that mean I won't have access to my Ko-fi early access?"
Hello early access viewers~?
Well, fear not.
I've actually emailed Ko-fi support
and they gave me a greenlight to do this workaround.
So if you donate on Throne,
as long as I obtain certain information that I can contact you in some way,
say namely your email address or something,
then I'll contact you directly over email,
a code you can use on Ko-fi that will discount
an item on my shop on Ko-fi by 99%.
Which means you'll only need to pay a single yen fee
to enter my Ko-fi exclusive content.
Now if you're wondering why a single yen,
that's because Ko-fi currently does not have 100% discount coupon at the moment
and I've passed that suggestion to them so hopefully they start implementing that
and allow me to do that kind of workaround.
However, as of recording this video,
I have not tested if this feature currently works.
So your mileage may heavily vary
but hopefully sometime around in the future, I'll get this tested
and I'll let you know down in the comments below whether this feature worked.
If it worked, I'll announce it on my discord
and the comments below and also in my community post
so I'll do some tests and I'll let you know by then.
Now I hope to bring more blessings and upgrades to my channel
in the next devlog but I'm not sure when I'll have another devlog
but there will be one,
if there's any major changes that can be compiled into one video like this.
But with that said, thank you all for believing in me
and hopefully I'll be back soon.
After all the backlog videos, the streams will resume.
There, I said it.
With that said, please do financially support me on Ko-fi and Throne
and Otsu-Melo, catch you next time!
I, uhh, god...
I haven't had that much confidence in a while now.
Screw off, don't bother me.
Ohhh, don't change anything about that.
Don't change anything.
There we go, we got it. Perfect.
Okay.
My hands were frozen.
Finally, I can turn on the fan now!
Awh, it's so hot.
I'm just sweating like crazy right now.
Fuck.
Cheers bloopers watchers. Cheers.
See ya.