Is that a Supra?
Oh no!
Sorry, Taco Man!
New Fast and Furious movie looks lit!
You have not changed ever ANNA!
ANNA, I've listened to you
since Forza Horizon 3 now!
God damn it, that guy!
Melori is Bri' 'ish!
Congrats, you played yourself!
Scott: Wait, is that a WINGSUIT?!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Why are you third wheeling me already?
Fuck off!
Ramiro, you're not cool Ramiro, not cool!
Ha!
We can now pick our starter cars, let's go!
Okay, so that's the Corvette
we were driving earlier.
That's the Bronco we were driving as well.
Is that a Supra?
Dude, is that a Supra?
Sorry, I gotta do that.
I gotta do that.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
There's a Supra!
But I also like, I also like,
I also like sports cars though.
I like supercars.
You know what?
Fuck the Corvette, go with the Supra.
Okay, Supra it is, let's go!
Oh, this one has a Toyota engine.
Or is this rebadged?
Cap, cap, cap, cap, cap, cap, cap.
Hard cap.
This is, tell me this is a rebadge.
Tell me this is a rebadge.
I have a feeling that this is a Supra.
Oh, right, here we go.
Hmm, what can I do?
I love moms.
Love moms.
You know what?
YOUR MOM is much better.
Don't you think?
So it fits all eight letters
and it calls out everyone's mom.
Should we go for that?
Oh my god.
I could not pass up this opportunity.
"I swear to god, yes, yes."
Let's go!
Controller disagrees.
Oh, no!
I was not expecting that.
Wait, there's a filter!
Okay, we can't do YOUR MOM apparently.
Alright, okay.
We can't do YOUR MOM.
Hmm.
For now, we'll put this as a placeholder.
Oh no, it's Bass Arena again.
Oh, we have to stop.
The game should have told us to stop.
I just pressed on.
Alright.
Wait.
What is coming?
It sounds like bikes.
Huh.
Sorry, taco man!
What are we dropping?
What are they dropping?
Bikers, of course!
Ah!
No!
I wasn't looking.
New Fast and Furious movie looks lit.
Introducing new Vin Diesel
that crashes from time to time.
How invincible are these bicycles?
I gotta be honest, what the heck?
Vin Gasoline!
Nah, he's just taking a shortcut.
Don't worry about him.
Woohoo!
What the fuck?
No!
What are they planning?
Ayo, ayo!
Wee!
Oh my god, I'm just scratching it.
I'm just scratching away.
This is not first place, do you know that?
A parachute.
Do you know what's called a parachute?
Stunt Team - Special Cargo.
What an interesting "vehicle name".
"Special Cargo".
Oh, we're taking my Supra again.
Let's go.
Where are we heading?
Get out of the way!
God damn it!
Ergggghhhh!
Oh!
Oh, the drift!
Oy, oy, oy, oy, oy, oy, oy, oy!
Holy shit!
That was unintentional.
But that was great.
That was sick.
Wait, we're supposed to turn left!
Eee!
You have not changed ever, ANNA.
I just realized about you.
ANNA, I've listened to you
since Forza Horizon 3 now.
Oh, okay.
Choose a story first, huh?
So, should we go for wild storms?
Or should we look for a barn vine?
VW, right!
Let's go!
But before that, can we get back
inside the festival, though?
Oh, yes!
Please be quiet, ANNA.
Right, let's head back.
Let's get driving for real.
Let's have a calming, calm driving experience.
With absolutely no chaos.
Oy, oy, oy, oy, oy, oy, oy!
AHH!
God damn it, that guy!
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh!
AHH!
Find a- oh.
Help Alejandra find an old car.
Right, we'll do that.
Huh.
AHH!
EH?!
Okay, okay, let's try to drive properly.
I've been watching and driving.
We're going to have another
Samir moment at this point.
Samir!
You're breaking the car!
FAST SHARP RIGHT!
AHH!
I was reading
the subtitles because she was speaking Spanish!
I like this.
For real, though.
Woah, woah, woah, woah, woah, woah, woah, woah.
We're supposed to get in there.
Hey, yo.
Mel- Melori is Bri' 'ish.
I don't- I don't know if you
can trust me with a truck.
Let alone driving a car.
"Don't worry, all you have to do
is try not to Isekai someone."
I think we will have to Isekai a couple of
grasses and- and- and- and- and electrical poles.
Nah, we'll jump it.
Get the Vocho back in the garage.
Wait a second, did I just miss it?
I was not looking at the map.
Oof.
"You missed the waypoint, bro."
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Did I miss the waypoint?
Wait, where- where was it?
That's the destination?
Wait!
Shit!
Where was the waypoint?
Hold on, where was the waypoint?
Oh-
I took it all the way to the festival!
"Congrats, you played yourself."
Oh my god!
"10 out of 10 driving skills", I know, right?
I was not even looking at the waypoint.
Thanks, chat.
Okay, let's- let's begin again.
This is why I love Forza.
You won't realize you get
lost until someone tells you.
"There- there's a minimap on your left, bro."
I know, I know.
I'm aware.
I played- I played 3 and 4 and
I- I know there's a minimap.
I just- I wasn't even looking.
"As a Forza expert, I'm disappointed in you."
I'm so sorry!
Hehehehe!
Okay, we're here.
"Nice, you didn't miss it this time."
Hehehehe!
Right, what- what should we do?
Should we do a normal event or should we do
some collab events or should we do rally racing?
Let's start with this for now.
Yeah, let's do a little racing.
Right, let's get in the event.
Ooh, we can PvP!
Or we can co-op.
Yeah, of course not PvP.
I- I haven't- I haven't gotten
any car upgrades yet, so…
Hehehehe!
For sure, we're not going to PvP.
But- ooh, okay.
These- ooh, these cars that I have in hand, holy…
Okay, okay, okay.
I wanna take my Supra.
I wanna- I wanna- I wanna
take my Supra because, um…
I wanna- I wanna have the- the
genuine story effect, you know?
For every red team beaten.
Ooh…
Is this online or is it-
Oh, it's Drivatar.
Yeah, I can see- I can see the- the icon.
It says Drivatar.
It's a team tag, huh?
Alright.
Ah, ah, ah!
I engage drifting too soon!
But we all know it's- this is Forza.
What- what do you expect?
Oh, shit!
I've touched it, right?
Okay, I've touched it, so that means it worked.
It worked.
I didn't miss a thing.
No!
I'm losing them!
No- nononononono-
Oh, shit!
Oh my God, you're single-handedly carrying me!
I feel so bad for you, oh shit.
I gotta carry at least like- what?
100 points?
Come on.
Let me- let me carry a hundred points at least!
Shit!
くそ… (shit!)
Ah!
No!
Okay, I gotta look at the minimap.
I gotta pay attention to
the minimap a little more.
Cause we don't have co-drivers, so…
Oh shoot, oh shoot.
Ah!
Damn it!
All the cosmetic damage.
We're not fine.
This is what I say- what I call as Daijobu'nt.
No!
Ah!
Oh no, I suck so bad!
No!
Alright.
No, shoot!
The one second I look at
the chat and then I'm gone.
Oh shit!
Oh shit, I'm too slow.
That was a really bad play!
Ah, shit!
Oh my God, I suck so bad at this.
Hahahahaha!
Wait, your car is missing!
Wait, what?
Your car is missing on the top there.
What the heck happened?
DNF.
There's XP for not finishing?
Wow, okay.
Oh!
He disappeared!
Go!
One is not like the other.
Everyone is having stock designs.
Ah!
Nice driving, bro.
Let's go!
Weee!
Get out of the way!
Yee!
Wah!
No!
Shit!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
I'm losing everyone!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Oh shit!
Did I touch it?
Nope, I missed it.
So I lost all points just
by falling off like that.
Oh, dang it.
Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah!
Lesson learned.
Lean a little on the right,
then turn left a little.
God, I suck so bad at this.
I was doing so well at first, and then
everything just comes crashing down.
The moment I hit that wall earlier.
Oh no, there's the timer.
Out of the way!
Give me the points at least!
Touched it!
Let's go!
Ah!
Come on!
Let's go!
I got some points!
I carried some points!
Ah!
Oh my god, what was that dance?
That dance though!
It's that, it's that, it's my boo dance.
That, "at night, I think of you~".
Oh my god.