You can tell I'm trying to keep up,
but I'm still editing the previous video as I'm filming this video.
Welcome to behind the scenes I suppose.
Kon-Melo.
This time round, this is going to be a very very different video.
So, it's again, once again one of those story time videos
that you saw in the previous video.
But, I'm going to be talking about a device
that is not alive anymore in the hands.
It's pretty much dead, so I can't really turn it on.
So this is going to be a really, really short video.
But, this is going to be a video that is going to get you understand
how I'm feeling that led to this device being quite dead.
It's a Razer Phone 1.
That's right.
So I bought into the old Razer Phone 1
because I thought to myself, man, Razer made cool product.
Well, at least that's what the innocent part of me used to say
before I learned the anarchy of businesses.
So, once I picked up the Razer Phone 1,
it was a pretty pleasant experience from the get go.
It was really smooth because it was one of the first phones
to have a higher refresh rate display.
And, it had a pretty decent Snapdragon 835.
So with a Snapdragon 835, it was pretty fast,
it was pretty lightning snappy smooth.
And, I was able to enjoy pretty much any games at smooth 60
with little to no issue.
Except, there may be some issues relating to the body of the device.
So, this Razer Phone is entirely made out of aluminum on the outside.
So, it's kind of heat conductive to many aspects.
So, when I was gaming on Honkai Impact,which was at the time
one of the most graphically demanding games on a mobile phone.
The vapor chamber cooling that was apparently in there was kind of cool.
It was working as expected really really quick.
But, it was getting really toasty and painful for my hands.
So, what did the naive little Mel did
to ensure that the cooling is consistent and everything?
She grabbed ice.
Put ice onto the phone.
Now, this is not what killed the phone however.
That was just what the past me did stupidly.
But, we'll get into what really killed the phone soon.
The phone really was amazing because it sounds amazing
albeit with Dolby Atmos and some enhancements on it.
But, it was a pretty well-rounded phone except for its software.
So, its software came in was pretty much a clean stock Android
with a few Razer additions to the built-in software.
So, like it came with Razer dedicated Dolby Atmos.
And, that's not much it honestly.
Yeah, I gotta be honest.
It's really really clean stock Android.
However, one thing I do not like about Android manufacturers
is their non-commitment to security updates.
Like I don't care if you don't add any features to it.
But, do some security updates because this is where the first realization
of Android business anarchy taught me.
So, my bank called me and told me
that my phone is slightly out of date in its security updates.
And, they want to make sure that I'm constantly connected with the bank app.
So, they told me that the next update is going to enforce this new
security restrictions where it checks for the update patch
that this current Android is on.
And that blocks devices with updates that are far behind over a year.
And, at that time I did my check and I realized that Razer
has not updated Android for nearly a year.
It was crazy long.
So, then I realized, okay, what do I do?
We can't just not use the bank app.
I gotta move money around.
So, with not many other options behind,
at that time I don't really have any other phones.
This was the only phone.
I brought my old iPhone back into my pocket
and its only job is to use the bank app.
It's not being my daily driver.
No, no, no.
It's not doing any of the sort.
All it does is be my bank app.
You may think it sounds stupid, but think about this.
It's an iPhone 6.
It's starting to get old.
It's starting to get a little chuggy chuggy laggy.
How would you expect me to move everything back there
and daily drive it again?
Especially when the battery was very very dead.
I mean, if you have seen my videos,
you will realize that I exchanged this battery just this year.
So, you could tell how dead that battery was.
So, it was kind of disappointing to me and I thought to myself,
"okay, maybe I could do something about it."
Maybe I could delve into the custom Android ROM.
Maybe that could help me a little.
However, here's another problem I have with Razer at that time.
They had really poor quality control
for the software implementation of the phone.
Or if I want to put it in the more advanced way,
the bootloader and the recovery is broken.
From the factory.
Broken from the factory.
How is that possible?
All I wanted to do was flash a new update or at least
have a clean flash of the stock ROM.
And that alone, the flashing script alone, bricked this phone.
Because, you want to know why?
So, what happened was, when I was flashing,
I realized that this phone can only accept one command at a time.
And it cannot accept a series of commands.
Which is what the install all script was supposed to do.
If you look into the zip file of the stock ROM,
you would see that inside there is an install-all.sh.
That's the script you're supposed to be running
to flash pretty much everything.
It's kind of pretty much what Project Treble
was supposed to do top to bottom.
With the vendor...
with the vendor drivers, system image, bootloader, everything.
All in a sequence.
Unfortunately, it froze midway and then it cuts itself off.
Connection drops after the first command.
Which coincidentally, was to tell it
to go to the different partition to flash something.
I don't really know what it was.
I just know that it told it to flash to the different side
and then that's the end of the story.
And ever since then, I've not been able to boot this phone.
So I decided, okay, let's drain the battery,
do the standard procedure that everyone tells you on Reddit.
Drain the battery and then plug it, charge it back up, whatever.
I've did everything.
Nothing brings it back up anymore.
Now there are some heat created by the power management IC,
but that's all there is to it.
No other parts of the phone started heating up
or anything during charging.
I thought to myself, that's pretty much the end of it, isn't it?
Like I got no phone anymore.
So I ended up daily driving this iPhone 6 again.
Which is kind of a grim story if you tell me.
Man, Razer, why are you such a disappointing company?
Now Razer, if you have not been updating security updates
for your Razer Phone 2, I'll be deeply disappointed in you.
In fact, if you're not going to make a Razer Phone 3, so be it.
We don't want to see you anymore in the phone space.
Because it was getting really close to being a Treble-perfect phone.
Like an alternative to Pixels.
But they screwed up everything with the quality control of the phone.
Everything is just lackluster and filled with unanswered questions
by the community to the Razer support.
Like if you go up to Razer Phone on the subreddit,
you see a whole lot of people facing issues
and have not had so much success with the customer support.
If anything, the closest they can do is just RMA it
and that's all there is to it.
So this is my personal terrible experience with the Razer Phone.
And this is what led to me holding on to a dead relic.
I've actually torn down this phone before.
So you can see that the speaker grills are gone.
Which is not really a grill
as you can see now that we've taken it off.
Like the speakers right here.
And then there's another down here.
That's it.
Whatever is over here is completely jack shit nothing.
And that's the camera,
that's probably the proximity sensor and stuff.
That's it.
That's all there is to it.
So I know the Razer Phone 1 was supposed
to be like a spiritual successor to the…
What was that dead company phone called?
So the Razer Phone was supposed to be a spiritual successor
to the Nexbit Robin.
I don't know what happened to the Nexbit Robin,
but this phone was pretty much one-on-one to the Nexbit Robin,
but with more gaming specs onto it.
And I gotta be honest, I am really disappointed.
This phone could be the simplest gaming phone in the entire world.
Well too bad, REDMAGIC has taken over this part of the category.
So, eh.
But yeah, this is the saddest story
I've ever had when it comes to an Android phone.
But that's not the end of the story unfortunately.
So without a mobile phone, I thought,
"okay, how am I gonna communicate with my groupmates in university?"
Well, this iPhone is technically doing the job,
but it's starting to show its age
and I have to bring a battery bank with me pretty much all the goddamn time.
Not to mention, in my pocket.
Not in the bag, in my pocket.
Because this phone dies so quickly
that it only lasts 30 minutes of its lifetime.
So I have to pretty much stay on tether pretty much most of the time.
Think of it like the phone is on life support
and I have to make sure that I don't end it, I guess.
So with pure desperation, and luckily I was on a contract with a telco,
I thought to myself, okay, let's buy a contract phone.
For a cheap low low price of 100 yen,
I got myself a Redmi Note 7.
That's right, the Redmi Note 7 is pretty much the cheapest contract phone
I've ever picked up.
Though the phone has been pretty decent.
There were some continuous security updates,
but it's not that frequent.
But let's be honest, it's always with the Chinese phone manufacturers
that always never promises on updates.
So I can't really expect much, but they have gone through a major update,
which was long enough for me to pick up a phone.
Or a phone.
So I picked up the Samsung Galaxy S10.
Unfortunately, the S10 is not with me anymore,
because you will not believe this story,
which is kind of crazy in my opinion.
So what happened is my mom dropped her* phone,
which was a Galaxy S8, and it shattered the touchscreen.
Like not just the glass, all the way down to the digitizer.
Complete shattered.
And it was unusable.
And she thought to herself, "oh god, I should probably get a new phone."
And then I told her, "you know what, fine,
I'll just sell my phone to you, and then I'll get a brand new one."
And that's how the Galaxy Note 10 Plus that you've been seeing
in the previous videos all these times, came to be.
So this is my goofy ass experience with Android phones.
It was such a crazy anarchy, that it made me jump back to iPhones.
Not because of these bad experiences,
but the anarchy of business that happens in the business world.
It's kind of more to favor the business people, than to favor the user.
So if I can't run with a phone for more than 4 years,
without it running into serious, fatal problems every time,
why should I be trusting a certain company for that?
So I've kind of lost my mind, and I went for an iPhone 12 Pro Max.
But I don't regret getting an iPhone 12 Pro Max.
I'm there for the performance, not the wall garden.
I've said multiple times on the Alternative Apps video in iOS,
that I use phones mainly for the performance and longevity.
And I couldn't care less about the ecosystem.
The ecosystem has nothing to do with me at the moment,
because I don't really care too much about customizability,
and sideloading is kind of a side thing to me, honestly.
It doesn't really affect me as much.
So there you have it.
This is another crazy story,
and I hope this doesn't come off as an anti-Android, pro-Apple
kind of looking ass video.
I am not siding with any side.
I still think Android has a lot of potential,
and Google is still making some teeny tiny strides on making it better.
But they also have a lot of L's,
especially from, as of the time of filming,
Google Play started rolling out a new, I wouldn't call it an API,
but a flag that allows developers to prohibit people from sideloading
a certain app of their making.
But I don't think that's too big of an issue.
I think this is more of a security concern for, say, bank apps
and stuff like that.
But the fact that Google did not address it specifically for bank apps,
kind of goes to show that they couldn't really care less
about the freedom of Android users.
But I got my fair share to burn on Apple.
But with all the ecosystem thingy out of the way,
I honestly don't have much opinion about it.
Because I've been using this iPhone 12 for four years now.
I mean, just a few weeks it will be four years old from the time of filming.
And the battery still kind of stands.
And considering how consistent Apple has been
with their software updates with their phones,
I would like to service the battery and keep going with it.
Especially when I'm at this time
where I actually cannot afford any other phones.
I seriously don't have any money.
And I'm still trying to grasp onto dear life.
Trying to make the best out of the content
and best out of my life for you,
for everyone who's watching this video in these tough times.
But yeah, anyways, with that said,
thank you so much for chilling with me.
And be sure to subscribe.
Be sure to share me around in all your socials
if you do kind of enjoy me.
And suggest more content, I guess.
What kind of content do you want to watch out of me?
And I don't know.
If you want to hear more story times out of me,
let me know in the comments below.
And with that said, I hope you like this anarchy of an Android story.
And I'll see you guys next time.
OtsuMelo deshita.
Woo~
[Ko-fi] Thank you for supporting me financially!
Member: Jo
[MeloriTensei 転性メロリ] Thank you for watching!
Check out my other contents!
Sheesh.