So this video is gonna be a whole lot different
and I'm gonna start experimenting around with who I can be probably
quote-unquote "inspired by"
So in the past videos, you've been calling me DankPods from Temu
and I kind of appreciate that as a joke, honestly
So how about have this video for a little change?
Hello everybody and welcome-
Oh fuck
That felt so unnatural
Kon-Melo and welcome back to another video
If you know who I'm referencing, please let me know in the comments
and today we're gonna have a very short and simple video
kind of showcasing what I have done to the phone
that I've mentioned in a past video.
This is the Redmi Note 7 which is codenamed lavender
and a while ago I said that I'm not gonna be on crDroid for long
and not for long have I really done so.
So, I basically hop on to the said installer
surprising surprising
it does have an installer
and it simply just tells you to turn on developer options
and turn on USB debugging and make sure your bootloader is on
and plug in the device and away you go.
You're off to the races, which was shockingly simple
and insanely accessible.
At least, it's only accessible from the user-end.
However from the developer-end it comes in really tough
and the operating system we're gonna be talking about is
Ubuntu Touch
So what's so different about Ubuntu Touch?
So Ubuntu Touch is...
primarily just trying to be an alternative operating system.
You know how there's, on the PC
There is Windows and then there's Mac OS and then there's FreeBSD
and then there is Linux.
With a whole lot of other distros using the Linux kernel.
Forgive the really husky voice that I currently have because
if you hadn't read my community post, I've gone sick in the past week.
So I'm still kind of trying to recover
and there's still remnants of phlegm inside my systems
that I'm still trying to get out.
But I can't wait to get this video out no matter what
So I don't really know much about Ubuntu Touch
And I have not really done too much research prior
because I don't really know where to start
So let's get straight on with my first impressions about this operating system.
It's...
overwhelmingly different in a way that it's yet so familiar yet.
So overwhelmingly different so like for the start you think
instinctively you would open the applications by clicking...
I don't know swiping up or something like that
whereas on Ubuntu, both the PC and the phone side,
you have something like GNOME where you have the application toggle
on the corner of the screen.
So like say the Ubuntu GNOME, you would have it on the top corner
or on the dock.
Whereas here it's right here in the bottom corner.
Sometimes it works, most of the time it does work.
But when I say sometimes it works, I mean like
when the touch kind of failed on me at times
(At the time of me trying out the OS for the first time,)
But most of the time it should work.
(which was long ago, it was on the Nexus 6P,)
So it opens up like a full application thingamajig
(where the touchscreen is broken AF.)
and on stock, surprising to me, that it has barcode reader by stock
So I don't know what you would use on a barcode reader
because the icon says QR code and the name says barcode.
It's a little bit confusing to me.
I have not done any tests because I don't have barcode to scan, unfortunately.
But I'm sure it'll be useful for some people
who are looking to use it on a QR code or something to connect to Wi-Fi
or something like that.
I'm not really too sure if this works on Ubuntu touch
So, please let me know in the comments below.
And then we finally also met with calculator, calendar,
camera, all the usual stuff and then this confuses me.
There is External Storage and then there's a File Manager.
Why aren't they the same place?
Like on that one app.
Why is there a separate app called External Storage?
Now this is my very first time starting up this application.
So I don't really know what to expect out of it.
Well, that was taking quite long.
(After a whole minute...)
Well, disappointingly, I want to get out of here.
So how do we do that?
So there's two ways, so you don't really pull it up, unfortunately.
Because pulling up does nothing.
That's not what we do here in Ubuntu touch
Instead if you want to bring up the dock, you bring up from the left side.
So that's the dock.
However, if you want to bring up an app switcher,
which is what we usually use, you will bring it up from the right side.
So it brings up like a book like kind of pattern
and then to end the application you swipe it up and
you're back to the home screen.
So let's continue with that.
And then we got the gallery, media player, pretty classic stuff,
messaging
Then there's something called the Morph Browser.
I don't know why it did not come with Mozilla Firefox or something.
But I'm not too sure what the Morph Browser is because I haven't really touched it.
Then we got the music player, the notes,
and then there's something called the OpenStore.
Sounds a little different to me and I've never really heard of it.
But I have tried it for one application
and you'll see what I mean later.
And we got the phone, then we got the system settings,
terminal as per usual.
We got weather built-in and then
well, this is not really built-in
But I have installed YouTube through the OpenStore
We get into the OpenStore,
you just get into the OpenStore
and it kind of feels a little bit like the Canonical Store to some extent
but on mobile, so
There's a whole lot of open source application that you could kind of look for
and I'm sure a lot of people will find good use of it.
But to me it felt a little bit.
I don't know.
Maybe there's a little lot more open source usage.
Maybe it's just me.
I'm not really too sure but it does look like there's a whole lot of choice
I gotta be honest, but I haven't really see myself actually daily driving it
to the point that I have actually gotten used to it
So I don't really know much.
Oh my god, people still call it Google Mail
and then there's a whole lot of unofficial web app
that is to make up for the lack of applications that
that you can't really find on this platform primarily because
no one really sees this as a viable platform I guess, to make official programs of
So unfortunately, it's all heavily community open sourced
So you'll be mostly at the mercy of the community
to maintain the usability of the app
But sometimes it's good particularly on the Linux PC side
I actually found this to be not too big of an issue
But I'm not sure about how big of an issue would it be
for Ubuntu Touch primarily because of the far smaller community
and a far nicher community.
I don't really see any Ubuntu users-
Sorry, Ubuntu Touch users even after the explosion of subscribers
and Discord users in my server.
So I guess that's probably how niche it gets honestly,
but yeah, this is pretty much the OpenStore.
So let's say what if I want to get into something like say YouTube
and if we start off with just a YouTube web app
Oh, would you look at that?
So let's say I want to open up Michael MJD's videos
and considering the display is kind of capable of 1080p to some extent.
I wonder if this web app allows you to do so
Well, this is surprising.
You can go all the way up to 4K.
I assume it's probably because it's a web app
and it doesn't really know the real resolution
that the phone currently has, so...
It's just bringing you everything but will it actually go up there?
Michael: heck, even back then, it was probably a bit of a stretch.
Michael: As this is more of a small internet appliance
Michael: that could browse the web, check email, read ebooks,
Michael: and do a few other things too.
Michael: So, when I found this one for sale on e-
(Mel pauses)
You know,
it's surprisingly good, I guess.
Albeit the web apps currently suffering with small things like
where's the title?
Maybe it's because the web app actually don't have a title up here
and then where's the like button?
Why can I only see the dislike button?
I think this is all pretty minor.
Can you drag it down to...
Oh yeah, you can do that.
Okay, that's cool
So it's almost insignificant, but it's still technically a web app to some extent
So you gotta have to navigate through the center console
that takes you around like
different tabs that you're supposed to expect out of a YouTube app
except unfortunately, it's a web app because there's no official YouTube app here.
So these are some of the shortfalls of being an Ubuntu Touch users
as far as I can see
However, it doesn't really stop you from properly daily driving it
if you're not really a very niche users like say you got games on it
like HoYogames and stuff like that.
If you're just a completely normal user,
so if you see yourself using something like like a general apps like
using it for office or some basic text messaging or some note-taking.
Then honestly, I don't really see how too big of a problem would it be
because I think it has reached a point where it's a bit functional
but not too functional to a point that is 100% reliable,
but it is still functional enough for it to be a working operating system
that you can actually use.
Now for people who are looking to tinker with this phone...
But before that, we're gonna quickly close off the applications here...
If you're looking to tinker with this phone,
fortunately, because it's Linux, because it's Ubuntu,
you can just feel free to open up the terminal and do your typical terminal things.
However, the default user always starts with "phablet"
and the device name is always "ubuntu-phablet"
and I mean you could do all the most basic things
like say for example updating your applications through apt
instead of using the OpenStore.
So like say
you can do "sudo apt update"
And then it's gonna ask for your password if you happen to have any password
which we'll get to that in a moment.
It's kind of a bit funny.
I gotta be honest
and then obviously you would have to go through repos and all that stuff,
typical of what apt does but on the phone, on ARM, in particular.
so you could pretty much do anything that you have already been doing here
except the major difference being is that you're facing with an architectural difference
which means the range of applications that you can install through apt
might be a bit limited and as not as far as I'm aware of
But when I was asking the question in my Discord server
about what should I do with Ubuntu Touch?
I've got requests of trying to run a Minecraft server on it.
But unfortunately, I could not find Java for Ubuntu touch.
There is not a repo that I'm aware of
that has Java or OpenJDK in some sort of way.
So I don't think it's possible at that moment
because of the limitations of not being able to find a Java as a library
and trying to run Minecraft as client.
Unfortunately, too is a problem because apparently on some of the forums out there
that I've searched up on Google.
They say that there is missing OpenGL library.
So that too is not an option unfortunately, but if you have any ideas,
please let me know in the comments below
and maybe someone else could probably give it a try
But someone I did see there's one very oddly specific website
that actually manages to run a Minecraft server on Ubuntu Touch
Well, big props to you, I guess.
I don't know how the heck did you manage to bring Java over?
But great job, I guess kind of shows that it is very possible.
Whatever you could do on the desktop or as long as you know how to convert it to arm,
then it might be possible to bring it to Ubuntu Touch.
So yeah, there's that.
'Right. Let's get on to one of the thing that jumped out to me.
So when you locked up your device,
by the default settings, for probably some of the device,
or half the Android device, the "double touch to wake" is on by default
while the other half do not.
So like I'm sure the Pixels do not have it on.
Maybe I may be remembering it wrongly, but please correct me in the comments.
But specifically Samsung double tap to wake is, I think on.
(Correct me if I'm wrong.)
So instinctively, I did that and unfortunately, it doesn't wake up.
So I have to press the power button.
You'll be met with that which is kind of interesting
It's a bit, well, odd
I'm not really too sure what this signifies like this ring thingamajig.
But it kind of did confuse me a little bit.
So and then to unlock you can swipe either sides.
So you can swipe to the left you swipe to the right any of the sides.
You can also bring up the dock if you feel like it,
which you can't really fully expand it, right?
Yeah, you have to unlock it before you can open it fully.
So it still takes you to home screen after that.
So...
right, so now getting into the screen lock part of things.
So to do that we go all the way down to system
and then we go security, privacy, locking and unlocking,
and then lock security and here you can use a passphrase.
You can use biometrics, you can use passcodes.
So what if I set a passcode like say one two, three four...
one two three four and set
and it'll ask you if you're doing a digits passcode
Would you like to have a keyboard prompt or would you like to have a circle pattern
which is a little different to me, I guess, from the sound of it.
So let's probably give it a try.
Oh, so you could add you can add some biometrics to it,
but I'm not gonna do that because I'm gloved.
So there's really no point doing that and let's have a look
Oh okay,
that's interesting, one two three four...
It did jumped out to me earlier that it's that it says you can swipe to it
and you do that...
(gasp)
What???
Okay, that is cool.
It's like you when when your finger enters the button it touches
and then you leave it leaves.
That's kind of cool.
You can just swipe your way through it.
That's kind of awesome.
Well, the reason why I got impressed is because I was using the keyboard one
which was just a touch pad that is like a keyboard touch pad that you normally have
with a T9 dialing kind of thing.
So it was a bit unimpressive, but that meant for that particular style.
Right.
So there's one thing that was a bit funny with the terminal.
I just mentioned earlier and we're gonna get into that right now.
So on the start of the terminal, it would ask for your authentication
So instinctively you would type your password in
but it's using a full qwerty keyboard to do that
Hilarious, isn't it?
Okay
So now that we're in the terminal
like say, what if I want to do something like like "sudo apt" again.
So like say I press enter and then it says enter password for phablet.
To some people you would think password and passcodes are different.
Unfortunately in this case, it's completely the same.
So you just type,
and you're through.
Which is kind of a bit funny to me at times
and rare times is a little bit funny.
Because like I thought if it had already asked you for your permissions
from the beginning when you open up the terminal app,
then why did it ask you again
when you when you execute a sudo command for the first time.
So I probably need some explanations to that.
So, please let me know in the comments below for that.
But yeah, however I don't really have plans of switching this phone
back to Android because there isn't really any ROMs out there that is kind of
maintained or functioned so I kind of want to stick around in Ubuntu Touch
and hopefully, with more comment suggestions, on what you want me to do with the phone
Then let me know and probably give me some exact instructions in the comments as well
so that I know what to do
Then maybe we'll test it out on another video.
But anyways with that said, thank you so much for watching
and be sure to subscribe.
Be sure to notification thingymajig like everything, if you like it.
You know what, you know what to do.
If you like gaming coming out of me, feel free to check out my live tab.
I'll be doing a lot of gameplay streams on the live tab
because I did realize that I could probably just have gaming on that side
and then a little bit of tech on this video side to keep my viewerbase balanced.
So yeah with that said, thank you so much for watching.
OtsuMelo deshita [It's been ya girl, Mel].
and I'll catch you guys next time.
See ya
[Ko-fi] Thank you for supporting me financially!
Members: Aerostatik, Natalie, Jo, Xandra~
[MeloriTensei 転性メロリ] Thank you for watching!
Check out my other contents!
No, this imitation is not permanent.
Phew
That was a really simple video I gotta be honest,
although I got really nervous.