Computers.
We all use computers all around us.
Sometimes it will be for work,
sometimes it will be for gaming,
sometimes it will be something else.
Probably for content
consumption, content creation,
a whole slew of other stuff
that you can do with a computer.
After all, the silicone is very versatile
and we sometimes take it for granted.
And as someone who's quite an enthusiast at tech,
you may sometimes ask yourself
this age-old question,
how much of computers do we need to know
to build the absolute banger of a PC that I want?
Now fret no more,
because I got it all prepared again.
So I got onto PCPartPicker because
I can't really do IRL shopping
because I'm stupidly broke.
Sad.
So instead, I'm going to be shopping online.
With a little help of Amazon
and a little bit help of
whatever PCPartPicker has.
We're gonna try to build up a rig
for four specific different types of people.
And here I got myself a list of profiles
of four different types of people
that we're gonna look into and try to build up
a spec sheet for those kinds of people
and explain what goes into my
mind as I select certain parts.
Now as you can see with the first profile,
this is going to be a regular thing
because currencies are confusing to me
and I'm practically everywhere.
So instead, I'm just going
to simulate picking parts
based on how powerful each of them are.
So based on each of these
profiles without a budget,
we're gonna try to build a
specifically suitable computer for them
without absolutely blowing the living budget.
We're gonna be a little bit realistic with this.
So let's start with the first person.
The first person happens
to be a university student,
primarily low to medium
requirement kinds of games.
Example, League, oh god,
Valorant, and Apex Legends.
Watching university lectures through
YouTube and online school portals,
having online classes through Zoom or Google Meet.
So basically, a standard all-rounder
is what I'm thinking about right now.
But considering how we got a little bit
of Valorant and a little bit of Apex,
I'm thinking we may need to,
from the average scale, bump
up the graphics a little bit.
But I think we will do fine
with a pretty chill processor.
Let's get straight into creating a sheet.
Right, now that we're on PCPartPicker,
we're gonna get into starting the build.
Alright, with that said, we're gonna start out
with two of the most important criteria.
The person wanted to game,
but they also wanted to be
able to attend online classes.
So we're gonna need 2 out of 3 GPU
and a 1 out of 3 CPU kind of split.
It may sound a bit funny
and may sound a little bit weird
for all of you tech enthusiasts,
but hear me out, hear me out.
Usually, I would visualize
this in a graph in my mind,
but it's a little hard to get it out of my mouth.
So we're gonna start a little simple.
So a pretty simple CPU, I
would say sometime around...
but if the said person's
not really too big of a rush
when it comes to getting
the absolute latest of tech,
I would say the 12600K or 12600 would be fine.
The reason why I'm not going
any lower like 12400 is because
Windows 11 as a requirement is starting
to become a lot more demanding these days.
And with Intel's new core architecture,
where it has P-Cores and E-Cores,
I honestly think Windows would be
kind of strained on the E-Core side
for simple tasks like navigating the start menu
and going through the even so smaller stuff,
which could hold back the operating
system a little bit in my opinion.
Although AMD Ryzen would be the
budget choice for some builds,
in my opinion, the old
architecture arrangement may be
a little bit spread out I guess,
considering how all the cores
are treated exactly the same
and Windows may just occupy all the cores,
which then leaves them all busy
and it could just make core
performance a little bit less optimized
in my visualization to say the least.
I'm not really too sure if
it reflects the real world
because I've never really had the new
Intel's P-Core, E-Core architecture yet.
So if we are to pick up the
12th gen, say the 12600,
let's see how much that costs.
Oh, that's a…
okay.
Don't you think it's a little weird that the 12600
is currently costing double
the price of the 12600KF?
Huh, the Amazon market's a little funny this time.
Okay, we're gonna pick up the 12600k first.
We'r not gonna worry too much
because we're just getting started,
so we can change just about anything.
This is not THE FIRST TAKE.
We got plenty of lives, so
we can change them whenever.
So we're gonna start simple.
Right, for coolers, I would highly
recommend something decently quiet
and usually you would go with Noctua's.
However, other brands would be fine
if you're really tight on budget,
but personally in my opinion, I
really really like the Noctua NH-U12S.
If possible, for aesthetic reasons,
you can also pick up the Chromax Black.
We're gonna hold on to that.
This might change at some
point, so does the processor.
Right, following that, for memory,
personally I would highly recommend
that you would pick up 16 gigs and above
because Windows 11 is stupidly demanding.
I'm pretty much a heavy user myself,
and what I mean by heavy user,
I mean like there is at least 4x4 amount
of background processes on my taskbar,
and I would have at least one or
two primary heavy applications,
something like YouTube in 4k and
Discord with too many chats open.
Though in comparison with gaming, I
don't think it's really that heavy,
but it would be kind of CPU heavy to be honest.
But even with that, look at this monstrosity!
With all my background processes running,
oh shit it's not 4x4, I got more than that.
With all these processes running in
background, and I need all of them,
look at how much RAM it's taking right now!
At least this includes all the
applications that I'm using,
but Windows itself would
take at least eight of it.
At least that's what I've observed with
my own laptop that only has 8 gigs of RAM.
You can hardly run on that
thing with 8 gigs of RAM,
so I highly recommend you to
pick up at least 16 or more.
Though 32 may be a bit overkill
for this gentleman right here
who only games and attends classes,
so 16 gigs is the way to go.
And luckily with PCPartPicker, we
could just pick something like this.
So depending on your setup,
if you like faster RAM...
Oh my god, what am I saying.
If you're planning to have multiple sticks of RAM
and have multiple channels to
be utilized at the same time,
which usually means um.. "faster
bandwidth" as many would say,
but in my opinion I don't really think
that matters for that small size of RAM.
So I'd rather say,
if the university student suddenly
wants to start gaming harder,
I would leave them some room for upgrades.
So I would pick a single stick of 16(GB).
However, if you have absolutely
no plans to upgrade at all,
then you would definitely be better off with 2x8s
because two channels is always better than one
when it comes to latency, at least,
even if bandwidth does not matter.
Now in terms of RAM types, between DDR4 and DDR5,
this would vary significantly with the
motherboard that you're going to pick.
And this may be a bit of a misstep from me
because we should have picked the
motherboard first before we pick the RAM,
but the reason why I went for the RAM first is
because I wanted the builder
to be very price conscious.
Because in event the person picks a
motherboard that uses DDR5 memory,
you're going to be locked behind
a really really high paywall
for the premiumness of DDR5 that
is still going on right now.
However, you won't have a choice
for particularly Ryzen boards.
Starting Ryzen 7th Gen, you're
going to be on DDR5 only
and there is no DDR4 supported
boards in Ryzen 7th Gen sadly.
However, for Intel, they still leave
you that kind of option for some gens.
I'm sure Intel at some point at a certain gen,
they're going to start changing
their minds and lock it out.
So while we still can, we're going to make
good use of the value portion of this.
So we're going to pick DDR4 for now.
Now that we've picked the speed and the type,
we're going to look into the
sets of RAM that are available.
Now a whole lot of tech tubers
like LinusTechTips and JayzTwoCents
would likely be recommending Crucials or Microns.
Or if you're into significantly shorter latency,
you would also pick up Corsair or G-Skill.
For someone who's only playing
League, Valorant, and Apex,
I don't really think RAM latency would actually
make a difference for this particular person.
However, it would make a tiny
difference for timing intensive games.
So usually I would just go
straight for the value option.
Which looking through the price list...
or we could just sort it like that,
most of which on the value
proposition is from Patriot.
Though I have not really heard of Patriot,
so I can't really say much for them.
So instead, I'm gonna go with one that
I've trusted for a while from Crucial.
Oh right, forgot to mention, the
RAM speed does matter at some games.
Say for example GTA.
Though I'm not really a GTA player myself,
but I've seen some people with benchmarks
that have shown some differences
with the stock speed of 2133
against the speed of 3200 or 3600.
Usually for League, Valorant,
and Apex, 2666 is perfectly fine,
but 3200 would be better than nothing.
And let's do some quick research with the 12600K.
Now believe me, this build
guide is not really going to be
for beginner friendly, but it would be
nice for you to collect some information.
So building up a spec sheet
involves a lot of cross-referencing
and a lot of cross-checking.
Haha, lithography?
Intel 7?
You are a fucking joke, Intel.
For context, Intel 7 is not really
7 nanometer, it's actually 10nm.
Intel is just screwing business people up.
Alright, back to our search.
We're gonna look through in
Intel's official specifications.
On memory types, they recommend
that they officially support up to
3200 megatransfers per second on DDR4.
Anything higher than that would
technically be overclocking
on the processor's own controller end.
So that means if we want to stay on the safe side,
we would be better off picking up the 3200.
So in this case, we would happily take that
because that would be pretty much the fastest
officially supported to say the least.
Though RAM overclocking isn't
really all that dangerous,
it's just that there may be some degree
of instability that you might not expect.
The chances are hyper slim,
but they're never zero.
Considering how we're talking
about a university student,
we wouldn't want crashes to happen so
often when they're doing their assignments.
So it's always best to stay on the
safe side for this guy for now.
And on to the motherboard.
We could have done the
motherboard from the get-go,
but I wanted people to be RAM conscious for now.
And since we've picked a DDR4 RAM,
you can see that PCPartPicker has
also grayed out the DDR5 options,
leaving us only the options to pick up DDR4 RAMs.
That's fine.
Now looking through the popularity rating,
you can see that the most popular boards
are usually one of the higher-end ones,
so we're not gonna really look into that.
How about we take this a little bit wilder?
Considering that we're picking up the 12600K,
we're also giving an option for overclocking.
Even though we're not intending to overclock,
sometimes it's also good to leave
him some room for overclocking
if he wishes to experiment with it.
Say they graduated or something.
So for that, we're going to
outright miss out on the B series,
because on Intel's side, the B series
motherboards are usually non-overclockable.
And the H series is below the B series,
which means it's a little bit
lower-end to say the least.
So what we want is to start from the Z series.
So we got an option between the Z690 and a Z790,
though I don't really have personal
experience with the Intel side
of this of these series of chipsets,
but I'm going to try my absolute best
to pick out what's really best for the person.
Overclocking may sometimes stress out a module
called VRM, or voltage regulator module,
which usually only happens if you're going
to overclock in a really extreme manner.
Otherwise, most of the times, it
should be fine without a heatsink.
However, it's always best with a heatsink.
We're gonna have a good look at the
motherboard and see what they got.
In hindsight, we could kind of see that
there are heatsinks accompanying the VRMs,
even if they're not directly connected.
What am I saying even?
God damn it.
So looking at the motherboard,
we can see that there's currently two PCIe slots,
which are usually used by
GPUs and other add-in cards.
Four RAM slots, looks pretty nifty.
I assume it would be two channels,
because this two would be one channel,
and then this two would be one channel.
And we got heatsinks accompanying the VRM,
which looks good in my opinion.
And it looks pretty barebones and very simple.
Now let's have a look at the I.O.
Looking at the I.O., it does look very barebones.
We got ourselves mic in, line out, and line in.
It is very very simple.
We got one, two, three, four, five, six USB 3.0s,
and a single HDMI for integrated
graphics, if you're going to use that,
and a single LAN port, which is probably gigabit.
Let me just have a good look here.
Onboard Ethernet, one gigabit.
Okay, yeah, it is.
So it is a gigabit LAN port.
However, with my personal testimonies
with a whole lot of different builders,
at least a small minority of
them have personally told me
that they have poor experience
with ASRock firmware.
However, with many other creators they have saw,
they haven't really talked about issues
with it, so your mileage may vary.
However, ASRock is already a pretty named brand,
so if there's an issue, you can totally RMA it.
So that's not too big of a problem.
And considering how in terms of the price range,
they start to vary sharply from here on,
and we're only needing pretty much
the basic abilities for the person,
I say it would be nice to
give him this motherboard.
He can continue to upgrade them if he so needs to.
Right, from here we're gonna have some fun,
because the harder part is mostly out by now.
So we're gonna start with storage.
So League doesn't really take that much storage.
Valorant takes quite a number.
Apex takes a bangton.
I honestly think going full SSD
is kind of worth it these days,
especially with the current market at least.
If we're talking about the
lower end SSDs at least,
because we want to make sure that this is
university-student-friendly as possible.
We don't want this build to be overkill in price.
So like I said, this build sheet will
change at some point of this video,
so don't click away, because you and me,
we're going to look into this process
and go through the mentality of how I pick parts.
Usually I would start somewhere and
then I'll change things as we go.
So usually I'm a big fan of budget
SSDs, and what I meant by budget SSDs,
I mean like those lower end slower
SSDs that are still quite fast,
faster than HDD, but they don't break your bank.
And this is where price per gigabyte
starts to become important for you,
at least you, because this is kind of
metric that we're going to be using
when we're going through some of these SSDs.
But first, size.
What we want is to start making up
our mind about how much gigabytes
we want to give this said person.
Considering Windows already taking
up at least 30 gigs of the system,
but let's say this university
student has a lot of research papers
that they need to store, so we're
going to bring that up a little bit.
And now what we want to do, just
for safety measure, double it up.
We're going to give him 256 gigs of boot drive
and look through the lowest price range for that.
Whoopsie, we forgot to set the minimum.
Actually we gotta set the minimum to 240,
because some drives can get a little bit funny.
I'm talking to you Kingston.
Looking through the lowest list of SSDs,
there are a whole lot of
what's called the SATA SSDs,
which are 2.5-inch drives
that are through an interface
that is admittedly criminally slow
in the current times for an SSD.
So to avoid that, we're
gonna go back into the filter
and go through the interface
list and pick up all that is M.2.
You can clearly see that
I've also picked M.2 SATA.
That's primarily because some M.2 slots can switch
modes between SATA mode and PCIe mode.
So if we do pick up a budget SSD now,
the said university student
can do an upgrade in the future
to something a lot more faster.
However, in my personal opinion,
M.2 SATA is still a little bit criminally
slow, just like I said earlier.
So we're gonna take that out.
However, if you're into the
bare bones from the beginning,
you can feel free to have SATA on.
We're gonna be dead focused on M.2 SSDs for now.
So looking through the price list once more,
we got ourselves quite a selection.
However, I would personally avoid WD Green,
because the WD Green is very much
of a very passive kind of drive
that you would use to just store
stuff and never use them as often.
It's more of a power budget friendly
version of those kinds of SSDs.
The regular version of this particular
would be the WD Blue instead.
And going further down, we're gonna look into...
Oh hey, we got ADATA XPG SX6000 Pro.
However, I'm not going to recommend that drive,
especially whatever happened recently.
ADATA XPG, I'm looking at you.
Whatever you've done back then,
the silicon swap, that's not cool.
You have pissed me off as a former customer.
I built a PC with that SSD on,
and I was actually very surprised
because I was lucky as hell at the time.
I picked up one that had the Samsung chip in it.
For those who are wondering,
the XPG SX8200, okay...
the 8200 Pro is amazing when
you have the Samsung chip on it
instead of the other inferior chip.
We did a whole lot of series of testing,
and the boot times were impressive.
The download speeds are impressive.
At least it maxes out my
internet, THAT kind of impressive.
Doing anything with transfers on
that drive was super impressive.
However, after the chip swap, I don't
know if I can trust you anymore, ADATA.
Like, I was going to trust you
until you did this shit to me.
You betrayed me, bro.
So instead, we're gonna go further down.
Ah yes, the Kingston NV2, the
ye'olde trusted budget-friendly SSD.
Now, personally, I'm using the Kingston A1000,
which is kind of like the slightly
inferior older version of this.
And it is safe to say, in my
opinion, that it is adequately fast.
Though the boot times are not as impressive,
maybe about like 7 seconds or 10 seconds.
But it is still just as fast as
what a basic PCIe NVMe SSD would do.
So considering we're gonna hunt for
the budget for this university student,
I would happily pick that up for this person.
Absolutely in a heartbeat.
However, if you do want faster, there's
always better choices out there.
Say, for example, the Corsairs and the Samsungs.
But we're not gonna look into that,
but we'll get into that in a moment.
However, we could add additional
storage if budget allows us.
We're gonna allow ourselves
a leeway of budget this time.
And instead, we're gonna
switch to the 3.5-inch drives,
which are usually the HDDs.
And we're gonna use SATA interface
because there's no such thing as M.2 HDDs.
And we're gonna hunt for the budget options.
Now, if you're into the second-hand market,
you will be very familiar with
the Western Digital Caviar Blue.
The Caviar Blue is, if anything,
the tried-and-true budget king for HDDs
in that kind of budget price range.
However, there are more and
more affordable HDDs out there
that are slightly better in quality
and does not do tomfooleries
like what Western Digital did with the RED drives.
I'll attach those articles on screen
so you know what I meant by that.
So my trust with WD is a little bit
fractured because of what they've done there.
However, this goes without saying, I
still want to give them some chances.
We're going to do what we usually do.
So the capacity I want to give them would be,
I'll say 1TB would be the basic goal too.
We're gonna have our capacity
target starting from 1TB.
And as you can see, we have
a whole slew of choice,
but I personally would not pick up non-popular
drives that are up there because personally,
if you haven't had other people
with experience of those drives,
it will be really hard for you
to tell if this is good or not.
So I've never really heard of AV-GP.
I've never, I don't think I've done any
personal research of the Constellation ES3,
so I can't really speak for those drives at all.
However, what I can speak for
is the basic Seagate Barracuda,
WD Carvia Blue, and the Standard Blues.
They're technically the same thing anyways.
I mean almost.
They do differ by speeds.
These are usually the gambits of budget HDDs.
And if you're just looking to
store some university stuff
that you won't touch as much as often,
or you just want to store some basic memories,
I would probably recommend
picking up the Seagate Barracuda.
But if you're starting to keep important
memories like say family photos and stuff,
I highly recommend using cloud storage instead
or get a longer lasting HDD, which
are not those drives I just mentioned.
Okay, so we've picked out
storage for the safe person.
Let's get into the video card, the GPU.
Ooh, spooky scary.
It's one of the toughest things to pick.
If you don't have a baseline,
say a previous GPU you've used
on the desktop scene, not the laptop scene,
it would be really really hard for you
to gauge which GPU you would like to pick up.
So for me personally, I have
used the GT 730, the GTX 1080,
the RTX 3060, and the AMD RX 5700 XT.
My range of GPU selection might
be a little bit extra slim,
so knowing that this person's going to
be playing League, Valorant and Apex,
usually I can tell that this person's
going to use a 1080p monitor.
It's unlikely for a university student
to be using a 1440p or 4k monitor,
unless say they're an art student.
But considering how the profile
just says university student,
we're not really too sure if
they're really an art student,
considering there's no mention about
using a drawing pen or any of the sort.
So it's likely just 1080p.
And also considering the market
as of the time of recording,
which is the 13th of May,
at the moment 1080p is still usually
the budget moment for monitors.
So if we put this into consideration,
League can run pretty much on a fucking toaster,
so we don't really need to think about that.
Valorant can run just fine
on a mid-range graphics card,
and Apex would be a little bit
more CPU sided than GPU honestly.
We will get into that point later.
But with that said, in my personal
experience with the RTX 3060,
Apex can run absolutely fine on 1080p.
So with that considered, we could
kind of cut it down a lot further
if we're looking into considerations of budget.
So we're gonna try to add
these two for the moment.
Oh, how about the AMD side?
We're gonna not leave them alone.
We're gonna bring them in,
bring them up to the spotlight.
So we're gonna bring in the 6500, 6600,
6600XT, 6700XT, and the 7 series as well.
7600, 7700... that should be fine.
This will be our current selection
of GPUs that we're gonna look into.
And looking at the budget options,
it's taking us to ASRock, Sapphire Pulse,
a whole lot of them that are Radeon RX 6500XT,
but there's also Gigabyte
Eagle OC that is a 3050 6 gig.
So this is what we're gonna think a lot about.
If this person's not playing any AAA
games above Apex or any of the sort,
the 3050 would kind of be
barely fine on medium settings.
But if this person's planning
to play anything more than that,
then I would highly recommend picking up the 3060
or the equivalent on AMD, which is the 6700.
Oh, we could also look at the 4060s, add
those into the list, because budget reasons.
If we're looking into the 60s already,
then you would want to compare
against the 30s and the 40s
in terms of market prices,
because currently the 30 series
is coming down in prices,
but it's not coming down slim enough to
have an excuse to be the budget king yet,
at least in my current market in my area.
However, in some areas,
like say in the western market, the 3060s
would be amazing for budget reasons,
and there would be less and less
reasons for 3050s to be around.
So considering how they specifically
say low to medium requirement games,
I'd say the 3050 would do
absolutely fine for them, really.
There might be some things
that I may fail to mention,
so please point it out to me in the
comments below, because sharing is caring.
But for now, we're gonna give them the 3050.
Though we could pick up the Radeon RX 6500 XT,
but in my personal opinion, the
AMD drivers are just about there,
but it's not really there there, you know?
And on the talks about ray tracing,
it may be a little bit ehhhhhhhhhh…
Say what if the person needs
to pick up a ray tracing game?
Then, mmmm, you know, it's not
we're not really there yet.
Sorry Lisa, we're not
picking you up at the moment.
The Gigabyte Eagle OC is a
pretty sound option for me.
Usually in some areas, brand don't
really matter when it comes to GPU,
and the cooling performance is usually
always better than the Founders Edition.
So we're gonna pick those up for now.
And as for the case, considering how
we've picked up an M-ATX motherboard,
a micro ATX motherboard,
which means they are a little bit
smaller than the standard ATX size,
we would have the choice to pick up cases
that are smaller than the full towers.
So for that, we can select all the ATXs
as like a choice for the larger size,
and we're gonna pick up all the M-ATXs as well.
And let's look through the cheapest case.
Let's see what shitshow it's going to give me.
DIYPC F2.
Who is DIYPC?
What the heck?
Who are you?
I've never heard of you.
What the fuck?
Why do you look like a stolen cooler master?
What the heck?
Okay, I'm not looking at those for now.
Jesus.
So if the university student is
currently living in a said dorm,
then size would actually start to matter,
and we're gonna have to start worrying about that.
So let's look into the Cooler Master MasterBox.
Let's see how it's like.
Hmm, interesting.
Now considering if we're picking
up a smaller case than standard,
you're going to need to start worrying
about what's called the clearance.
So if you remembered earlier that
we've picked the Noctua NH-U12S,
we're gonna need to double check if
this case is small enough to fit in.
If this cooler is small enough to fit in the case.
Because the smaller the case size, the more
we have to worry about all these stuffs.
Hence why there's a lot of cross
referencing in computer parts picking.
So usually you could just
go up to Noctua's website
and head to [Support] and look through
[Noctua's Compatibility Center].
And in Noctua's compatibility standard,
you can click on [Cases] and
search for [Manufacturer].
So which in this case, we're currently
eyeing on the Cooler Master MasterBox.
So, Cooler Master...
Let's look at the model number... Q300L.
Right, getting back here.
I'm going to search for Q300L.
Let's look at the compatibility
and see if it's compatible with
our coolers that we just picked.
So the cooler that we were
picking was the NH-U12S.
And you can see that there's a green check,
which means it's fully compatible.
That means it fits.
So, good!
We've basically found a case that suits it.
Wait up, before you continue,
there's one more thing that we have to
worry about when it comes to clearance,
the GPU.
Because if you zoom in right now, oh Jesus.
Because if you zoom in right now,
look at how it barely fits a Strix
graphics card in the product image.
Okay, let's be real.
The Strix GPU is a three fan card.
And the GPU that we just picked up is a two fan.
So in theory, it should fit just fine.
So I don't think I would have to worry about that.
However, if you're building
a rig with a very long GPU,
you're going to have to worry about that.
For real, for real.
Okay, with that said, the Cooler
Master MasterBox Q300L looks amazing.
Though I'm going to pick up
the white color because I am,
I'm a big fan of white colors, honestly.
And now we're going to get into
the big hunk-a-dunk-a-dunk,
the power supply.
This is where things get a little bit scary.
But fret not, PCPartPicker
has a power supply calculator
that does an estimate of power
draw that you might need.
With that considered, it's
estimated to have 331 watts.
You could just trail onto that number,
like say, pick up a 350, but
I wouldn't recommend that.
Say if your processor ends up boosting,
it's going to start speeding up a lot more.
That means it's going to take more
power and then boom, we just lost power.
So it's always better to get
above it than to go below it.
So with that in mind, I
would highly recommend, well,
the old saying of the rule of
thumb would be to double it.
I'm getting, I was so tempted to say
"double it and give it to the next person".
Jesus, this is such a brain rot.
The old rule of thumb would be to
double it and go by that number.
But power supplies these days
have become efficient enough
that you won't have to worry too much.
Take that number, half it,
and then plus on top of it.
So like say 331, we double it.
So 662, half it.
No, not half it.
Um, if we, no wait, half, half this number,
331 would be like somewhere around 160 or 150.
I can't do my math, but say
roughly 400, 500 watts about that.
Somewhere around that number, 450 to 500 watts.
So I would personally recommend
picking up a 500 watt then.
So we're going to start from 500 and go through...
I wouldn't say the cheapest because I
wouldn't recommend going the cheapest.
In fact, I don't even know why I clicked on that.
That's stupid.
We're going to pick the top ratings for now.
Hold it right there.
There is another piece of paper
that we have to reference right now.
We're going to create a new tab
and search for [PSU tier list].
You're going to look for the one that's
currently hosted on LinusTechTips.com.
Where the hell are you really?
And search for this from Linus Tech Tips
Forum, the PSU tier list revision 16.1.
Though there are no newer that I am aware of.
So we can only stick with that for now
until Linus Tech Tips manages
to finish testing all the PSUs
and have a very detailed list in LTT Labs.
This will be our current list that
we're going to refer to for now.
But don't take it as gospel for now
because when it comes to building PC parts,
you're going to have some degree of skepticism
when it comes to certain
judgment of certain parts.
And everything you need to know, like
an explanation, it's all up here.
So please have a good read of that
before you go through the list.
Instead of going "Oh hey, tier
A. We'll take these then."
Sometimes it's fine to go a little bit lower
as long as you're not going
into the explosive region.
So what we want to look at is
currently on the top rating,
we got ourselves Seasonic Focus (Plus) 650
Gold, which is currently about 104 bucks.
We're going to keep scrolling down
and see what other power supplies
we got that looks interesting to me.
Since we said we wanted 500 watts and
we don't need any more than that really.
Okay, you know what, let's just set the
filters to probably 650 to be the top.
That way we can keep our
filters really really clean.
Right, EVGA.
Oh, I miss you EVGA, holy.
Let's have a look.
EVGA Supernova 550 G3.
Let's look through the list and
CTRL + F, EVGA Supernova G3.
What tier are you from?
An A-tier.
How interesting.
Low priority units.
Though I'm not really too
good at reading the tier list,
if it did end up on that high of the tier list,
I honestly think it would be pretty good.
Though personally I would be picking
up only Corsair or Cooler Master PSUs
because Seasonic is not available here sadly.
However, Linus has been
sponsored by Seasonic so much
that they've built PCs with them so much.
Almost every build they got has been
Seasonic, have you realized that?
That's freaking interesting, doesn't it?
If possible, I guess you can try out Seasonic
and be your own judge about this.
But I'm going to pick up the EVGA Supernova.
However, we can't really see the
price at the moment for the 550W
so we're gonna pick up the 650W.
Wait a second, are there
any 550W that has a price?
Oh yeah, Corsair does but the prices
are not really all too different
from the whole 100W difference.
So I'm gonna be picking up the EVGA
Supernova G3 as the PSU for now.
Operating system, Windows 10 is gonna be
dead because Microsoft being Microsoft.
Though I would personally
give them Windows 11 Home.
But considering the $30 price difference,
I honestly think it's fine to pick up Pro.
Now we've got our price list populated,
that is at least without the
monitor, without any other stuff,
without headphones, keyboards, mice
and everything, just the PC itself.
We've kind of racked up close to a thousand bucks.
And honestly for a university student,
a thousand bucks is like quite a lot of money.
So we're gonna see what can we cut down
and we're gonna run through the list once more.
Considering earlier when we just
mentioned that this person plays Apex.
So an Apex is particularly more of
a CPU heavy game than over the GPU
and we would have to make sure
that we hold on to the 12600K
because I don't think the
12400 can hold on to Apex.
Personally, I don't really think so if you have
all the background services running as well.
So I much rather hold on to the 12600K.
So we're gonna keep going through the list
and see what else can we
cut off from the price list.
Looking through the list, honestly I
can't really think of what I can cut down.
Though if you do have a suggestion,
let me know in the comments below.
But if the said university student isn't
archiving too much of their assignments and stuff,
I think we can kind of just cut off that HDD.
Though it would be bad choice for many people,
but in my personal opinion I
think that would be the choice.
I think we might be able to
cut down on the CPU cooler
by picking a different model.
So if we're going through
the lowest of the price list,
if we're going hardcore budget friendly,
we need something that
actually still cools that thing
without anything stupid going on.
So going through the list, I can kind
of see ye-olde trusted Cooler Master Hyper
212, but I think we can get better than that.
So we're gonna keep going through the list.
Wow, Amazon Basics cooler is here.
In case you don't know, Amazon Basics
is basically a rebadged Hyper 212.
Now that I've looked through
the budget section of the list,
I think the Hyper 212 would be a solid
choice based on my past experience with them.
So let's see how much we have cut down.
Oh hey, we got down to 900 bucks.
So we've saved essentially just 100 bucks less.
Can we go any lower than that?
Probably.
We're gonna see what we can do with this.
Apex Legends is still quite a
CPU heavy game though honestly,
but if that person knows when to
turn off Firefox or Google Chrome
or whatever browser they're going to be using,
then I think dropping the CPU a little
bit lower would be fine as well.
So we've already dropped the GPU, so
might as well drop the CPU as well.
Let's see how much lower we can go.
Looking around the market, we
could see that there's a 12400F.
Let's see what cores they got.
The 12400F has only six cores,
which is likely probably like 2E
cores and 4P cores, or maybe just 4E.
You know what, let me just
do a research real quick.
There's no fucking way right?
Oh, they're all P cores.
I see.
Though if we do pick it up, it
would save us a whole lot of money.
The problem is that it's not
really saving us that much
in terms of performance now, isn't it?
So honestly, considering how
we're already having a GPU,
if we are really really tight on budget,
we would have to save 25 bucks
by picking up the 12600KF.
So K means overclocked and F
means without discrete graphics.
What's bad about the F series chips
is that you're not going to
have integrated graphics,
which means for diagnosis purposes,
you're not going to have integrated graphics.
And this could be quite bad if you
do run into like say a PCIe problem,
a graphics slot problem, and you
have nothing to test out with
because if the slot don't
work, you're not getting a GPU.
So that's kind of a problem with that sometimes.
Am I really going to sacrifice that?
Hmm, how's the 14600KF?
Oh, that's a whole lot more impressive.
Never mind then, forget I asked.
If this person trusts their technician more
and they're not doing any stupid shit,
I think the 12400F would do fine.
I think they're going to
struggle on Apex a little bit.
With a few changes we've made, we're
gonna need to redetermine power supply.
Now we have a slightly shorter power budget.
So say 300, by half is 150.
So then uh 450.
So we could hunt out for power supplies
that are slightly lower wattage now.
So we're gonna start with 450
and end with 550 for the filters.
And let's look around the budget, but
be wary of the of the popularity rates.
If possible, it would be nice to
have some degree of 80 plus rating.
So like say bronze, silver, and
gold, and anything above that.
Try to avoid the standard 80 plus
because some of which are fakes.
If we're talking about the Chinese
made ones, they're usually fakes.
Right, looking into the budget section,
we're gonna look into which one is it
that we have been very
familiar with this whole time.
Seasonic 550 watt, 80 Plus Gold.
Looks pretty good.
A whole lot of ratings on
Amazon, 12 of them particularly.
"This thing hasn't blown up so far."
- hoefetus_deletus
Looking at the reviews, there's
a whole lot of people that
that said that it is pretty good.
So and it hasn't blown up on them I guess.
So I guess we could just kind of
safely pick up that power supply.
Though Seasonic has already
had a good deal of popularity,
so we're gonna pick that up.
And we basically save ourselves another 50 bucks.
So our final price at the moment is 754.
Now say I'm not giving Windows 11 Pro,
how about we give Windows 11 Home instead.
That saves us roughly 20 bucks.
Yeah, somewhere around there.
So we got a bit of savings.
Let's see how far can we go further.
When it comes to cases, you can pick
pretty much any kind of cases honestly.
You can buy a trash can even.
If you're an engineer, we're going for it.
So earlier I talked about sizing.
Considering how we're on just try
to stay within micro ATX or larger.
And currently as we see,
that MasterBox that we saw earlier
is the one that we just picked.
However, for some weird reasons, Amazon
has this fairly weird and unfamiliar case
that I have never seen before in
my life, which is the DIYPC F2.
Judging by its price,
ooh, "Really cheap and feels like
it would fall apart in any second.
Fans are awful. Spend an extra 10
bucks for a better case please."
Though a whole lot of other
people are either positive
or just outright negative for this.
And honestly, I don't know.
You be the judge on whether it's
worth saving 7 bucks from this.
Look at this. It's 47 bucks okay.
And then this is 40 bucks.
If you're willing to save 7 bucks, then go for it.
As far as I can say.
However, there are a whole lot
of cheaper cases out there.
When I mean a whole lot, I mean
like a whole whole whole lot.
You can easily find one for like 10 bucks even.
Just snag one.
Snag one somewhere at the side
of the street or something.
But we're gonna pick this for now.
And this would be our final price.
$724.24.
And there you have it.
Here's my build mentality.
Now that we're done with the first person,
we're gonna work on the second persons.
Okay, so earlier I said that
we're gonna have four people.
I've looked back at the list and I
realized that I don't need one of them.
So we're gonna do three people in total instead.
So let's get right into the second person.
So scrolling down, we're gonna see that
the second person is an AI enthusiast.
Oh we're getting into AI right now.
Oh red flag, red alert, red alert.
Melori is an AI.
She is not real.
She is a robot.
Okay, jokes aside.
Presumably, this person
wants to experiment with AI
to understand how AI things work.
So we're gonna give them basically
pretty much the basics of AI I guess.
And considering no budget
has been mentioned at all,
we're gonna go ham with it.
And saving money is not really an
option for experimenting with AI.
So we're gonna get right into it.
Alright, let's clean up our workbench once more.
And we're gonna start with CPU.
So most stuff with AI,
particularly like say retrieval-based
voice conversion, RVC,
or AI art, something along the
lines of say stable diffusion,
or upscaling, something along the
lines of using waifu2x and the like,
and maybe AI transcriptions, somewhere
along the lines of StoryToolKitAI.
These all particularly used mostly GPU
because the GPU is the only one that's
primarily capable of handling the task
due to their insanely high core count
in comparison to the core counts that
you have on CPU, which is very little.
So we're gonna be really focused on
the GPU side of things than the CPU.
All the CPU really needs to do is be
a computer that facilitates all that
and compile the results I guess.
We're gonna start with CPU.
And usually you would have
already been picking up on a CPU
that would handle a good deal of task.
So we're not gonna pick up
Intel for the time being
because we're gonna need the core counts
on every core to make good use of it.
So we're gonna be sticking to Ryzen for now.
This may sound stupid for most
tech enthusiasts in my opinion,
but hear me out once more.
I'm sorry, my brain works in a way
that I can't really teach you of.
It may sometimes be a little bit
stupid, so please bear with me.
I may be very very cringe, I'm so sorry.
So we're gonna start with the 7th gen Ryzen
because we're gonna need pretty fast RAM,
at least fast in the sense that
it's fast in megatransfers.
Because some AI tasks make
good use of either the VRAM
or your system RAM or both.
So we're gonna need to be very
prepared for both of them.
So we're gonna pick up the 7th gen
Ryzen or even the 8th gen Ryzen.
Oh we're not picking up the 8600G.
Damn it AMD, what's wrong with you on the 8th gen?
Okay fine, we'll do the 7th gen.
So for this I'm going to
recommend picking up the 7800X3D,
the most popular choice up here,
because we're gonna need most of the cores
and most of the level 3 cache if possible.
Basically use everything
that's there, go ham with it.
And I'm not a big fan of liquid cooling honestly.
If you're going to go liquid cooling,
then might as well go custom tubing
because AIO sometimes is way more of
a pain to maintain than anything else.
It's like there's more complications
with AIOs in my opinion.
So in my opinion, if you're perfectly
fine with your current room environment,
you don't mind the size, you can
absolutely pick up the gold standard,
the Noctua NH-D15.
And now we're gonna get into the motherboard.
This time we're gonna go ham.
When I mean ham, I mean go ham.
So we're gonna be picking up the X-series
chips which is usually the higher ends of it.
You could just pick up the B-series chips
because there's really not too much affected here,
but we're gonna go ham with
anything and everything.
So we're gonna pick up the X670s and
let's see what's the popular choice.
The Gigabyte Aorus Elite.
Huh, interesting.
And the MSI Pro X670P WiFi.
Though we don't really need WiFi at the
moment so I would happily pick that up.
Let's have a look at the VRM.
Ooh, heatsinked.
Nice.
It seems like we're in good business.
Right, so we're gonna pick up this baby
and we're getting straight to the memory.
So for some AI tasks,
they might end up using a little bit
more system memory instead of the VRAM.
So we're gonna need to be ready for that.
So at least 32 gigs is, if
anything, the bare minimum.
If you're doing something
like AI training outright,
you're going to need a good deal of buffer.
I mean not too much of a buffer.
I mean like say if you do pick up a
GPU with a very short amount of VRAM,
Windows at some point of time is
going to reallocate those RAMs
to the system memory as like the backup measure.
So you're going to need some extra headroom.
So instead of the 16 that I just mentioned,
I'd rather you pick up 32 gig personally.
So we're gonna start there.
DDR5 and we're gonna pick up two sticks of 16
so we can make good use of the dual channel.
And this is where we can decide on the speed.
We're gonna go with a little
bit of a populous choice
over budget options instead.
And we can clearly see that
there's a good deal of Vengeance
users and a G.Skill Trident Z Neo.
So looking through the prices,
this is much faster in RAM speeds
and it has slightly lower latency as well.
So I would pick that up absolutely.
Right, storage.
Depending on what you're working on,
if you're training AI, we're
gonna need a lot of space.
Like say approximately going into the hundreds.
Maybe if you're training AI art, you're
going to need way more than that.
But if you're training like
say AI voices like RVC,
then you would probably only need ever so little.
Like roughly around the tens.
So we're gonna swing in
between of those two extremes
and stick with I'd say one terabyte of NVMe SSDs.
We're gonna make sure we leave
no bottlenecks for AI operations.
So we're gonna start with
1000 and end that with 2000.
You can buy more HDDs in the future if you want
or more SSDs in the future
if you do run out of space.
But use this as your boot drive.
It would be nice.
And we're gonna stick with the 980 Pro.
Oh hey, look in the same price.
We got the 990 Pro which usually is much faster.
If anything, an upgrade from the 980.
Oh hey, it's the two terabyte.
To those who are picking
up the 980 or the 990 Pro,
please update your firmware immediately
when you're done installing Windows
because there is a fatal chip-killing bug
on the initial firmware of these drives.
You have been warned.
Right, following that, this is
where we get real serious about it.
Usually with AI workloads,
you would want to use some sort
of workstation GPUs of some sort.
But considering this person is just an enthusiast,
we're gonna give them consumer GPUs for now
because workstation GPUs are a little
bit on the side of being a bit overpriced
for the power that it provides.
Primarily because of the price premium
and the fact that it has ECC sometimes.
And primarily the fact that it is made
for specialized workloads like that.
Like AI and working on editing videos and stuff.
Basically specialist workloads I guess.
But the consumer GPUs are usually just fine.
And since we're talking about efficiency,
depending on how heavy this
AI enthusiast is looking at,
we could probably give them a 4080 or a 4070.
So we could play around with that.
Though with my personal experience,
the 3060 is just as good
for experimenting with AI.
Like if you're just a consumer, an AI
consumer rather than an AI trainer,
then I think the 3060 is
absolutely perfect for it.
But let's say if we want to play around
in the middle of the two extremes,
between just a consumer and a trainer.
What if you want to be on the middle of it
and you still want to dip your
toes into AI and stuff like that.
I say be on the middle.
So I would say somewhere around
the 4070s or the 4070 Super.
So I would give them 4070Ti Super.
Let's see if there's any pretty good ones.
Let's see if there's anything
really popular by the ratings.
Oh, Asus TUF.
It's been a while since I last heard you.
Holy.
There's 16 gigs of VRAM, which is pretty nice.
It is not much, but it would do.
The reason why I say it's not much
is because on my personal experience
with being an AI art consumer,
as in the sense of we just
create content using AI models,
that in itself has taken
quite a lot of RAM actually.
Having 16 gigs or more would be very, very nice,
but we can hold on to that for now.
Also to make things really, really clear,
I don't use AI art for commercial reasons.
I'm only using it to experiment
things and understand how they work.
Use AI models ethically.
And that has been the public service announcement
brought to you by MeloriTensei.
Right, continuing on.
A case.
Well, airflow would matter a lot.
So we're going straight to
the Corsair 400d airflow.
And power supply.
We're going to need to worry
about power supply from here on
because AI workload is a really
power intensive operation
and it's estimated wattage is about 566 watts.
If we do the same rule of
thumb that I just mentioned,
which is half that and then plus
over the top of the original number,
you would get yourself somewhere
around the range of 700-ish.
So we're going to go a little bit above that.
We're going to take 800 watts as a starting point
and we're going to hold on to that for now.
So we're currently being
recommended with Corsair RM850e,
which is an 80 Plus Gold, 850 watt power
supply, which looks pretty decent, honestly.
Though if you can find any power
supply that's safer than that
or more power efficient than
that, like say 80 Plus Platinum,
I would highly recommend picking those up instead.
Or even Titanium.
So like say that be quiet! Dark
Power that has 80 Plus Titanium.
But we don't really need 1000 watts
for that kind of build at the moment.
But if you do want to future proof
it, this would be a good choice.
But what I'm currently looking at is, um,
say probably, what if I want to
lock it down to strictly 850?
Will we be able to find a
titanium around that price?
Oh, yes we do.
There is a be quiet! Dark Power,
80 Plus Titanium, 850 watt.
"Mel, you didn't tell us, you've been
talking about 80 Plus this, 80 Plus that,
but you haven't really explained what 80 Plus is."
80 Plus is basically just the
percentage of power efficiency
when it comes from the wall
and then in comparison to how
much it's actually coming out
of the power supply to the parts.
So 80 Plus is basically just a saying
of "it is 80 percent plus efficient".
So like say there is a bit
of 20 percent power loss
and there inside the power supply itself
after some like voltage conversions and stuff.
But what you have to worry
about is the word after it.
That determines its efficiency rate.
So Titanium is the absolute top,
the most efficient basically.
So what we want is, we're going
to pick up 80 Plus Titanium,
which means we're going to have the most
efficient of power flow into the computer.
And operating system wise,
depending if you are using Linux
or are you using Windows, this would differ a lot.
But I think this person
would likely be dual booting,
so we're going to give them Windows 11 Pro.
And with that, we've settled
with the price range of $2206.79.
That is interestingly expensive in my opinion.
However, if you're willing to pay that
kind of price for experimenting with AI,
I say go for it.
Because this kind of build is kind of
a bit future proofing in my opinion.
Because for me, I like the processor
to be a tad ahead of the GPU.
When we do fall behind in the times and
we do only end up upgrading the GPU,
the CPU is not falling behind.
And we will still be able to
do the workload that we want.
So this is also why you would
see me picking processors
that are a little bit over
what the GPU can handle.
Future proofing has been in
my mentality this whole time.
So yeah, there we have it.
$2206.79
Here we go.
Right, let's get on to the third person.
Right, let's see what we got.
Third person.
Oh...
A rhythm gamer.
Plays mostly osu!, Project Heartbeat,
Beat Saber, Project Diva Megamix,
and SoundVoltex Konasute version.
So if you don't know what
SoundVoltex Konasute version means,
it basically means the arcade game
SoundVoltex if you've heard of it.
It's actually a game where you
have a series of four buttons
and two more in the lower layer
and two not on the upper end.
It's a really cool rhythm game.
I highly recommend you check it out.
So SoundVoltex made a home arcade version.
So basically you still have
to pay them to play the game,
but you get to play them at
home over online, I guess.
And according to some people,
you can actually save money
by subscribing to it on a subscription basis.
If you do play it almost every
day and very, very often,
this could save you more money
than you spend tokens on it.
And also big shout out to Harukawa Zinta.
That's my good friend that I found when
he was streaming SoundVoltex as well.
Do check him out.
Link in the description.
Right, let's get into cleaning up our
board and let's get straight to it.
So I'm not too worried about Beat
Saber, Project Diva, all the other games
because these games are
really easy to take care of.
What I'm worried about is osu! itself.
Because osu! in my personal experience on
this past many years that I've played for,
you might have seen me play that game on
stream during my previous Donathon last year.
That game in particular is a hell for me to manage
because this game is really CPU sensitive.
If you have too many background
services running in the background,
this game can give you hell with input latency
and stutters will happen if
you are really choked on CPU.
So CPU becomes a heavily
important portion of things
and we're gonna keep that very strictly in mind.
But considering a rhythm gamer
is usually just a casual gamer,
we're gonna start worrying about the CPU first.
Then we'll worry about everything else later.
So starting first, it would be very very
nice to separate the P-Cores and the E-Cores
so that Windows will be managed on the E-Cores
and the game would be deadly
focused on the P-Cores.
So the Intel's recent series, the Intel 14th Gen,
would be a great candidate for that.
Sadly, I'm so sorry fellow guys.
The problem is that hitching is a
real pain for every rhythm gamer.
So we will have to worry about that.
So we're gonna look into Core i7,
i9, and i7 Extreme just in case.
And we're gonna look into…
oh damn, I can't really
read the core family names.
We're gonna look into the 14th Gen like this.
14.
There we go.
And I can kind of see that the 14700K and
the 14900K are the most popular choices
but we're gonna compare between the two
because I don't think one would
spend this amount of money
for a 14900K just for a rhythm game.
So we're gonna have a careful good look at it.
So the 14700K has um…
let's see, 20 core count.
Okay now that we're on
Intel's page for the 14700K,
we can see that they're giving
it 8 P-Cores and 12 E-Cores
which is kind of good in my opinion
because Windows would have a lot more cores
to manage their background services
horseshit tomfoolery around.
With the 8 cores all left for osu! to manage.
Which is kind of good stuff because for osu!
in particularly, more cores
doesn't necessarily mean good.
But with multi-threading enabled,
it can benefit it to some degree
as long as these cores are not
being occupied by anything else.
So we have a whole lot of
breathing room from here.
When I mean a whole lot, I mean
like a whole whole whole lot.
That means we don't really need that 14900K.
We can go any lower than that if
we wish to save money from here.
So the price for this would be $389.99.
So we're gonna go see if we can
find anything lower than that.
How about 14600 in some sense?
There's no 6 yet?
Aww, drat.
Fine, the 14700K is the only choice.
We could go with the 13s but we're
gonna stick with future proofing for now
because this is going to be a real problem
if this rhythm gamer does not wish
to upgrade for another five years.
Right, CPU cooler, we can worry about you later.
We're getting straight to the motherboard first.
So the 14700K is an overclockable chip
so it would be a great added bonus to
be able to have a Z series chipset.
But it is also fine to pick up a B series chipset
if you're not planning to overclock it.
But there is a slim chance that
you might end up overclocking
on this kind of setup so it is always advisable
to pick up a Z series chipset for this one.
Right, getting on to the memory,
we're gonna hop back here and find out
how much is it supported officially.
With DDR5, it only supports up to
5600MT/s which admittedly is a little bit
ehhhh... a little bit slow
but we can overclock it right?
So according to the general market,
6000MT/s is the usual sweet
spot for overclocked gaming
so we're gonna pick that speed up.
And in terms of RAM amounts,
if this person knows how to manage
their background processors,
I don't think we would need that much of RAM.
Probably 16GB would be more than enough honestly.
But since this person only
plays rhythm games on this PC,
we would be giving what's best for
them, those channels with 16GB.
That's it, very simple, we don't need to say much.
But in terms of speed though,
we're gonna give 6000MT/s.
Let's see what they got.
6000, 6000, 6000, 6000!
That's the only absolute top that we can find.
And currently on the budget line, we
currently got the Kingston Fury Beast.
Sounds interesting.
And interestingly enough, if I
just look below it a little bit,
there's a slightly shorter latency version
of it at the cost of what, 4 bucks?
Yeah, just 4 bucks.
If you're willing to take that trade
off, I say pick this up instead.
It's not too bad really.
Now let's get into the CPU cooler.
Cooling the 14700K is going
to be one hell of a moment.
It says processor base power at 125W.
Considering how we're going
to cool a space heater,
we're going to need to worry
about cooling a whole lot more
and remember when I say how an AIO is a hassle?
Admittedly it is a hassle
but if you're going to build once and
forget forever, I say the AIO is fine.
It's just, if you live in a tropical
country or a very very hot country,
chances are there might be
an extremely slim chance
that water may or may not
evaporate through the tubes.
At least that's what happened
with my personal experience
and I heard a bit of gurgling on my AIO.
Maybe I'm just unlucky with
my own AIO and something
and I'm just hating on AIOs like a stupid Karen.
Okay, with that said, let's have a good look
at what I've known for a
long time, the NZXT Kraken.
Let's see if it can handle the thermal
design power that it's meant for.
Usually if you do have a
baseline for other computers,
you can have a look at the reviews of some
other processors based off what you know.
However, Intel itself is a
space heater so the 7600X is
not really close at all when it comes
to the TDP or thermal design power
or basically the amount of heat
is dissipating in wattages.
So we'll probably have to get out
of our way and actually Google it.
You may be wondering why I've
been calling Intel a space heater.
That's because my previous processor was a 7700K
and that thing is really really hot.
It's so hard to tame the Noctua
NH-D15 on that processor.
It's like trying to tame a dragon
but that dragon just keeps screaming
at your face for no reason.
And for some interesting reasons,
I looked at reviews for the more recent processors
and it seems like Intel hasn't learned a
thing or two about improving their processors.
Now looking at the compatibility
from NZXT themselves,
it is said that they're
compatible with Core i9, i7.
That's all we need to hear honestly.
However, it would be nice if we got
to see the TDP that they're supported
in the sense that if they're able
to cool down a certain level of TDP,
that would have been a great nice thing to see.
But I think this would be fine because
considering rhythm games are
not really a stress tool,
I think this should do fine.
Right, following that storage, rhythm
games usually have a good load of beatmaps,
say particularly for osu! and
Project Heartbeat players.
There will be a lot of community beatmaps
and you're going to be downloading a lot,
so I would say you need at least 1TB of storage
or 500 if you're really tight on the budget,
but 1TB is always the way to go.
I would have recommended the Kingston NV2,
but if we're going ham on the speed,
it would be best for you to
pick up the 970 EVO PLUS.
It has amazing boot speed, amazing
load speed, and durability?
God-send sometimes.
So I highly recommend that.
In fact, my current PC currently
has the 970 EVO non-plus,
but it is still very very good and
it boots really quickly as well,
so I highly recommend that.
It has great reputations.
You don't have to bat an eye at
the others, the 980 or the 990s,
because the performance curve is going
to get really really thin from there on,
so I guess this would be a perfect middle
ground for having a premium and fast SSD.
GPU.
Now this is where we'll have to
worry a teeny tiny bit about this,
because Beat Saber is mentioned.
Even though every other game
like osu! and Project Heartbeat,
they don't take as much, you
could easily pick up a 3060.
Beat Saber in particular,
depending on your VR headset,
say if you're picking up the Valve Index
or 5k and above resolution VR headsets,
you will have to start worrying a
little bit about graphics really.
So personally, I would recommend
picking up more than a 3060,
so I say somewhere around the 4070s and onwards.
Probably 4070 Super, at least that
would be my personal recommendations,
but you can go higher than
that and it would be fine.
But the absolute lowest, I would say 4070.
So judging by the absolute cheapest
that we can find, Zotac Twin.
Hmm, I've heard of you Zotac.
I was just about to buy you until
someone came up and undercut him.
Guess who?
It's Palit, my current 3060.
Okay, let's have a look at Zotac Twin Edge.
I think it would be fine performance-wise.
The cheapest 4070 Super I can grab in my country.
Ooh, interesting.
I think that would be the cheapest
4070 Super in my area as well,
but I don't know, you be the judge for that.
If you're looking for a hard budget at
a higher-end GPU, this is the way to go.
Right, on to the case.
I don't think you would have
to worry as much honestly.
You can pick up any kind of case honestly.
As long as they fit, you'll be fine.
And lucky for you, PC Part
Picker grays out these case sizes
that don't fit on your motherboard at all.
So you can just pick the ones
that fits, which is perfect.
And I've had kind of not so good
experience with NZXT's case,
particularly the H510i
because the H510i was a bit of a
cooling choke to say the least.
And it's a negative pressure case,
which means you would want the
airflow to be exhausting only.
No intakes, just exhaust.
Let the natural air do the intake kind of thing.
But I can clearly tell that NZXT
has started learning their lessons
and started making the Flow series cases.
So the Flow series basically is
the same as their predecessors,
but with meshes on the front.
So that means air now don't only come
from a tiny hole on the side here,
but they all come from the front, which is good.
Props to you, NZXT.
And not to mention, this is a mid-tower case.
That means it fits most
parts of the rooms just fine.
So I guess it would be a
perfect case for them then.
The H5 Flow would be nice.
Right, getting into power supply.
There's mostly boost clocks
than anything full clock.
So I would say you could
just go a little bit higher,
like say 750 watts and you do just perfectly fine.
So 750 watts and set that limit
to 800 as the absolute top.
Right, let's see what's popular.
Ooh, Corsair stands on top once more.
Ooh, how interesting.
The SFX power supply.
Though SFX basically means it a
little bit shorter than the ATX
and it's mostly for slim
builds that are for tiny cases.
I'm not really too sure if SFX power
supply can actually fit into ATX cases.
So thread with caution.
Not to mention you have to
face with this price premium
for the small size on top of
having 80 Plus Platinum rating.
So we're going to look into
the next few best ones.
Hey, our little friend Seasonic
is back with 750 watts, $84.99.
That's interesting, right?
We'll pick that up.
Oh yeah, here we go.
Operating systems.
Windows 11 Home.
I'm not giving two flipping
fucks about what they care.
You are getting Home.
You're going to stay at home!
Just joking.
If you do want to up the price a little,
then you will be fine to pick up a Pro,
but that would in turn bring up the price
because currently our price range is really,
really on a stellar high moment of $1809.
And we got a CPU strong sided setup
with a little bit of GPU strong as well.
Like a, I wouldn't say "strong", but
like a GPU mid to heavy kind of side.
And also a little bit of a
really high end motherboard,
maybe a bit overkill for just rhythm gaming,
but say in the future, like five years later,
what if this guy wants to keep
this very setup and not upgrade?
So this person can just
overclock away and just go at it.
Sure, the current price premium
sucks, but think about this.
If you have the salary for
it, feel free to pick it up.
But if you don't, it's fine to
go back to the B-series chipsets.
No one's going to offend you for that.
If there's anyone bullying you for that, tell me,
because it's perfectly fine to use B-series
chipsets on an overclockable processor.
If you're there for the higher boost speeds
or at least a better path to upgrade,
maybe say you're just saving up.
So you cheap out on the motherboard.
So you wait till the market price goes down and
you pick up this same motherboard
at a way cheaper price.
You basically save yourself more money again.
So there's that.
Of course you have to sell the old board first
to be considered saving money to say the least.
But yeah, $1809.42.
That's still quite a little bit
extra expensive in my opinion.
My kind of builds are usually
on a higher price admittedly
because how I like recommending
future-proofing a lot of the setups.
And I don't really like, you know,
making do with what's current
because you end up finding yourself
changing them every two years.
And that's usually not my mentality
because I like a PC to be
lasting about five to six years
and you only change a part
every so of that interval.
Otherwise, I genuinely wouldn't recommend that.
So unless you're building like
something like an office computer,
then going ham on the budget is perfectly fine
as long as you're not
cheaping out on the processor
because the processor is what
keeps the entire computer together.
And you can cheap out on the GPU.
That's perfectly fine.
You're only doing Excel sheets.
You don't need a 1050 for an Excel sheet.
But don't cheap out on the processor.
You're going to regret it five
years later in my opinion.
With that said, here are my three
different kinds of build mentality
for how I would build PCs for
these three different people.
At least three different fictional people.
And let me know what you
think in the comments below.
Be sure to press Like if you do like
to see more of MeloriTensei content,
tech, gaming, any kinds of
sorts, probably even vlogs.
I like doing tech videos here and there like that.
So I hope you enjoy because my
knowledge is still very very limited.
I'm not as knowledgeable as
Linus Tech Tips, JayzTwoCents,
Paul's Hardware, Bitwit, and the like.
But I hope that my knowledge is
of anything remotely helpful.
So with that said, thank you so much for watching.
See you guys next time.
OtsuMelo deshita (It's been ya girl Mel)!
See ya!
uuuuugh!