(Song begins) I do not have the actual lyrics in my view.
(Hence some slip ups and skipping)
Some parts of the English lyrics (while most having the original)
are modified to stay true to the JP lyrics (and avoid trouble).
♪ Yoru asa made, zutto soba ni ite ♪
(Day to night to morning, keep with me in the moment.)
♪ Aizu wo shitatte, iwanai no? ♪
(I'd let you had I known it, why don't you say so)
♪ Zenzen kidzukazu, mou houhou wa nai ♪
(Didn't even notice, no punches left to roll with)
♪ Atashi ga hoshii to, sou itte yo ♪
(You got to keep me focused, you want it, say so)
♪ Yoru asa made, zutto soba ni ite ♪
(Day to night to morning, keep with me in the moment.)
♪ Aizu wo shitatte, iwanai no? ♪
(I'd let you had I known it, why don't you say so)
♪ Zenzen kidzukazu, mou houhou wa nai ♪
(Didn't even notice, no punches left to roll with)
♪ Atashi ga hoshii to, sou itte yo ♪
(You got to keep me focused, you want it, say so)
♪ Itsu kara kimi ga (Ai wo sezu) ♪
(It's been a long time since you fell in love)
♪ Uchiakerarenai ♪
(You ain't coming out your shell)
♪ Kimi wa doushita? ♪
(You really ain't been yourself)
♪ Dou sureba ii no? (Oshiete yo) ♪
(Tell me what must I do, do tell, my love)
♪ Kakushigoto minuketa ♪
('Cause luckily I'm good at reading)
♪ Yametai kedo. Tamaranai ♪
(I wouldn't bug him, but he won't stop cheesin')
♪ Kou tsudzuketemo ii ♪
(And we can dance all day around it)
♪ Otagai ni semeatte ♪
(If you front then I'll be bouncing)
♪ Hoshii nara hora sakebe ♪
(If you want it scream and shout it, babe)
♪ Shinai to ikenai ♪
(Before I leave you dry)
♪ Yoru asa made, zutto soba ni ite ♪
(Day to night to morning, keep with me in the moment.)
♪ Aizu wo shitatte, iwanai no? ♪
(I'd let you had I known it, why don't you say so)
♪ Zenzen kidzukazu, mou houhou wa nai ♪
(Didn't even notice, no punches left to roll with)
♪ Atashi ga hoshii to, sou itte yo ♪
(You got to keep me focused, you want it, say so)
♪ Yoru asa made, zutto soba ni ite ♪
(Day to night to morning, keep with me in the moment.)
♪ Aizu wo shitatte, iwanai no? ♪
(I'd let you had I known it, why don't you say so)
♪ Zenzen kidzukazu, mou houhou wa nai ♪
(Didn't even notice, no punches left to roll with)
♪ Atashi ga hoshii to, sou itte yo ♪
(You got to keep me focused, you want it, say so)
♪ Mune wo hatte, Iki wo nonde ♪
(Let me check my chest, my breath right quick)
♪ Mita koto no nai in a dress like this ♪
(He ain't never seen it in a dress like this)
♪ Konna ni suteki hito wa nai ♪
(He ain't never even been impressed like this)
♪ Prolly why kimi wa damatta mama like zip ♪
(Prolly why I got him quiet on the set like zip)
♪ Like it, love it tamaran ♪
(Like it, love it, need it bad)
♪ Take it, own it ubatta ♪
(Take it, own it, steal it, fast)
♪ Boy, stop playing shuchuu shite ♪
(Boy, stop playing, cut to chase)
♪ Enryou nante iranai ♪
(Why you actin' like you shy)
♪ Shut it, save it susume ♪
(Shut it, save it, keep it, pushin')
♪ Shoujiki ni ie ♪
(Why you beating 'round the bush)
♪ Knowin' you want all this woman ♪
(And knowing you want all this woman)
♪ Ajiwatte mite ♪
(Never knock it 'til you try)
♪ Mawari ga hantai shitemo I have you with me ♪
(All of them fakers hating I have you with me)
♪ Tomodachi ga sayin' you mad committed ♪
(All of my buddies saying you mad committed)
♪ Realer than anybody kawari ga nai ♪
(Realer than anybody you had, and pretty)
♪ All of the body-ody, furete ii ♪
(All of that body-ody, get'a load o' them assets)
♪ Yoru asa made, zutto soba ni ite ♪
(Day to night to morning, keep with me in the moment.)
♪ Aizu wo shitatte, iwanai no? ♪
(I'd let you had I known it, why don't you say so)
♪ Zenzen kidzukazu, mou houhou wa nai ♪
(Didn't even notice, no punches left to roll with)
♪ Atashi ga hoshii to, sou itte yo ♪
(You got to keep me focused, you want it, say so)
♪ Yoru asa made~ ♪
(Day to night to morning~)
♪ Aizu wo shitatte~ ♪
(I'd let you had I known it~)
♪ Zenzen kidzukazu~ ♪
(Didn't even notice~)
♪ Atashi ga hoshii to, sou itte yo ♪
(You got to keep me focused, you want it, say so)
♪ Oooooh-ooooh~ ♪
♪ Ha-ha, ha. Ha-ha, ha-ha, ha ha~ ♪
♪ Yoru asa made, ♪
(Day to night to morning,)
♪ zutto sobani itte. ♪
(keep with me in the moment.)
♪ Aizu wo shitatte, ♪
(I'd let you had I known it,)
♪ iwanai no? ♪
(why don't you say so?)
(light music)
♪ Na na-na~ ♪
♪ Ah ha ha ha ha ha~ ♪