Oh shit!
Kon-Melo!
Kon-Melo! Kon-Melo! Kon-Melo!
It's ya Tech Wizardess girl, MeloriTensei!
Hello, hello! Melori Valentine desu!
Right, Zenless Zone Zero.
That's the main topic today.
I hope today's livestream goes really well
because I'm so looking forward to this game, honestly.
Like, I'm genuinely so looking forward to this game.
I don't want to waste too much of your time,
but we're gonna get straight into the few important stuff.
Every session with MeloriTensei always starts with the few usuals.
One of which is graphic settings.
So, let's get right into it first.
Woo!
I pre-installed the game
the moment it was open for pre-installation.
It was…
I just went "Ope, let's go download them immediately, let's go!"
Right, without further ado,
let's get straight into setting up the graphic settings.
So at the moment, I have it on custom
and I have it on this following settings.
I'm not sure if this is really the setting that might work for me.
How about we try out max settings first,
then we'll figure out what happens next.
Well, I hope for the best for all I know.
Ooh, here we go.
TV: We interrupt your regular programming for this breaking news.
TV: A Companion Hollow has suddenly appeared
on Fortheenth Street.
TV: And has already breached level-three containment.
TV: The Hollow Investigative Association has dispatched a team
to the scene to carry out emergency protocols.
TV: Evacuation of residents in nearby blocks is underway.
I wonder what's the breach.
TV: Please stay away from the Fourteenth Street area
TV: Residents of adjacent blocks are asked
to follow disaster guidelines
when evacuating in an orderly manner.
Aw, that Bangboo is adorable.
Also the AirPods though.
Belle: Wise - come check this out.
Wise: What's that?
Mel: Oh, this guy is the older brother.
Wise: Fourteenth Street? I think the news mentioned it earlier...
Give me a sec.
Mel: Alright.
Wise: Yeah, in the Janus Quarter.
Wise: They say it's already breached the level-three controls.
Mel: Gotcha.
Wise: We'll be seeing some business coming our way soon.
I wonder what they're really about, as in between the two of them.
I mean, what's their job?
I wonder.
At least that's getting me curious.
So we got choice of Wise and Belle.
I'm a girl, so I'm going for Belle.
Here we go.
Wee!
Belle: Cool, now we play the waiting game.
"Chapter 0: Business x Strangeness x Justness"
Huh.
Nicole: Go left!
Whoa, okay.
Wooo, okay.
My controller rumbled.
Okay, so there is rumble support, that's interesting.
Great job, HoYoverse, honestly.
Holy.
Nicole: Hm?
Mel: Hm?
Gangs: Over there!
Gangs: Go! go!
What the heck is…
oh.
I'm just wondering what's with that thing.
That's so huge, not to mention the band-aid was like…
on that spot.
Alright.
Reporter: I'm *ing *ed! As this station's reporter,
I can't listen to this anymore! Those criminals need to get *ed!
"Those criminals need to be get screwed."
Oh my god.
Reporter: As soon as we find them we should just *ing * them all!
And then * them again!
I'm…
mmmm…
alright.
Billy: There's a window! Boss, we can get out this way!
I wonder if these guys are the ones that they're looking for.
Nicole: But that's a Hollow down there...
Fine, a way out is a way out. Can you break the glass, Billy?
Billy: Easy! Leave it to me!
Alright.
Ah...
Uh... (laugh)
Ah.
Billy: Uhh...
(Mel laughs)
Tryna play cool, I guess. (laughs)
Anby: It bounced off. This glass must be tough.
Oh?
Nicole: Wait! Is that a flashbang?
Anby: Correct. It's a GS 2 high-lumen military flashbang.
The blast is quite strong.
Mel: Oh?
Nicole: Awesome! Time to wake up, Billy!
Oh, Billy, okay.
Alright.
Gang: What?!
Mel: (mocking) HUH?
Billy: Eyes open everyone!
Billy: SAY- CHEESE-!
(imitating flashbang) Biii!
Gangs: Wahhh! My eyes!
Gang leader: I'LL KILL YOU ALL!
Nicole: Hahaha, you've made a mistake, mister.
We aren't your enemy.
🥵👉👈 Yesh, mommy. 🥵👉👈
Ah, I mean, sorry.
(Screenshot sound)
Uh...
It's not what it sounds like.
I'm innocent, I swear.
Reporter: What? You've found the Red Fang *ers?
Oh my god, the reporter guy.
Reporter: Then what are you *ing waiting for, Commander?!
Reporter: Pick the biggest gun and rain down JUSTICE!!!
Helicopter: Falcon 4, attack order received.
Oh my god, come on.
You got three surrendees at least-
I mean, at least from what they see.
And they're told to attack… ugh...
okay.
WITH A ROCKET!
I mean, a missile!
WHAT ARE YOU THINKING?!
Nicole: I'm done for...
Oh, not like this.
Look at Billy's face, he's genuinely giving that "Not Like This" face.
(NOT LIKE THIS, BOTTOM TEXT)
Ah!
Billy: I want to file a complaint!
(laugh)
I…um.
I don't know if you are in the right place
to file a complaint, but okay!
I wonder where's the box (a strongbox) that we saw earlier.
Oh.
Woo~!
But wasn't it night time out there?
We're landing in…
🥵👉👈 Yesh, mommy. 🥵👉👈
She's so cool.
Oh my god, that walk.
That walk.
She's so cool.
X (button).
Looks like attack, yeah. Oh!
I mean, with every game, the X (Xbox) is always attack,
so I'm not surprised.
"Basic attacks generate energy."
"With enough energy, Special Attacks will be enhanced to the…
EX special attacks."
I assume it's like exclusive or extreme?
Wow!
The game makes you press the button
instead of skipping through it.
Okay.
Alright, alright, alright.
Oh my god, the camera work. Holy.
Anby: Ahem, this is Anby Demara, a member of the odd-job agency, the "Cunning Hares". I accidentally fell into a Companion Hollow.
Oh, I assume we're currently in a different universe.
Because…
oh, that explains the difference between day and night.
Okay, I get it now.
Billy: -Ah, there you are, Anby! Great!
I mean, you have every right to be excited at this point, Billy.
Billy: I knew you'd be okay- (slash)
Billy: Whoa whoa! Hey, what's gotten into you?! You almost cut me!
Anby: I've met another being of reason.
He looks a lot like my colleague: Billy Kid.
(Mel laugh)
Billy: What are you talking about? It's me! Billy!
Anby: An Investigator has previously encountered Ethereals
who can mimic human speech and behavior.
Anby: The Investigator rescued the Ethereal
pretending to be their teammate,
but once they got out of the Hollow, it revealed itself.
Billy: Wait, isn't that the plot of that movie
that was in theaters not long ago!?
Anby: ...There was a long list of victims involved
in the incident. I read all their names.
Mel: Oh?
Billy: That's called a cast list!
(Mel laugh)
Wait, wait, that was not real?
Hold on, whaaa?
Hold on.
No, I'm getting confused right now.
Is… is...
is Anby a robot of some sort?
Because that's hilarious.
Anby: Question: Who would you most like to have dinner with?
Oh hey, security questions. (laughs)
At least that's what I would think if Anby thinks like a robot.
Billy: Huh? Dinner? Of course...
that'd be the big screen superheroes, the Starlight Knights!
Billy: Wait wait wait! Put your blade down, I'll tell you!
You know, with that kind of lore,
I actually am kind of interested in seeing if…
if HoYoverse might make it into like a proper anime.
Billy: ...It's really the late night drama actress
from "Oh~ Sweetie", Monica...
Anby: All clear. The individual has been confirmed
as the real Billy Kid.
(laughs) Alright.
So his name… his full name is…
Billy Kid.
Anby: Meeting Billy Kid increases my chances of survival
by over 67.8%. I'm glad you're okay, Billy.
Billy: I told you I'm me!
Hehe. "I told you I'm the real deal." (laughs)
Aww.
Billy: ...It's been a while since we fell. Nicole must be trying
to come up with a way to get us out from the outside.
Hmm.
Billy: But will she be willing to pay for the help?
You know how Nicole is, hahaha...
I mean…
If Nicole is as what we think of her as…
Anby: Based on Nicole's tight-fisted spending habits,
I'd say your original analysis is likely correct.
So, she would be more likely to outsource
than to do the job herself.
Alright.
Billy: Damn... Now you've got me worried.
Alright, that might be a bit... yeah.
It makes it seem like she's hopeless.
I don't know.
Alright.
"Stunned enemies are unable to move
and sustain additional damage."
"Special Attacks trigger a Chain Attack
upon hitting a Stunned enemy."
Wait, what?
Oh, that.
So when we swap out…
Alright.
When your squad contains two or more agents,
press [RB] to switch between them.
"Launch a chain attack."
Uh… one…
two…
No wait, that…
Oh, that!
(Billy screams)
Oh, that's hella cool.
That's hella cool, I gotta admit.
"When your characters hit enemies, they generate Decibels."
Alright.
"Once your Decibel rating is at Max…
Press [RT] to launch the Ultimate."
Alright.
"Wipeout."
I like the camera work.
Seriously, that's so different.
(Billy's gun clicks)
Ah.
Classic Billy moment.
Billy: Hmm?
(Mel laughs with her mouth full)
That sound he made.
Billy: Uh-oh, forgot to reload!
Billy: Okay buddy, wait a sec! Time out!
Mel: Hehe.
(Anby's sword slash)
Billy: Wahhh-!
(laughs) Oh my god.
Billy: Ughh!
Oh, that's big.
That's big.
"When a golden prompt appears,
press [swap] to trigger a Perfect Assist."
Ooh.
"Then press Basic Attack to launch an Assist Follow-Up."
Oh, like that.
So if you don't do it, it doesn't do it.
"Consumes assist points."
"Chain attack can replenish it."
Alright.
Wooh.
He was on guard.
Can we get behind him and then... give him a slap!
Oh, we can… we can ult it.
Let's go!
Billy: He's recovered?
Billy: Is his Ether activity still increasing?
Anby: Keep up the attack?
Billy: Nah! we don't have the firepower to fight for long!
Ooh, cool.
Smoke 'em.
Alright.
Let's go!
And of course they'll be gone.
eeeeYup.
I wonder where to they've gone to.
Ah, the box.
"Meanwhile, in downtown New Eridu."
"At a video store in the corner of Sixth street,
over in the Janus Quarter..."
Oh, Nicole!
Nicole: Hey, listen up! I was there when that explosion took place.
Wise: Hello Nicole... It'd be nice of you to knock next time.
(Mel laugh)
Come on, Wise!
Belle: I feel like I hear of your urgent needs
at least three times a month, Nicole...
(Mel giggles)
Damn it, Belle!
🥵👉👈 Yesh, mommy. 🥵👉👈
Alright, so I assume these proxies are…
had already made a name for themselves.
Wise & Belle: What trouble did you get yourself into this time?
So we're up to the task.
(In Chinese - Mandarin) "Don't Read Before Sleep"
"Don't read before bedtime."
Oh my god, I find that hilarious.
I assume that's a horror magazine or something.
It's Friday morning!
Today is Friday in California!
Sorry!
Nicole: They're really cracking down on Proxies.
They set up a hotline, and...
Cracking down on proxies?
Wait, hold up.
So we're basically another White Hat vigilantes or something?
"Which creditor is chasing after you this time?"
I kinda wanna hear what the response is.
Belle: So what's the hurry, Nicole?
Which creditor is chasing you this time?
Nicole: That's not it! I was set up by Public Security
and that angry reporter from Ridu TV!
Also I just realized, hold up, umm...
Looking respectfully, right beside my head, umm...
She has a mole on a unique spot.
Man, character designers honestly.
I mean, I get it, moles can be everywhere but…
I just realized about that. (laughs)
"Finish the job and I'll clear my entire bill in one go."
Wait, she owes us?
Hold up.
You know what, screw it.
"Sounds pretty good."
It would be hilarious if we haggled for a better offer.
How about be a part of us?
Hmm...?
Belle: You've been dodging your bill for months Nicole.
Have you even considered the interest?
Nicole: Fine, I'll give yo ua share of the commission payment.
Does that cover it?
Oh my god...
i'm so...
Oh my god, I'm so harsh. (laughs)
I'm sorry, Nicole.
But I honestly like...
like... Belle's look.
Oh my god, her look is just...
Y'know what? Hold on. Lemme just...
(Screenshot sound)
Don't mind if I do. (laughs)
Nicole: Ohhh? Deploying your "Bangboo Double", huh? Okay!
Bangboo double.
Oh, because they're (the) "proxies", I think.
(gasp)
Oh my god.
That's so…
So adorable.
(stutters)
Oh my god, okay.
"Metro Goblin"... Goblin?
(Fubuki sings WE ARE JAPANESE GOBLIN)
Mel & Fubuki: "WE ARE JAPANESE GOBLIN"
(laughs)
I'm sorry.
Wise: Hello, can you hear me Nicole?
You can put Eous through now!
Nicole: Okay! Right, little one, off you go then~
Nicole: Done! Bangboo's on the way!
Wise: Well then, can we begin?
Belle: Uh-um.
Woah.
Hehe, what's that?
A bomb? A pokéball?
I wonder what that is. Honestly.
Anby: Incoming, get ready.
Billy: Wait, that wasn't me!
Proxy Bangboo: Hey, guys! Over here!
Huh.
Proxy Bangboo: Good work, all.
Anby: It's a scarf-wearing, talking Bangboo...
Billy: Ohhh! You're-
Billy: Phaethon!
Oh my god, she's so cool when she leans like that.
"A few more compliments and I might give you a discount." (laughs)
Ahh, let's... Let's have a look.
Belle: A few more compliments like that
and I might just give you a discount.
Anby: Really?
Billy: I think the Proxy was just trying to be polite, Anby.
Anby: We have to get out of here.
Alright.
Anby: Unless, Billy, you'd like to stay here forever?
That new Starlight Knight Belt you wanted?
I guess I'll place it at your grave next year.
Hehe... "I'll place it at your grave next year."
Billy: When you say things like that with that poker face of yours,
I can't tell if you're joking or not.
"Observation Data - Scattered throughout the Hollows,
you'll find crucial materials known as "Observation Data"
Each commissioned Hollow contains 3 sets of Observation Data.
Collecting these data sets increases the final rating of...
of?
your commission and rewards you with additional Polychromes.
Alright, I wonder what Polychromes are.
"Observation data in the hollow will be saved once picked up.
You don't need to pick it up again when exploring the same area."
Oh, so like, it's a one-time thing.
It's like a one-time bonus.
Right.
Poopie.
We're getting into…
Ooh?
A battle, I assume.
Oh my god, Anby close-up is so pretty.
Ooh.
Ooh, that is a good synergy.
I like this.
Ooh, whatever that is.
"Hollow observation data." Oh, okay, right.
What is this one?
Anby: Ethereals. They're catching up, Proxy.
Oh.
Billy: What should we do? Fight?
Ooh.
Wise: It's cool. Just come with me.
Alright.
Does it do it by the time basis or step basis?
Oh, per step basis, gotcha.
Wise: This track-laying machine... We can use this.
Ooh, what's this?
Oh, it's just conveyor belts.
Wee! More boxes.
"Safety valve data. - The system log shows the valve is unlocked
by inserting the preset amount of Gear Coins..."
Really?
Why do we need to pay to get to be safe?
Well, I'ma...
Billy: Hmph! Even in a Hollow,
they're seriously gonna charge a toll?
Billy: Even if I agree, the Starlight Knights wouldn't agree!
Billy: And even if the Starlight Knights agreed,
Nicole wouldn't agree!
Billy: ...So take that! Starlight Mirage!
HDD Broadcast: Agent Billy detected,
he is forcing the valve lock with the butt of his gun.
HDD Broadcast: Valve detection - Open. But Agent Billy has suffered
partial damage to his hand's exoskeleton.
Partial damage? What kind of partial damage?
What did he do?
Billy: Ow... That hurts!
(laughs) What did he do?
We're escaping.
See ya!
We're bustin' outta here.
Hell yeah.
Oh?
Pop pop pop pop.
Get the heck outta here, Bill!
Wise: Don't worry. Just do what my sister says.
Billy: That voice... Oh! It's the other Phaethon!
"Don't take over my channel like that!"
Belle: Seriously, can you not jump on my channel
all of a sudden? You scared me.
"Sensory synchronization has been disconnected-"
Okay.
Anby: It's gone quiet...
Billy: It became a regular Bangboo.
Ohhhhh. So this Bangboo can be…
Can be hacked in and be used as a proxy.
Billy: Why would they de-sync at a time like this?
(Mel breaks)
Anby: Going straight forward. Brace for impact.
Just smash the wall.
Billy: We're gonna crash! We're gonna crash! we're gonna crash!
(Mel laughs)
"With a strange sense of release,
the two pass through the wall as though it's nothing.
Oh, so that's the fake Hollow wall that takes us back to the surface.
Anby: The oppressive weight of Ether is gone.
Billy: We're out... We're finally out! Aha!
Aw, that celebration outta Bill.
Ugh, fiiine.
"Nicole Demara."
"Partnership established."
Gotcha.
Alright, we now have reached the point of free movement.
But regardless, I hope to be able to continue
making Zenless Zone Zero streams.
(This highlight was painstakingly clipped
around several stream crashes)
And there'll be more Blue Archive streams
and Zenless Zone Zero streams.
(Hopefully it's bearable, lemme know
in the comments if you like it!)
OtsuMelo deshita. (It's been ya girl, Mel)
Have a good night, y'all.
Ko-fi - Thank you for supporting me financially!
Member: Jo
MeloriTensei 転性メロリ
Thank you for watching! Check out my other contents!