Salutations!
Welcome to Melori's Tensei's…
Oh, Melori's Tensei?
What the fuck?
Heh.
Pfft.
So, you're an iPhone user like I am.
Pretty much an iPhone user that
does not use the ecosystem.
Well, salutations!
I'm Melori Valentine, and
this is my personal guide
to ditching the walled garden ecosystem.
Though with disclaimer,
that some of the services that I'll be using
might not necessarily respect your privacy.
So, please do your own
research about these services.
There might be some services that might
be a bit of an anti-feature for you.
So, for those privacy-concerned users,
please stick around in the video,
and I'll show you a very cool list.
Or you can just jump straight
to the description and just…
I don't know.
That's the end of the video for you, I guess.
Okay.
I'm nah…
I'm just joking.
Alright.
Let's get straight to…
First up, the biggest elephant in the room.
Because I know many people
will click off this video,
and they're gonna go away and say
goodbye and crash my algorithm.
So, we're gonna go straight from
the biggest to the smallest instead.
So, first up is going to be…
Photo Sync!
Now, we all have precious photos
that we like to sync up to the cloud,
so that nothing gets lost,
even on the time of taking.
So, what do we use?
So, for me, however, I use two
different solutions at the same time.
The first one being using MEGA.
So, MEGA is pretty popular as
one of the cloud services that…
Quote-unquote, "online privacy for
everyone", or cares for privacy.
So, you either take their word for
it, or do a plenty of research.
And speaking of research, two years
ago, as of the filming this video,
there might be a little bit
of a trust problem with MEGA.
So, for me, I do trust MEGA a little bit,
as long as my photos are not really
mission-critical or sensitive.
So, you be your own judge for this.
I'll link those resources
in the description below.
Now, for the second one, in case
MEGA goes to shit, I use SeaFile.
Well, SeaFile is mainly a personally
self-hosted cloud sync server.
So, this also means you need a little bit of a
technical know-how to be able to host a server.
However, functionality-wise, it is more
or less the same as MEGA, Google Drive,
a plenty lot, but it is a little,
kind of like, clean-looking, I guess?
It doesn't come smacking at you with,
like, premium features this and that,
because you have control over your files.
This sounds like a really awesome idea.
So, this is my current secondary backup option.
So, there you have it.
However, SeaFile do come with,
well, kind of bare of features.
Like, how do I say this?
You have extremely basic Office,
and that's pretty much it.
You can't really do much of it, like,
sharing notes, that does not exist yet.
So, this is where NextCloud comes in.
NextCloud is a lot more whole
and a lot more complete,
because it is more catered
to the corporate platform.
And even if you do host it
on your casual platform,
it kind of feels professional to some extent.
I'm also personally a NextCloud user.
However, I don't find myself using
all the features on NextCloud,
so I can't really say too much for
the features that are available there.
But once again, with SeaFile and NextCloud, so,
the security can only be as
good as the hosters themselves.
You gotta keep that in mind.
It's not really a one-click
setup and forget solution.
You would have to take note of
how you are supposed to host it,
how you're gonna configure it,
and how you're gonna secure it.
Pretty much most of that.
However, it's still kind of
setup and forget to some extent.
There are some bit of maintenance occasionally,
like, from time to time, like
months or something like that.
But if you're really, really privacy
concerned or privacy conscious,
this might be a solution for you.
Right, with photo sync and cloud sync out
of the way, let's head on to the next one.
So, if you happen to use Apple
Keychain, and you thought to yourself,
how do I bring it to other platforms,
because I don't just use an
iPhone and I don't just use a Mac.
Let's say I got a Windows computer
and I got everything else,
like Linux, Android, whatever that is.
How do we bring them over?
Well, obviously, you gotta ditch the Keychain.
There's really not much to say,
you gotta ditch the Keychain.
So, there are a few more alternatives
they can pick up instead of the Keychain.
And on the very top, I got Bitwarden.
Bitwarden is one of my personal favorite
because its code can be independently audited.
Though I may not necessarily be a security expert,
it is that bit of assurance that
professionals can check the code
and call out to the public for
that, should there be any issues.
And accountability can be
held on Bitwarden themselves,
which sounds really important to me
because I care more about a
really clean and secure code
over a very paper guarantee from a company.
So, Bitwarden is definitely on the top of my list.
Now, Bitwarden lets you save passwords, notes,
and there's a little bit of secure vault.
However, you're gonna need
a pro subscription for that,
unless you self-host your
own server. (*Check desc)
Now, correct me if I'm wrong, however,
Bitwarden does give you an option to
self-host your own Bitwarden server.
So, you can store your password in your own server
rather than Bitwarden's own
servers, which is pretty awesome,
but I don't really do that for myself
because I don't really trust my own server.
I'll explain in a moment.
Now, following down the list, we got ProtonPass.
ProtonPass, however, I have
not personally used ProtonPass,
but I am a user within the Proton ecosystem,
namely ProtonMail and ProtonVPN.
However, I've never really experienced ProtonPass,
so you be your own judge, give it a try,
maybe do a little bit of a
back and forth testing with it.
But, I have trusted Proton as
a company for quite some time.
There may be one particular incident,
but it can get a teeny tiny bit concerning
depending on how far is your boundaries
to what you allow Proton to log.
They say zero logging, but obviously they
refer to the content that is zero logging,
but your access logs might still be there.
So, please keep that in mind.
That may potentially be a law in some places,
so this might be a little bit of a factor
that might be a tipping point for some people
who are really, really privacy sensitive.
Moving on to a really
proprietary* company, Dashlane.
So, I have previously used Dashlane before,
however, at the time, it was like
many, many years ago already.
You might have heard of Dashlane
sponsoring a lot of YouTubers
and basically just promoting their
password manager and so forth.
That is at least, they've done it after LastPass,
but we'll get to that in a moment.
And I thought to myself, maybe
I should give Dashlane a try.
Maybe, let's see what's different about it.
And when I tried it, it's pretty awesome
that when you do pay for a subscription,
that means you also have a file vault.
That's cool.
So, I kept a lot of documents at the
time in there, and that is pretty cool.
However, I do have one personal complaint.
I'm not sure this is resolved yet because
I'm no longer a Dashlane customer.
But as of many, many years ago in my past,
at that time, Dashlane was
acting a little bit funny.
I'm not talking about like privacy funny.
I mean like behavioral funny.
It's like sometimes it bugs out
with the auto-fill features.
Sometimes even with the saving feature,
sometimes I might lose some entries,
but particularly the ones that
I created brand new instead.
The existing ones stay the way it
is, but it's kind of funny still.
Like, it kind of did get in my way and it
takes off like a couple of minutes of my time.
Which is not really wise as a university
student at the time of subscription.
So, Dashlane, if you have fixed it,
please let me know in the comments
below if you happen to be watching this.
Though I won't guarantee you
that I'll be a customer again
because I currently don't have money.
Right, moving on.
There is a password manager I would like
you to completely ignore at the moment.
Personally, at least.
It is LastPass.
So, I have used LastPass before.
LastPass as a product was really really good.
Like I genuinely like it and sponsors
weren't really lying about it.
However, ever since its previous
security breach long long time ago,
it kind of got a little bit concerning
for me to the point that it's like,
"can I trust them any longer?"
And it kind of got a little
bit, well, very worrying.
It's like you paid to get hacked?
Huh?
So, I thought to myself, you know what?
I'm out.
Sorry.
That's how I switched to Dashlane.
It's kind of wild.
However, LastPass said that they're
going to keep enforcing the security
and leveling up the security.
So, my personal advice is threat with extreme
caution if you insist of using LastPass.
However, I would have recommended
you to use Bitwarden instead.
Right, moving on.
Two-factor authentication.
Particularly, the ones
where you have to type those
four-digit or six-digit or eight-digit numbers
whenever you need to log in to
some places like websites like Yu-
Yugo?
What the fuck?
Some places like Google,
Facebook, Instagram, so forth.
Man, I'm such a boomer.
You would need something that's kind of basic
and usually these websites will tell
you to install Google Authenticator
or Microsoft Authenticator.
I would personally go against
that and I'll explain in a moment.
But first, we'll get it
right into the alternatives.
My top recommendation, however, is 2FAS.
So, 2FAS is amazing and it's really
snappy and it's kind of transparent
and you can also audit the code
similar to how Bitwarden does theirs.
It's honestly a very robust way to handle things.
They have talked a lot about their
mentality on their YouTube channel.
So, I hope they keep that
mentality throughout so far.
And I hope they don't sell out
to some big giant corporate
like a certain company that I
will talk about in a moment.
And the one good thing about 2FAS, however,
is that it allows you to use iCloud
Sync to save your keys as a backup.
However, if you are not really comfortable
with saving things in the cloud, that's fine.
Turn that toggle off and you'll
be completely local again.
The one cool thing I really
like about 2FAS, however,
is this amazing feature where you
can just have a browser extension
and you just click on it...
And it pings your phone and you just press accept
and then it auto-fills the password for you.
So, you don't have to go look up and
down and up and down for the keys.
Which I honestly think is
seriously an awesome feature
for people who are really really lazy
or they just have limited access
to the keypad on their keyboard
or something like that.
Or they just outright don't have a keypad.
Like say, TKL users.
TKL keyboard users.
Yeah, I see you.
And 60% keyboard users.
Yeah, I see you too.
Hey, custom keyboards, let's go!
Anyways, back to the main topic.
And they also allowed you to export your keys
so you can bring it cross-platform
to the Android side.
Say, you have both devices like I do.
Like say, both an iOS and an Android device.
I would export it and then I'll take it
to the Android site and import it there.
So, I got two points of entry.
Though, preferences is always preferences.
So, you don't necessarily
have to do exactly what I did.
But at least that's a
scenario that you can imagine.
Right, following that, how do we make this better?
Clearly, there is a point of inconvenience for me.
So, you know how I just
mentioned little seconds ago
about how you need to export the keys
and take it manually to the Android site.
How do we do this a lot more automatically?
And that's where I found Ente.
However, I have no personal experience with Ente.
But Ente seems like a photo sync platform.
A more encrypted photosync platform.
But it is under a subscription basis.
So, it kind of deterred me from considering Ente.
However, if you scroll just a little bit down
and you see products and you get Auth.
Wow, it's Ente Auth.
It's an authenticator that is
free and cross-platform sync.
However, I don't have
experience with Ente Auth yet.
But I am looking forward to
try it out after this video.
So, if I do talk about securities or 2FAs
or anything related to it on a video.
I would probably talk about
my reviews on that video then.
Please do keep an eye on my channel
and be sure to subscribe for that.
However, it sounds really really awesome that
it's kind of like 2FAS but a little
more cloud-focused and encrypted.
It may not necessarily be a cup of tea
for people who are more local-focused
rather than cloud-focused.
So, if you are more of that
person, 2FAS would be for you.
However, there is an alternative to
2FAS when it comes to being local.
There is Aegis Authenticator*.
Though I don't have personal
experience with Aegis,
but I have heard of a lot of
recommendations in the 2FA subreddit.
And there were plenty of them in fact.
The reason being is pretty simple.
You can just access the source
code and audit the code yourself.
Which is pretty freaking awesome in my opinion.
It's kind of like the transparency
is just there for you to see.
Which is kind of awesome.
And it's also available in F-Droid
which is an alternative
download store that you can use
if you don't feel like wanting to use Google Play
or you just don't trust Google Play.
Or you rooted your device or you use a custom
ROM that does not have Google Play Store
and you still do not want
to have Google Play Store.
It's kind of awesome to have options like this.
So, big ups for Aegis.
Now, we're getting into the dangerous zone.
Now, let's get into those
that we should avoid outright.
Ravio OTP.
Initially, Ravio was being
recommended a lot by the subreddit.
However, ever so recently, Ravio
has sold out to a sketchy company.
Sketchy enough that…
Here, let me get this.
Let me set the story for you, okay?
Ravio was competitive to Aegis
because its source code was open
on GitHub during its launch.
However, ever since they got sold
out to a big sketchy company,
that big sketchy company shut down the repo,
hid everything relating to
transparency and all you got is this.
This website.
That's all there is to it.
Do you see where I'm going at right now?
Now, you catch my drift.
You don't know if this app is safe anymore or not
because there's no way to audit the code.
So, Ravio OTP for me is a big deal breaker.
Hell no, I'm not picking it up.
Thank you very much.
And here's another one.
Twilio Authy.
Now, Twilio Authy at the time of my usage,
it was really, really painful to use.
So for one, for logins, you need
to use your phone number to log in,
which genuinely freaking suck.
And now, I think it seems like
from looking at this documentation,
it looks like they made it even
more confusing for people to use.
You still log in with your phone number.
And as you may know, SMS
OTP is not exactly secure.
If you live in a place where it's
susceptible to SIM swap or interceptions,
this will be really, really bad for you.
So, there's that.
So, that's a big no for me.
And lastly, Google Authenticator.
Now, Google keeps saying, "oh, we're
securing everything in the background
and everything in the back is secure.
So, there won't be a hacking software
that will be breaking into it."
Have you looked at what's in your face?
So, the problem with Google
Authenticator, however,
is that if you can break
whatever's in front of you,
you immediately get access to all the
keys inside, which is not really good.
So, like, say for example, Google
Passwords in Google Chrome.
If they can bypass your admin permissions,
your secrets are no longer a secret.
Same logic goes to on your Android phone.
If your device has a security vulnerability
that bypasses your screen lock,
you've set yourself up for a serious problem.
So, personally, I genuinely do not like
Google Authenticator for that reason.
So, if you're using mission critical
services or websites like this,
Google Authenticator is a hard no-no for me.
So, we're going to yeet that.
Speaking of yeeting, I've
done it a long, long time ago.
Right, moving on.
So, if you remember from the photo
section at the beginning of the video,
I talked about how you can
synchronize your photos and stuff.
Let's say what about all your other stuff?
So, like, say your documents or programs
that you want to back up or audio files,
anything outside of photos, what do we use?
Now, if you remember from earlier, you would
see that SeaFile is back on the list again.
However, I would also bring in Nextcloud
as well because both of them are kind of
cool when it comes to being a file sync platform.
However, there is a downside to that,
but we'll get to that in a moment.
Now, say if you have a server that
operates on an operating system like
unRaid, TrueNAS, Proxmox, and the sort.
Then you would usually find yourself
using network attached storage
kind of thing called SMB or Samba.
And Samba is basically a protocol
that allows you to connect
to network attached storage within your network.
It's also being used on Windows
and plenty of other platforms
that happen to support it as well.
Which I would say pretty much if
you have devices that are smart,
like your computer and your smartphone,
you can pretty much access it.
No problem.
So, the Apple Files app genuinely
sucks in various things.
You can even see that it is pretty evident
on Linus Media Group's channel, Mac Address.
When Jonathan Horst complained about the
Files app, there were plenty of complaints.
And one of which happens to resonate with me,
which is the inability to
refresh on the Files app.
What kind of stupid thing is that?
The inability to refresh
with the Files app also means
you're unable to reestablish connections
with your network attached storage.
That is, either you change passwords
or you've changed folder structures
so dramatically different that it
is to the point of no recognition.
And the Files app would just think, oh, the
file structure is basically still that way.
And then it will stay frozen in time forever.
How do we avoid that?
Well, sadly, you would have to
resort to third-party solutions.
Which is where this program
comes in, ES File Explorer.
It's an app made by a subsidiary of
Baidu, so please be your own judge.
If you do think Baidu is a
bit of a malicious company,
especially on their origins,
please keep that in mind.
However, in my personal experience
of using ES File Explorer,
if you have trackers completely turned
off, it's kind of a pretty good app.
At least for the iOS side.
On the Android side, I would have recommended
you to use Solid Explorer instead.
Whereas on the iOS side, I highly recommend
using this because it carries things around.
At least it works in the kind of fashion.
If you do have any other File
Explorer that you would recommend,
please let me know in the description below.
Description?
What the fuck?
That's the second time I've said this already.
Please let me know in the comments below.
So the one good thing about
ES File Explorer, however,
is that when you want to take out
your photos into your SMB servers,
you can just use it to move*.
Which means it will basically just copy the
stuff over and then delete it on the local end.
So say you take a lot of videos
and you want to take it out
like how you do with a USB drive or something.
This is like the network's version of it.
So in my personal opinion, this
is genuinely kind of awesome.
However, there is a different solution.
So say you have a server that runs Syncthing,
which is one of the most awesome
decentralized file synchronization program.
Which kind of is like, think of it
like Soul Link in Honkai Impact.
I guess you don't play Honkai Impact then.
Don't worry about it.
Basically, if you kill one of them,
the other resurrects the one that you just killed.
So this is kind of an awesome idea in my opinion.
But that also means you would need
to have both copies on both ends.
However, if that's kind of your cup of
tea, then you would have Möbius Sync.
Though I haven't really used Möbius
Sync because I don't really have money
to buy the full-fledged version to review.
So, uh…
However, I have used Syncthing
in every other platform
that is available for free like
Android, Windows, and so forth.
And it has been really, really robust.
And this is how I've been
moving my files around so far.
So if you really, really want to consolidate
your files in the form of Syncthing,
I would recommend doing that instead.
Right, moving on.
Now we've reached a point where we
kind of go thinking to ourselves.
Okay, we've protected ourselves from the ecosystem
from most of the major standpoint.
Now let's get into the browser.
Now, the browser market may be a
little teeny tiny bit funny and…
I don't know.
It's a little bit…
Ehhh…
You're going to trust at your own volition.
However, I have done my research
and plenty of people on the iOS subreddit
has recommended to use Brave Browser.
Though Brave Browser does come with a
built-in ad blocker and a built-in PIP.
So you can kind of just do whatever
YouTube thing you couldn't do
on the free version on that browser.
To which I cannot legally directly address.
But it is kind of a janky way to do it.
And I kind of respect the hustle.
But Brave does more than just that.
They have a search engine of themselves,
which I haven't really gone around trying.
But apparently, they have their
own search indexes as well.
So that's like independent of
Bing, independent of Google.
And DuckDuckGo is based on Bing.
And you got SearX is kind of like based on Google.
Whoogle is also Google.
So Brave is like an index of its own.
Though I haven't gone around trying it,
so I can't really explain that to you just yet.
But if you do want the most basic
tracking and ad blocking browser,
I guess Brave might be a good option.
However, alternatively, you
can also try out Firefox.
However, Firefox does not come with ad blocking.
And extension support is
only available on Android.
So Firefox is, if anything, the
only thing that makes it convenient
is just if you happen to use Firefox on your PC,
then synchronizing the bookmarks and possibly tabs
that you want to move over
would be easier that way.
However, there's a tiny caveat.
So I have previously used Firefox before.
And there was a little bit
funny going on in the code
that if you open and close your
Firefox app way too quickly,
there are times where its cache gets so
corrupted that all your tabs disappear.
I have two instances of mine where
20-ish of my tabs all disappear
and I don't know how to retrieve it.
And that in itself is kind of concerning
because I couldn't even find it on Firefox sync.
So Mozilla, if you do catch that,
I hope you can resolve this ASAP.
Now I get it, Mozilla.
I get it.
All browsers on iOS is more
or less just Apple WebKit
with a little bit of a wrapper
and extra stuff on top of it.
But come on, you got a big market here as well.
However, if you can't stand the anomalies
that you get from third-party browsers
and you still want to stick with Safari,
I recommend you check out all
these following extensions.
Hyperweb.
Hyperweb is kind of an all-in-one extension.
And you can do ad blocking,
overriding search engines so you
can use your own search engine
instead of whatever Safari provides you.
And you can do custom CSS and
JavaScript injection as what it says,
though I have not really used it myself.
So I can't really tell you.
Perhaps it may be something
along the lines of TamperMonkey,
but I can't really guarantee you that either.
And there are also some additional features
like creating custom search filters.
So the search filter will be a lot
more biased to more trusted platforms.
Like say, if you're searching
for something medical,
it will give you WebMD and other
more trusted medical websites.
Also, don't call me on that about WebMD.
According to WebMD, you have cancer.
And following that, AdGuard for iOS.
AdGuard may be a little bit heavy.
So if you use the ad blocking feature on
Hyperweb, I think it should be enough.
However, if you do want a
bit of a sanity assurance,
then you should totally check out AdGuard as well.
AdGuard is kind of powerful on its free version,
so you can basically turn everything on.
However, your browsing experience might hitch
so much that it becomes probably like a
loading time of four to five seconds, honestly.
But don't just take my word for it.
Experiment with your setup and see what suits you.
And there are three different other
extensions that I use on the side of it
that kind of enhances the experience of Safari
so it feels less miserable.
One of which is Web Inspector.
And you might be very familiar
if you're on a browser.
You press F12, that's the inspector.
Pretty much that.
So if you're into looking into web elements,
then I highly recommend Web Inspector.
And following that, PiPifier.
So you might be familiar
with Picture-in-Picture view.
So like say, if you happen to be a YouTube
Premium user, you would understand that.
Which is a feature that lets you, when you exit,
you can kind of have it in like a tiny window
that you can watch alongside
as you do other stuff.
That's PiP.
However, obviously if you don't have
Premium on YouTube, you can't do that.
But there is an extension
that kind of lets you do that.
At least it works for the time
being, at the time of filming.
And the PiPifier is available on the Mac
App Store and namely, the iOS App Store.
So you can basically PiPify
whatever videos that you're watching
on the Safari browser version of YouTube.
And following that, we got TLS Inspector.
TLS Inspector is basically what you
would do when you click on the padlock
and look at the security information
of this website you're currently on.
Say like, what kind of HTTP
security it is and stuff like that.
View certificates and stuff like that.
This is basically what TLS Inspector does on iOS.
So you would know if a certain
certificate is expired or is invalid.
This is how you make yourself
a little bit more aware
about HTTPS and TLS security on Safari.
Because built-in Safari
apparently does not have that.
And I'm a little bit icky about it
because there are some websites
that are meant to be trustworthy.
Somebody in the tech department
forgetting to update their certificates.
Okay, so with that said.
These are the five Safari
extensions that I recommend.
So let's move on.
So for someone who likes
to take some notes out of…
Say they want to take a quick note.
You know, back in those days,
back in the old Hollywood times.
People always had these notepads in their hand
and they just quickly write a note
so that they can remind themselves in a moment.
How about we do that digitally?
So obviously you would have Apple
Reminders and stuff like that.
However, what if I want to bring it
cross-platform to elsewhere as well?
We're gonna keep that in mind most of the time.
So I've got some recommendations
from fellow good Samaritans online
and also some parts of the iOS subreddit.
And most people recommended Joplin.
Joplin to me in first
impressions kind of feels like
when you have Apple Reminders,
Apple Notes, and Trello have a baby.
Which inherently is not
really that bad in my opinion
because I am personally a Trello user.
That's how I've been reading my notes so far.
Though I don't have personal
experience with Joplin.
But I'm looking forward to try it one day.
And I was told that Joplin
allows you to backup your notes
in cloud services like Dropbox and so forth.
So I would be very much looking forward to that.
Hopefully it would optimize my experience.
Maybe it might not.
Who knows?
I'll update you in the future.
Now moving on.
This is where I'm gonna tell you
to tread with extreme caution.
Because if you're very privacy conscious,
you wouldn't want to use these.
So namely one of these is Google Keep.
Okay, I get it.
Reality check.
Google is interestingly "a kind of company".
But it is hard to deny that Google Keep has
been really really useful for me so far.
But privacy wise, I wouldn't say
it's necessarily that convenient.
So my best shot is if you are keeping quick notes
that are not really private or sensitive.
I guess Google Keep may just be fine.
But who knows one day Google
might change their TOS and go,
"Oh we're gonna start reading your notes."
Hopefully not.
And following that, we got another sketchy one
coming from Microsoft Sticky Notes.
Though the good part about
using Microsoft Sticky Notes
is that you can put it on top
of your screen on Windows.
And you can also do some changes
on the OneNote app on iOS.
However, the synchronization
is a bit wonky as hell
that sometimes the synchronization
just do not work at all.
Sometimes I type something really
really freaking long on my iPhone,
nothing left the phone.
Even though the app says it has.
Synchronization can be a bit janky here.
So I wouldn't recommend using that
unless you are absolutely a Windows fan.
So tread with caution for those two programs.
Right, moving on.
Home Management.
It's Home Assistant.
Yeah, that's pretty much it.
I have nothing else to say.
Because if you want cross-platform, Home
Assistant might be the best for you.
Though you could try out some other ones like say,
those that use Apple Home as their main platform.
But I still end up finding myself crawling
my way back to Home Assistant instead.
Because although Home Assistant might
be a little bit iOS unfriendly at times
because of the optimization that Apple
imposes in their operating system.
It's still quite useful when it works.
And it didn't really fail on me too hard so
I don't really see that much of a problem.
Right, moving on.
In terms of contact sync.
I don't really have experiences
anywhere else outside
because I didn't really want to keep
having a lot of point of management.
Especially when I'm managing
this channel all by myself.
I have plenty of load on my shoulders already.
So I've basically just used Google Contact Sync.
However, for those privacy conscious
people, you might want to stick around
a little bit to the end of the video for
what you may be interested in looking.
So, moving on.
In terms of cameras, there
really isn't any other camera app
that I really really like to use personally.
Aside from none other than ProShot.
ProShot basically makes you feel
like you're handling a DSLR.
Because most of its features do feel
kind of like a DSLR to some extent.
It's basically a DSLR in the form of an app.
Though of course the software
capability is confined
within the hardware capability of your device.
So your mileage may vary significantly.
However, as an iPhone user,
ProShot has been seriously
one of the amazing apps that gives
you the amount of flexibility.
Like say you want it strictly on a certain
aperture and a certain focal length.
And you want it at a certain
zoom and a certain setting even.
Like frame rate settings and so forth.
All of that are available in this one app.
It's genuinely amazing.
Big camera energy.
Please don't tell a certain someone about this.
If you're a very enthusiastic photographer,
I highly recommend this app no matter what.
Though there may be some other things
that you might be interested in like
filmography and stuff like that.
Then maybe Blackmagic camera might be your taste.
But ProShot is kind of like an
all-in-one Apple camera killer.
So, big ups Rise Up Games.
Seriously, I've used it for so long.
Like I got this app close to a
decade ago already at this point.
And they just keep growing and
it just keeps getting better.
And I haven't really been pissed at them so far.
So, big ups.
Moving on.
When it comes to photo editing,
this might be a bit of a sticky
situation to say the least.
I wouldn't recommend Photoshop Express
because in my opinion, it just sucks.
Sorry to those who use Photoshop Express.
And many of the other apps just kind of are wonky
in the way that they put watermarks.
Or they put a limit to the
resolution and stuff like that.
It genuinely pisses me off as a consumer.
Like a general consumer that
have bought such a device
only to pay even more price premium*.
It's kind of like you've
entered the most expensive place
only to pay for even more expensive
stuff that you don't really need.
So with that, this might be a bit
of a very, very harsh situation.
But if you're into Photoshop
and you still want all the
features in Photoshop, Photopea.
So, Photopea is basically, well, legally
distinct Photoshop to say the least.
And you can use them on your PC, you
can use it on your mobile device.
But if you want to use it on
your mobile device, however,
I highly recommend that you use
it with a mouse or a stylus.
Either of which.
Because you might end up misclicking
some stuff on the screen.
Considering how iPhone is kind of a
small screen if you think about it.
But Photopea's functionality is more or less
the same as the Adobe suite of programs*.
So, if you're looking to escape Adobe suite of
programs, Photopea might be one of your choice.
That's really it for photo editing, honestly.
And last but not least, if
you're into video editing
and you want the top of the class video editing.
And you want to break free from the
Apple ecosystem, namely Logic Pro.
The only other solution for you is
if you happen to use iPads, then
you would have DaVinci Resolve.
And DaVinci Resolve, interestingly,
you can export and import
your projects back and forth between
the computer version to the iPad.
Which is kind of freaking awesome.
So, say you were editing something
really, really important.
And then suddenly, your
entire family drags you out
because they accidentally
bought your tickets to Hawaii.
But you still want to edit,
but you don't want to carry your
bulky ass desktop or laptop.
But you got an iPad Pro, however,
DaVinci Resolve for iPad would
be an amazing choice for you.
However, if you're on an iPhone,
DaVinci Resolve does not exist for the iPhone.
Which is really, really sad
because I kind of really wanted Blackmagic Design.
I hope you port it to the iOS as well.
Because I genuinely want to edit my videos
without worrying about
completely different programs
when I'm on different platforms.
So, for the time being,
LumaFusion from LumaTouch is
kind of like a backup for that.
It's available on iPadOS,
it's available on iOS as well.
And as far as I've seen from
all the reviews outside so far,
and the screenshots I've seen so far,
it kind of feels like DaVinci
Resolve, but for iPhones.
So, though I have no personal
experience with LumaFusion yet,
but I'm looking forward to buy it eventually.
Please let me know of your experience
of LumaFusion in the comments below.
And with that said, that's pretty much it
for all of my choices for alternative solutions.
Now, for those who have stuck around in
this video that are very privacy conscious,
here's a page that I highly
recommend you check out.
There's this page called Awesome Privacy,
and it is a very massive list
for everything you need to know
about what you should avoid
and what you should have
if you're very conscious of privacy.
Say for example, I'm interested in
the two-factor authentication section.
Let's have a look.
Avoid using these apps that won't
let you export your key easily,
Authy and Google Authenticator.
However, there are some programs that
claims to have been able to
import from Google Authenticator.
I don't know about that, but
I guess that might be just
part of security vulnerabilities
on Google Authenticator.
But hey, we got Ente over here, that's awesome.
I wish they have added 2FAS onto the list.
And there are plenty more.
Say Android app stores,
you have FDroid or Obtanium
I would recommend personally.
Obtanium is basically just
fetches straight from the source.
Like say, if you have someone's app
that is directly hosted on GitHub
and FDroid and all the different places
that are kind of like git focused,
you can use Obtanium to get app updates
that way, which is kind of awesome.
Now say I want to look for mail services,
like say it would tell me to avoid
Gmail, Outlook, Yandex and Yahoo.
And instead look for ForwardMail,
ProtonMail, Tuta, Riseup and Mailfence.
And if you want to self-host yourself,
these are the options over here.
And then you got clients for it as well.
K9, which is a pretty good, basically
Mozilla Thunderbird, but Android?
It's made by Mozilla Foundation themselves.
I mean, not really made, they didn't create it.
They bought it and then they
maintained it and so forth.
Kind of like that.
So you get the idea.
Awesome Privacy is a really
awesome page to check out.
So I'll be linking it in the description below.
So please check it out.
And that is all I have for you today.
Thank you so much for watching.
And I hope you understand my thought process
for my choices of lists and stuff like that.
And if you do have your own suggestion
that you want to tell the other fellow
commenters about it or lurkers about it,
please comment it down below and
maybe let's discuss about it.
So it's been your girl, Mel.
And I hope to give more personal
knowledge of mine to you.
And I'll see you guys on the next video.
OtsuMelo deshita.
See ya!
According to WebMD, you have cancer.