Are we live yet?
It's been a while since I last hear that BGM.
Hello, welcome fellow live viewers, VOD watchers.
What you're about to see is going to be
a major first step to a major change to this channel.
This major change is going to happen progressively.
It's not going to be a one click or a one snap,
but I'm hoping to be able to do all these changes over time
and eventually into something really really big.
So I hope you join me on the ride and I look forward to this.
With that said, I hope you enjoy the first start and the first change
to the live stream part of MeloriTensei.
See ya in a few minutes.
Melori's Zenless Zone Zero Adventures - Part 2
The Soda, The Neighborhood, The Breaches.
Yaaaaaa,
Kon-Melo Kon-Melo Kon-Melo,
it's ya Tech Wizardess girl, MeloriTensei!
Hello hello hello!
It's been a while, hasn't it?
Like, you've been seeing videos out of me, but you have not seen streams for so long.
Well, we're finally back with a stream, yippee!
We're finally back streaming again!
We're finally back again!
Yippee yippee yippee!
So, as you may have noticed, most of my assets have changed.
Like, my starting soon screen now has looked a whole lot different.
What do you guys think?
VOD watchers, live viewers, what do you guys think?
Let me know in the comments below.
So another major thing is, as you may have noticed, the BGM has changed.
I figured to myself I kind of want something a whole lot more…
I want to have more vibes to this, more than just lo-fi.
So I thought, let's go hunt up for more BGMs.
And also, if you haven't noticed, in the past year of streaming,
the BGM has really driven me crazy.
So to combat that, what I have done is I have added way more BGMs than ever.
Unfortunately, you won't be hearing the BGMs that you've been hearing in the past.
That has been completely replaced, unfortunately.
However, I can assure you that these are a playlist of bangers.
So I hope you continue to enjoy and feel really comfy about this.
However, for this stream, I don't think you'll be hearing
the playlist that I have picked for the stream just yet.
So I've been thinking for a while now, I haven't really put that much thought to
how I would really want a certain screen to look like.
So like, say if there's a technical issue and stuff,
I usually have a BRB screen when that happens.
So I have changed that as well.
And we got a different playlist of BGMs for it now, finally.
So in the past, the chatting and BRB screen were one screen, uh, were one playlist.
Not anymore.
Yep.
It's kind of adorable.
I find it adorable.
The idea I was going with was to give it a goofy vibe.
So like, "oopies!".
Kind of, you know, that kind of funny vibe.
You'll get to see that when I run into technical issues.
And as you may have noticed, I got a new transition as well.
Although there are quite a number of assets that I have removed that were particularly
of OwOsRikos, I have also added a few.
So technically, she's not out of my asset list.
So big shoutouts to OwOsRikos.
OwOsRikos! Riko!
Are you watching?
Because this, I highly appreciate your assets.
I've been using your assets for some videos, like this background.
It was in my ASMR video.
I hope that's perfectly fine.
Although I'm still gonna call myself the Tech Wizardess,
I may, I may change some, some, um,
some small things like maybe the theme
or the vibe by a little bit, like 1%, just, just, just a,
just a centimeter off, kind of thing.
But we'll see.
It takes a whole lot of experiment.
It takes a whole lot of experimenting, a whole lot of understanding
and to see, to see what I really want to be.
But regardless, I'm glad that you guys joined me on the ride.
I'm hoping that more people could financially support me so I can,
so I can be financially stable and be able to continue making content the way it is,
because I'm going to keep putting up,
I'm going to keep upgrading the content and it does take quite a lot.
I would say financially and mentally,
but I'm hoping to bring up everything as we go.
We'll scale as we go.
So with that said, special thanks to a, to a Ko-Fi member that we currently have.
Thanks, Jo, for, for being my member for, I think, three months?
And also all the one-off donations that Jo has been donating to keep,
keep some stuff alive.
I greatly appreciate those.
Right, without further ado, let's get back into the main content.
Oh wait, before that, just next to my table.
Okay, right.
We got something hilarious.
So I was supposed to do this on the first Zenless Zone Zero stream.
Unfortunately, I completely forgot about it and I left it in the fridge.
So basically, I was being stupid.
So what I want to do is I want to try out soda water.
I don't know what you call that everywhere else, but some people call it tonic water,
some people call it soda water.
It's basically just carbonated water.
I've never tried it before because I don't think I've ever heard of it before.
Oh my god, it's so difficult.
I feel like it has been compressed for a long time or something.
Ooh, there we go.
Right. (sniffs)
I don't smell anything.
I smell nothing.
Right, let's give it a try.
Ugh, wow, that's weird.
Wow!
That is weird.
It's like you got, you got, you got, what do you call that?
Like, it's like you got distilled water.
Like it's not mineral water.
It's, it tasted like distilled water.
And then you put, you,
you pump a whole lot of CO2 carbonation into it or something.
Holy, what the f-
This is so weird.
Okay, on the second taste, it's almost like, it's starting to get less bad now.
It's like it tastes, it tastes better than sparkling water or something.
I don't know because I, I've only tried one and it was,
it came from France and it tasted really weird.
Like it's not the fermentation, I don't know,
it's just something felt, felt really off.
And it's not expired.
It's, I don't know, it's, it's just so weird.
Right, what I want to try next is, what if I put tea into it?
So I'm gonna pour it by the rim, like so.
Oh my god, it's, it's already fizzing up like as, as it reaches the bottom.
What's going on?
Is this how soda water supposed to work?
Probably half, like half a mug of soda water and another half a mug of tea.
I bet it's gonna taste weird.
I bet it tastes weird.
Right, let me just give it a try now.
Whoa, what the, what in the world?
Okay, that, that in itself is weird.
That is so weird.
I don't know what I, I don't know what I was expecting.
I genuinely do not.
It's like I have diluted the, I've diluted the tea so much I could not even taste the tea at all.
It's just all soda.
Okay, no.
No.
I'll have them separately, thank you.
It's better when you're making cocktails after all.
Oh god.
Ugh.
I got so much carbonation in, in me right now.
Excuse me.
To self, don't ever buy soda water unless you're actually making a cocktail.
Or I don't know, mango soda at least.
Right.
Without further ado, let's get into, let's get into the game.
All right, let's get into the, let's get into the, let's get into the...
whatever we left off.
Because if we press escape right now, as you can see
I still have not set a name yet because the game still hasn't let me.
So we're gonna get into that.
Hello Wise, it's been three months.
We deleted the last alternate account after we finished.
This time, you can use my info to create a new account again.
Oh.
I was just talking about my account.
Open the Inter-Knot and register an alt account.
Ey, there we go.
Right, let's...
Right, what should we call ourselves?
Right.
I'm calling myself CyberMelo.
Right, let's register as CyberMelo.
We can change after all, right?
Something happened to my delivery.
An intriguing new commission?
Let me have a look.
Yes, judging by this ID and the content, it seems like someone we know.
If I'm not mistaken, the requester should be General Chop from Waterfall Soup.
You forgot to switch the account back to Phaethon.
From General Chop's perspective, the one taking on the request is the new Proxy named CyberMelo.
He might find it a bit suspicious.
In that case, why don't you see General Chop and explain the situation?
By the way, Susie from the Box Galaxy gadget store just contacted us.
She said she had something to ask us.
Metro Goblin.
We-~
Sorry, I'm not gonna repeat that ever again.
Check out the Sixth street.
Right, let's have a look at the Sixth street.
Okay, now that I'm out the door, let's start the daily ritual.
Scratch cards at the newsstand.
All right, so we're gacha-ing even in near reality, I guess.
Aw, that's so adorable!
Right c- oh.
Oh my god!
Oh my god, HoYoVerse, that's so cool!
You can- you can scratch with your right s-
That is so cool!
Okay, I like that.
What the heck?
Right, let's speak to General Chop.
Hello, General Chop.
Argh!
How annoying!
What's the matter?
Ahh...! It's you.
Sorry, but I can't take your order right now.
And all because of Pegasos Logistics!
The ingredients I ordered haven't arrived yet.
I just ran a track and trace on the order.
Apparently, they somehow sent everything into a Hollow.
I've already posted a request on the Inter-Knot to find the truck.
Proxy named CyberMelo accepted the job earlier.
The account is new though, so I'm not sure if it's reliable or not.
Hold on, let me just lean away.
"Points to yourself."
(Seagull Mel laughing)
Huh!
You're the one who accepted the job?
CyberMelo is you, huh?
Oh, I see.
You created a new account to make certain things easier.
I got so flustered earlier.
I should have just come directly to your store for help.
I shouldn't have wasted time on the Inter-Knot.
But since you've taken on the job, I'm somewhat relieved.
Right.
Susie.
From the gadget store.
Wait, this is the gadget store?
Box Galaxy.
It looks like an arcade.
What- what?
Aw.
Hello, welcome!
What is it?
So, what do I have to do?
Okay.
So I assume…
This person's lost in the Hollow?
Oh no, it's about-
Okay.
W-Engines, okay.
All right, cool.
Whoa!
Where did you come from, Anby?
Anby, what are you doing here?
Aw, she's innocent!
Uh.
Um.
It's a slang.
Oh!
Oh, poor Susie!
Alright.
Okay.
Since Susie has no idea about her boss's side gig,
let's be careful not to spill the beans while discussing the commission with her.
Okay, second commission!
You've accepted the commission, are you going to enter the Hollow now?
As Proxies, we can roam freely within the Hollow.
Which isn't easy for most people, at least.
But still, we need agents with combat experience, like the Cunning Hares,
to handle Ethereals and other dangers.
As usual, you should get in touch with the trusted agents to accompany you.
Signal Search has been unlocked.
What is Signal Search?
Oh!
Is this gacha?
So, we got 21 right now.
Okay, we got 21 at the moment.
That's interesting.
Oh, the BGM though.
So we got one A.
Awesome, who are we getting for A?
Ayy, we got an A, finally!
So it's an A W engine then.
Right, here we go.
Woo!
Wow, there's vocals to this song?
So that means when there's vocals, there's S?
Or something?
Hell yeah, this is such a vibe!
Let's go!
Where is it?
No way!
Okay, we got Nekomiya immediately.
One break later...
Ayy, I'm back.
Let's just say I got something real fizzy.
Ah, much better.
But I still got a single mouthful of soda water left to drink.
Let me try to finish the soda water.
Oh god, the soda water is tasteless as hell.
Venture into the uncharted depths of the Hollow.
It's essential to navigate your paths on the monitor array through the HDD.
With your path laid out, all you need to do is fight and eliminate the threats in the Hollow.
Outstanding Commissions, 2.
Ultimate collectibles.
Locate the missing W-Engine crate.
Okay, here we go.
Oh, we're back to the television.
Nya~ She's so adorable.
There we go!
Oh, that…
Woo!
That was satisfying, I gotta be honest.
That was satisfying.
Oh damn, the camera work.
Especially with Nekomata.
Oiii~
Let's go!
Oh, so that's her ult.
That's cool!
That's cool, I gotta be honest.
That's serious stuff.
And I've just defeated everyone with her alone.
I don't think I've swapped in this one.
And that's straight to the exit.
Okay, we've collected all observation datas.
And polychromes, denies.
Hmm, okay, let's get in there.
Whoa, her damage is good.
Seriously, do I have a fill form for this?
Of course!
It's your damn job!
You're an investigator!
Well, that's all for the mission, I suppose.
Okay, we got S rank for this.
Nice.
Pretty cool.
By the way, Pegasos called shortly after we went into the Hollow for the commission.
They told me the driver has been brought out of the Hollow by someone from the association.
Wait, that means I sent you there for nothing?
Well, it's better to, uh, on the side of caution.
Belle, you're so reliable.
Anyway, I thought I'd treat you to a meal once you come back.
What would you like to eat?
Today, I'm pulling out all stops to give you my specials.
All right, here we go!
What you got?
Gotcha.
Unlocks at level 20, 20, 20, 20, 20, 20, 30, 30, 30, 30, 30.
Dang it!
Okay.
What, what is this?
Vegetable noodles.
For 30+ attack.
Okay, that's cool.
But damn, he says he's gonna give us anything and we're, and we chose vegetable noodles.
Are you serious?
Game!
Why?
You could have,
you could have at least given us a basic chashu ramen for, for, for, um,
for meat lovers.
Come on!
Dang it!
You sorted everything out?
Yeah, let your boss know.
By the way, let me ask you secretly, Belle.
That W-Engine boss gave you, did you give it to that cute girl for fighting?
(PANIK...)
Stay calm and think of how to respond.
Oh no, no, yeah, I mean for battling other players, right?
So, did you win?
(DOES SHE KNOW?)
So, okay, okay, hold on.
Let me just have a look.
Oh, so this is how you get it, okay.
Oh, you can recycle W-Engines as well, that's cool.
Oh?
Brooooo!
That was fast.
Looks like you've already met the neighbors.
You always take so long to read my texts.
I was gonna head out and look for you.
Is something urgent happened?
Nope, just got a DM from Nicole and they'll be coming over real soon.
Hello there!
Special event.
All right, so we're about to get it done, huh?
Okay.
Oh.
Don't, don't make, don't make me, don't make me one star you on Yelp.
I'll show you customer rights!
Oh my god.
So, that's what the breaking up, the sound breaking out was for, right?
So, the audio breaking up wasn't me.
It's not my PC.
Oh, what a goddamn relief.
Data connection unstable.
Attempting to re-connect.
Oh my god, I just noticed.
Did you notice that?
H.D. œD
Holy.
WHHHHITEEEE NNoi$
Oh?
Oh, we're losing, we're losing signal.
What happened?
Huh.
Access denied.
We have been hacked.
Database formatting in-
Oh, not one of those. They...
Oh.
Ransomware.
Screen flickers into action as a video sent by a mysterious hacker begins to play.
Three familiar figures come into the view.
Oh, don't tell me they're flooding in more (enemies)
Oh no.
No.
That face.
Oh, there's the red eyes.
So you guys have not been paying off, have you?
Okay, god damn it.
I get it.
Is she gonna give a random code?
But unfortunately.
Oh, that was cool.
What a threat.
Haha, dumbass.
How about we just report them?
Ha ha ha. Ha~
Such a wuss.
(Mel's Ambulance noises)
We have reported you to the police.
To the house of the hackers.
So basically, now that they have taken over our systems, the IP address is now going to them.
So that means if they self-report, in theory, it now goes to them instead of us.
That's some 5D chess!
And... they left.
We're back!
All right.
Nice.
Cool.
We have retrieved.
Aww.
So you're secretly a good person?
That squeal.
Little late to be screaming.
Yup, we're back!
So what we gotta do is we have to open,
unlock these doors, I assume.
So we got a button over there.
And we got some enemies over here with a giant loot.
So we're gonna go grab the big fat loot for them.
I'm terribly sorry because I am greedy for money.
Haha.
Let's go.
Nice!
That was smooth.
That was really smooth.
I like that.
Right.
We got some big fat loot.
Here we go.
Right.
Now we're gonna head over there and get to the button.
Open her up.
Aww. Ain't you just…
What?
You're just…
You're just a…
You're just a bypass.
God damn it.
Welp, we got a boss to take care of.
Here we go.
Aww, no…
No swap...
No swap suggestions?
Screw it.
It's showtime!
Oh my god, this dude's…
I'm using a Chinese track.
And he's saying "It's show time!"
in the Chinese track.
That's so cool.
Alright.
Nope, we got kicked off.
I may be a Proxy but I'm not that merciless.
What about the Ethereal?
Where's the Ethereal though?
Ah, there it is.
Woo, what a timing.
Swap.
That was quite a nice swap lineup.
Ayy, we killed them anyways.
I guess.
The strongbox.
I knew it!
Okay.
All for the money, I suppose.
Huh.
It's a plugin.
Or attachment of some sort, huh?
Oh, it's a memory card!
Okay, wait.
No, no, no.
I'm bad.
I'm bad at understanding this.
Ayy, get downloaded.
What?
So what do we get?
How we're getting that memory card?
Chances are we might be able to get…
Whoa.
Chances are we might be able to get more commissions relating to the…
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, what is that?
No, this is sensory overload.
Holy shit.
What, what, what, what the…
What in the world am I just seeing?
What the heck?
Holy…
What, what the heck?
I wonder what that means.
What happened?
Was it like a future?
An alternative dimension?
What is going on?
What actually happens if we agree or disagree?
If we disagree…
Well, here goes nothing.
Oh we have no choice.
So the software is really overloading someone.
All right.
Okay.
Huh.
You didn't secretly record me, did you?
That would be creepy, right?
I mean…
What?
So we got a new software installed?
I suppose.
Huh.
Hello, morning!
Whoa, whoa.
Huh.
Okay.
So…
Huh.
What is in the video archive?
Let's have a look.
Stores video recordings of the important plot.
Oh, so we can look back to it.
Okay, that's cool.
Let's get some rest and let's look at what's coming up next in our commission.
I mean, not commission, like missions.
See what comes up next and I'll see if we could keep going on for a little bit longer.
Rest till morning.
Of course, we gotta have a little bit of late night surfing, cuz…
Don't we all?
I had trouble sleeping.
Makes sense, considering everything that went down yesterday.
Taking a breather for a few days might be a good call.
But we had a good way to relax.
How about we focus on managing the video store for a change of pace?
You can take charge of retrieving the overdue videotapes rented by our neighbors before the store opens.
She says "Hey, would you like to play a game and relax a little?"
I feel like I've forgotten something.
Maybe I left the stove on and forgot the clock.
Morning!
Oh, it's you.
Seeing you makes me feel like I forgot something relating to you.
The video store is reopening.
Has your vacation ended?
Oh, I remember now.
The videotape I borrowed is due today.
Sorry for making you come all this way.
Keeping track of every little thing in life is so much tougher than playing games that only rely on short term memory.
Oh my god, I could not be so called out right now.
What is going on?
Welcome, welcome.
I'm sorry, the cafe isn't open today.
Why not?
The Coff Cafe is currently getting new equipment and selecting new seasonal bean varieties.
I'm looking forward to the newest batch of dark roasted beans.
But the delivery of goods on both sites has been delayed due to a Hollow, which means the coffee shop won't be able to do business for a while.
Oh hang on, I just remembered.
One of the videotapes I rented out is almost overdue.
I should take this chance in returning it to you.
They sure are adorable bunches, aren't they?
Welcome!
What's that?
Need a videotape?
The one our boss borrowed?
Right here, here it goes.
Just about overdue, please take it quickly.
Belle, I ran into a cat at the street corner...
There's a little black cat, seems like a sort of thing you like.
I'll be there in no time.
Hello, Wise.
Come on and try it.
Try?
Aww, so adorable.
And capture.
Aww, it closed it's eyes.
Whateves, save it.
I've sorted the videotapes, including the ones that you have just returned.
We have enough videotapes to keep the business going for the time being, but in the long run we'll need more.
We should consider getting some new stocks.
You guys are getting ready for new stocks?
That's great.
I've already watched every videotape in the store 10 times.
Oh, you are?
10 times?
It's me, Heddy, your super loyal customer.
Aww, hello.
Did my controller just ran out of battery?
Luckily I got this one just as charged.
Just gotta dust it off and we'll be fine dandy.
Ah, you guys really need some promotion at this stage.
I can help with that.
I just realized I have no idea how to go about with it.
Don't sweat it, I'll show you how.
Now that we're back in business, let's get our tapes sorted.
Let's start by picking some tapes for display.
Best choose the most popular genres to attract more customers.
This should be good.
This reflects the popularity of a videotape.
What do you mean?
Oh, the amount of money that we'll be getting.
Okay.
Let's leave the promotions up to 18.
And open for business.
Let's go, let's start shop.
Every Denny counts.
Yippee
We're gonna hold it off for the next stream because…
God knows how long I'm gonna be staying up if I'm gonna keep playing.
So, we're gonna have another stream on another day.
With that said, thank you all so so so so much for watching.
Even if you're a VOD watcher, so be it.
That's fine, that's pretty cool.
Man, I've never felt so alive.
Getting back to livestream once more.
Be sure to subscribe, be sure to…
Whatever, hit the notification bell, do whatever the heck you want.
I'm gonna take my last sip of that…
That soda water tea concoction.
Ugh.
Okay, so that's it.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you guys next week.
OtsuMelo deshita [It's been ya girl, Mel].
See ya!
Take care, take care, take care, take care, take care.
Yeet.
[MeloriTensei's Ko-fi] Thank you for suppporting me financially!
Member & One-off donator: Jo
[MeloriTensei 転性メロリ]
Thank you for watching! Check out my other contents!