I'll press play first.
What?!
They have a launcher and it says signing in.
What?
Okay, okay, uh, volume mixer.
Trust me bro, you won't die.
I don't think so amigo.
Woo, poor Scott, we're leaving him hanging right now.
Kon-Melo~
So good to be back again
It's been so long since I last gone live on on anywhere ever
Okay.
Ah, I'm getting so excited.
Here's the thing, right?
Here's the deal.
Okay, um
The thumbnail and the game category says Forza Horizon 5, 'kay?
I literally bought this game literal hours before the stream
Okay
so,
I have not touched the game ever
like this is going to be my absolute first touch on the game
So hopefully hopefully this goes well
Press play first.
What?!
They have a launcher and it says signing in.
What?
That is insane
Syncing data.
Oh, wat.
It's doing pre-syncing beforehand.
What kind of launcher is this?
I've never seen this before.
What the hell?
"Gaming Services UI"
Oh, it's Xbox's own in-house launcher for Forza
Now I'm just trying to start the game.
It's gonna take a little while
My PC is slow
It's so slow I can see my I can see the SSD going already.
It's like it's working its asses off right now
Chat: "Anyways bets on how long it is before she crashes."
No, no.
No, no, no, I don't want no crashes today
I don't wish for any crashes today
I don't wish for any crashes ever.
Oh, oh, oh, it's accessing more files on the disk.
Okay, it's touching my SSD again
Oh, it's going up again.
Oh, oh, yes.
Oh, here we go.
Oh, it's gonna get loud.
Oh, where's the volume mixer?
Where's the volume mixer?
Hold on.
Where is the volume mixer?
Where's the windows key?
Where is it?
Okay.
Okay
Disclaimer okay, uh, volume mixer?
Okay,
it's not so loud it's not so loud it's not so loud,
okay, I think I think we can I think we can do
This I think I think it's I think it's alright
Okay, okay, okay.
Okay.
It's not too bad.
It's not too bad
I don't I think...
I don't think I have to pull it down
Oh, nevermind.
It's not showing at all
OBS could capture it but not but before there is it
for whatever reason it's not showing.
I don't know what's up.
Oh, there's my reason
I forgot to turn it on
Let's get the volume fix first cuz
Why do we have to save first? Why can't we just adjust it as we go?
Oh my, the motion blur you see that? The motion blur on the scrolling,
Holy
That is... oh my, okay.
I love that.
Okay.
I love that
controls...
change input mapping...
Oh, no, does it not have a playstation
No
But wait, it captures though.
My mouse disappeared when I moved the controller
Microsoft, that's a missed opportunity!
Oh my god, hold on where is my Xbox controller?
I'm gonna go grab them right now
They have the guts to bring the game to steam
but not have the guts to bring PlayStation controls into here
You kidding me
That aside.
!-
I got my Xbox controller.
Now, I just gotta plug it in
'right.
Let's get the cable.
ERH!
Let's plug it in port number one and the controller...
Wee~
Oh? There's the window sound the satisfying usual window sound.
Hey, it works.
Let's go.
Works by default
Difficulty
Mmm, how about I have it off?
Yeah, we'll have that. Let's go hard...
on the driving part except for shifting.
I can't shift.
Driving line, we'll turn off driving line
because we all know that driving line is cringe
Launch control.
Ooh, okay.
Hold e-brake and throttle when stationary until the it stops increasing
then release it to launch
I know what launch control is, but why is there a toggle for that?
Isn't that per the car basis or something?
Oh,well.
There is one thing I have to take care of though,
and that would be copyrights
Streamer mode.
No HDR display.
Okay
60 frames v-sync
Yeah, sure.
I'll have v-sync drive for driving games, v-sync is not too important
But if you're playing FPS, then yes, it would be important.
Motion blur, fuck you...
Okay
Graphics, yeah, let's turn up way down, but we'll have minimum of everything.
So like this
We'll have the minimum of everything
Well a little of everything, you know what?
No, no, no, no, no. No.
I got a different idea
Let's kick it.
Let's kick it up the notch, max out the graphics
and then we'll go down from here on
We'll figure out how things goes
Raytracing, let's go
They have ray tracing!
Right, let's start.
Let's see how the frame rate goes.
Oh, here comes
Oh, my frame rates
The problem with me using the Xbox controllers is listen to this
It's sticky.
I need to dismantle this controller one day and actually fix it.
Oh, here begins
Oh my god, that was so loud.
Holy that is loud
Ramiro: Home
Ramiro: The most beautiful place on Earth.
Ramiro: Where everyone is welcome.
Ooh.
Ramiro: Together, we can explore the wonder and beauty of Mexico.
Ramiro: Experience true freedom.
Ramiro: Feel alive.
Oooh, family.
Vin Diesels: Family, family, family...
Ramiro: Let's go together as friends...
Ramiro: ... and family.
FAMILY!!! Ay, let's gooooo!
Ramiro: You may ask, are we ready for what happens next?
This feels like Vin Diesel for some reason
Ramiro: My friend, one thing I have learned chasing the horizon...
Ramiro: Sometimes... you just have to let go and enjoy the ride.
Oh, here it begins.
Oh hold up, my frame rate is 44 right now.
Ok, I know how much it is now.
A to jump into the horizon.
Can I please press the pause button to turn the graphics down?
I want the maximum experience
God dang it.
Oh
Actually, it's not so bad.
41 frames while visually painful it's not so bad.
Oooh, drop it while it's hot.
Let's go
But please let me at least press the start button.
Let me go and turn down the graphics real quick.
AHHH, the framerates!
Ah, finally, okay.
Okay settings.
Where you at?
Um here
Okay, let's turn it down now
Video, no not here, graphics.
Yes.
Let's turn it to just Ultra
No, um restart later.
See how much can we improve from here?
Okay, most of the settings does not apply right now so we have to restart for real
While we're at it, let's have a good look at the some of the settings.
This is without way twa-
what the fuck am I saying, ray tracing!
We turn it to ultra and we restart right now.
Hopefully it starts fast enough though.
God damn it.
It's taking quite a while
I'm gonna go gremlin mode at this rate.
Ah that's so loud, why is there no skip button for this?
Microsoft why?
We're back in the video again, aren't we?
Can I skip this this time?
Can I skip it?
Like for real?
I want to skip it, please.
I've watched it once and I don't want to watch it twice, k.
God damn it
Okay lesson learned,
if I want to change graphic settings, finish the tutorial first
Weeeee.
ARRIBA!!!
Let's go
Is my controls working properly?
Ramiro: Bienvenido a Mexico (Welcome to Mexico)!
yes it is
Yo!
All right get to the Baja Circuit, gotcha.
Trust me bro, you won't die.
I can predict what happens next.
RTGame is going to crash his car on his start.
RT: This is not a safe place for a vehicle.
Ramiro: Bienvenido a Mexico (Welcome to Mexico)!
Ohh, who else is getting dropped?
Where we're dropping boys.
Chat: "a little traffic? Don't worry a more the more accident the better"
Indeed.
Woo...
What cars is this, is this McLaren?
Is this a McLaren?
Weee
No, it's not.
It's a Corvette.
No way.
It's a Chevro-
Is this a brand new Chevy?
No
I've not seen new stuff yet.
So I don't know.
Oy, yoy.
Yo, yo, yo, yo, yo, yo get out.
No, no, no, don't get in my way
Chat: "more accident, don't worry, we have family"
Indeed, we have family
Oh shit oh shit.
Oh shit.
Get back.
Get back on track.
Get back on track
Let's go come on, you're-
come on slow pokes get behind me into the smoke we go
Wooooooooo
VAMOS!!!! (LET'S GOOOOO!!!)
Let's go hehe.
Chat: "New York be like"
"New York be like" for real, for real
Ramiro: Okay, on my mark... five, four...
Nope heheee~
Ramiro: ...or now, that's fine.
"or now that's fine" HEHEHEHEHE
Ramiro: Er, this could get a little rough...
Okay, now.
Hopefully we're not committing war...
Pekora: AH↓HA↑HA↑HA↑HA↑
...crimes?
Let's go
That's not even the-
Wait, are we driving the same car?
I don't think so, amigo.
Ramiro: Flamingos!
Get out of the way
Chat: "Oh Mexico, I like crois-"
no, no, no, no, no, no not crois- that's French!
No
We're not having stereotypes
"I like burritos"
I like I'm not I'm not even paying attention to Ramiro anymore
Wee whoo~ that's cool, sheesh
Get on the track so I can get grip
What am I seeing? What am I supposed to see?
I've been seeing planes the whole time.
Ooooh
Okay.
Oh, the historical sites. I see what you meant.
I thought you're showing me the Horizon Festivals already
Okay, but there's more to come huh?
What do we have here?
Let's go
Whoo, come on, oh it's an an AM-
Oh, it's a Mercedes AMG.
Let's go
I don't think so.
But vamos indeed
It doesn't allow me to off-road with this car
What? Did Mercedes not like it or something?
Did Mercedes not like me driving in an off-road or something? Come on
Come on, not cool.
I wanna I wanna off-road this bitch
NO! No, no, no, no!
Who do you think? Who do you think?
Welcome to Horizon Festival for the fifth time!
Let's go!
Hey, oh my god, seriously, I'm a big fan of Forza Horizon games
Seriously, even though I started from for Horizon 3
I've been I've been very I've been very hooked on to the game.
I've been very very hooked on to the game
"Welcome to Mexico"
"Arrive at the horizon festival Mexico site" says the Xbox-
Xbox achievements
Very well, at least we got through the tutorial I guess.
Oh, we're straight into the menu already Wow, okay.
Sure.
All right
Hold on what is this haircut?
Hold on.
Sorry.
No, not the haircut the hair color like.
Oh wait, there's a hair and hair color section.
So maybe I'll just pick the person itself and then I'll go from there
I'll take this and then hair color.
Oh, yeah.
Okay, so it lets you do that
Chat: "You're gonna have blue hair and pronouns in this game."
I'll take this one. Hair color.
You know what pink actually suits this one don't you think lilac
I'm that looks more like lavender.
I don't know
Prosthetics
Oh that calls for inclusiv-
Inclusivity.
Okay, that's interesting, but I'm good for now
Amplification what that's so...holy.
That's a lot of details
They have pronouns
Scott: Kinda left me hanging there, y'know.
Scott: Scotty had his... his intro all timed out.
Scott: But it's cool, it's cool.
Poor Scott, we're living him hanging right now.
"Your character can be changed at any time
by visiting the site or your house."
Sure