(Stone grinding...)
Vtuber Q&A Self Introduction
(Yaaay~)
Are you ready?
Let's go!
What's your name?
Melori Valentine
How can I call you?
Melo-chan!
What kind of VTuber (are you)?
A Tech Wizardess VTuber
When's your birthday?
July 31st
How old are you?
Take a guess~ (Y2K)
What's your gender?
Trans Female.
How tall are you?
168cm (5' 6")
Where are you from?
It's a secret.
What's your charming point?
Being chill.
Please do an impersonation!
Kon-Koyo~!
Where are you active?
On YouTube!
Starting greeting?
Kon-Melo!
Ending greeting?
Otsu-Melo!
Fan emojis?
💫 🪄　（Sparkling Bling~!）
Live tag?
Don't have it yet.
Fanart tag?
#JankyMelori
Fan name?
Apprentices
Favorite color?
Pink (#FFAAFF)
What are your hobbies?
Messing with tech!
What are you good at?
Causing bugs
Now, confess your love!
AI SHITTEN DA!!! (LOVE YA!!!)
Favorite food?
Ramen.
Favorite drink?
Tea.
Favorite manga?
Flying Witch!
Favorite anime?
Lucky☆Star
Favorite game?
Burnout 3
Favorite music?
Anything goes.
Any dislikes?
Toxicity.
Who do you admire?
IRyS!
What's your dream?
Money!
Some closing remarks, please!♪
"Ya girl's got a story to tell...
T'is I, Melori, at your service!"
Be sure to check me out!
See ya next time!
(Yaaay~)
See yaaaaa~
Otsu-Melo!