There's something a familiar YouTuber once says.
USB.
Kon-Melo, it's ya Tech Wizardess girl, MeloriTensei.
And this right here is my personal USB
that has clutched me through all of university.
So if you're wondering what's inside this USB,
it contains a set of applications
that helped me through it because we got stupid thing called
university rules on the computer.
So what do you mean by that Mel?
Past Mel back in university, had to use computers
that were provided by the university in the computer lab
and something like that.
Imagine this, like lil Mel's just walking around
and she needs to grab a quick file from say
a network attached storage from the university,
but it's only accessible by those computers.
So I got to grab those.
In theory, I would just grab the files,
take it to my laptop and do the work there.
But what if I'm just, all I'm doing is just editing a file
or something like a notepad or something like that.
And now I got to grab notes from say,
probably my student's website from their own servers,
like a school servers, something like that.
What if I want to do all that?
Okay.
It should be pretty easy.
You remember the password, right?
Right?
Now this is where I hit a roadblock.
So it's 2020 at a time and people started adopting the use of something
we known as password managers.
So I started scrambling all my passwords and um,
lo and behold, it came biting at me
that I have to type every single passwords each time on those computers.
And I have to spend like probably what a whole minute to type my password down.
Yeah, that's fucking insane.
Unfortunately, no.
Well, in case you're wondering what took a whole minute,
it's a 16 character passcode.
So not to mention you got case sensitivity, numbers, symbols,
they're all in factor.
So it took me that long to type.
Yeah.
Little man had to go like grab a keyboard and go,
Oh, let me just, uh, shift, percent,
uh, small T wait, no, go back.
A big T.
Yeah.
Um, that, that's kind of the problem I brand into.
And I didn't want to go through all that all the time,
because what if someone needs the computer really quickly
because there's a limited count of computers at some point,
or maybe I just want to be quick because I hate wasting time.
This, this USB has saved me for a very, very long time.
And it saved me a lot of times that I otherwise wouldn't have.
So let's have a look at what's inside.
Let's grab this and plug it in, I guess.
Oh, before I'm plugging it in, in case you're wondering,
I'm a big fan of tea.
This is just an off-topic stuff, but I kind of like to show, well...
Think about Craft Computing.
You know how Craft Computing always has a beer at the end of videos.
Well how about have a tea for myself?
Ahmad tea.
Well, I'm just a big fan of drinking teas in general.
So, so this is just one of my choices of the moment
because I'm not too big of a person who buys a lot of tea at one time
and then drink them all at the same time.
I would be a psychopath if I'd be drinking that much.
But the boxes of tea that I currently have right now is
a chamomile lemongrass version.
And I gotta be honest, it's kind of very refreshing
and it gives you that calm vibes.
And while you're editing, it just brings you down to tranquility sometimes
while you're editing.
It's not so stressful and yeah, I guess I just enjoy it in general.
However, if you're wondering what's my top favorite tea,
it would be the Taiwanese High Mountain Oolongs.
Those give a serious massive punch.
It's kind of like an alternative to coffee
where the coffee gives you the energy punch
except in tea form.
So that's kind of how I feel about Taiwanese High Mountain.
Right, all the tea yapping out of the way,
let's get back to the main part of the video.
EEEEGH!
dadun~
da-DON~
Right, I got my USB plugged in and let's see what's inside.
Oh, um, there's nothing here.
Right.
If you know me as a person who does a lot of experiments with tech,
you know that I tend to clean up my USB a lot.
Yeah, um, those are one of those days, you know.
That means I think I probably have lost everything.
Well fear no more!
We could probably just minimize that
and open up the very program that we need.
It's called PortableApps.
So PortableApps.com allows you to have portable versions of your favorite apps
in the USB or whatever hard drive you're going to carry around.
It's basically meant to be like a mini program of your choice wherever you go.
It works on drives, it works on clouds, it works on anything,
it works on, well, anything you can put it in, it works.
With a small little caveat,
I've only had prior experience with the Windows version of the app,
so I can't really tell you anything about the Linux version or the Mac version
because they say it also works with it via crossover, WineSkin, WineBottler, PlayOnMac.
So your mileage may vary when you're on those platforms.
However, we're gonna get into here
and we're gonna start with downloading PortableApps.com
and soon enough, we're gonna have an installer.
After some time...
So once you're done, open up the installer as per usual and...
Oh look, Mallory is British.
Hahahahah, get the goofy ahh reference? No? Yeah... I know...
Okay, right, let's click on next and agree to the terms and yada yada yada.
And what we're gonna do is click on a new copy, a new installation,
and it's gonna ask you what type of installation you're gonna put it in,
in a cloud, in a portable, or like local, all users, or anywhere you want.
We're gonna pick portable.
And it's gonna ask you which drive, which in our case would be the D drive.
Haha, D.
Alright, let's press install.
Now we're gonna wait for it to finish installing.
And then following that, it's gonna ask if you wanna run the program.
And once you start, it opens up something like this.
You got the about page, and then you got something
that looks a little awfully like Windows 7 kind of start menu,
except everything PortableApps related.
I'm gonna close that for now because what we're gonna do
is we're gonna go to, oh,
it has done it for us.
I was gonna click on it but it didn't, it didn't let me,
it just opened it up itself.
Right, so we're gonna start grabbing things that we want.
So say for example I want my Chrome and Firefox,
so we just go scrolling through the list and uh, internet.
We got Firefox Portable right here, we just tick that,
and then say um, I probably want something like
Telegram desktop if you happen to use Telegram,
and download whatever you want.
There's even OBS Studio as well, that's surprising.
And if you need VLC, they, they do have VLC.
So you can see that there's a massive choice of applications that you can use,
however I did not use all of them unfortunately.
I did use a few, particularly Firefox.
And I think that's pretty much it.
Otherwise, it's kind of like my utility USB if anything.
But yeah, with that said, I'm gonna show you what I actually have,
because I fucking lied to you in the beginning.
I did not wipe my drive without knowing that, that I have my shit there.
I have backed it all up.
So I'm gonna bring them all back and then I'm gonna present to you what I got.
Right, so I've opened up my, my particular copy of PortableApps, and um,
well it's been quite a while since I last updated anything,
so there's some updates that it automatically came up as I opened it up.
So let's press install on those.
So it does most of it for you,
however there are times where they will ask you to confirm your agreement to the EULA,
because some apps require you to agree to the EULA before proceeding.
So this process of installing apps are not 100% unattended,
some of which requires your EULA attention.
So please take note of that.
So um, if you're planning on doing anything else while you're installing,
please make sure to check back on your computer when you're doing that.
Some more time later...
Right, with the update done, I'm gonna click finish,
and we can bring back our things.
And now, I'm not sure if you can imagine what kind of person I am, but…
(Boss music INTENSIFIES)
Yeah, um, I've downloaded everything.
To the point that, when I click this button,
I'm only left with 3 programs to download brand new.
I'll take care of that off camera.
But what's more important is that you can fit a lot of programs.
There's about over 50 gigs, just programs only.
That's freaking insane.
It's like, you can just grab a 64 gig USB and throw everything on it,
and booyah, you got yourself a hyper-utility USB for anything.
Like tech support for your grandma, tech support for yourself,
or a quick emergency schoolwork by borrowing someone's PC
and then not installing it onto their computer so you can use your own.
There's so many different things you can do with it, and there's everything.
Like Notepad++,
they got even LibreOffice as well, so you can do some of the office works.
It's just super, super flexible as a program.
And if you feel like it, you could probably also install your own portable apps
and chuck it into the apps folder,
but I'm not really too sure how that works
because I installed an older version of OBS and threw it in,
and it somehow showed up for me.
But not in my current case, but it did show up in the older case.
Not sure about today though, however, but your mileage may vary.
So this thing, considering being portable,
which also means that if you load Firefox on it, it's not gonna save into AppData,
it saves into its local folder as well,
so that means I could also save my password managers in there,
and I could get stuff copied and pasted very quickly
without having to worry about needing to install another program.
Uh, but Mel, doesn't that mean you're installing a program
or using a third-party program on a computer?
Technically, it's using third-party programs,
however, in my university, it said nothing about installing anything,
(Correction: What I meant is that it said nothing about...)
so I technically didn't install anything to the computer.
("running third party programs" just "installing" is no-no..)
I've only installed it to my USB for use on the USB,
and I'm only piggybacking the processing power from the desktop
that the university provided,
which technically, I'm still in the right of doing that.
But yeah, this is how this one tool has clutched my entire university life.
You may wonder to yourself, why don't you just bring your own laptop?
Well that's because my laptop battery was dead at the time.
Yeah, um, about that, um, you can see where I was going with that.
But yeah, I don't think there's much for me to yap about and show about,
but it is something that I would like to show and tell and yap about
primarily because I think it's worth showing
and it's kind of a cool concept in my opinion.
So that's pretty much it.
With that said, thank you all so much for watching.
Be sure to subscribe, be sure to press like, notification bell.
Want more tech videos?
Check out my videos tab.
If you want more gaming, check out the live tab.
And um, if you want to hang out with me, check out the discord,
and we probably talk about a lot of different stuff and stuff like that.
If you would like to support me financially, check out my Ko-fi
because none of these, like the computer I'm using, the equipment I'm using is free,
so hopefully we can be financially sustainable to be able to maintain
all these hardware that I'm currently using for filming.
But anyways, with that said, thank you all so much for watching,
and OtsuMelo deshita (It's been ya girl, Mel).
See ya!
Have a good day or night or whatever the time zone is at your place.
[Ko-fi] Thank you for supporting me financially!
Members: Jo, Natalie, Aerostatik, Xandra~ | One-off: Owa-San
[MeloriTensei 転性メロリ] Thank you for watching!
Check out my other contents!
Kay, top down camera done!
UGH UGH UGH UGH I almost dropped that fucking camera.
HAHAHAHA
I'm not dropping that camera ever again.