Guess who's back?
Back again.
That's right, this Android phone's back once more,
for one more extra flash.
If you remember the last
time I was flashing PixelOS
and then suddenly I switched to crDroid.
So when I was on crDroid, I was a little
disappointed in myself at some point,
because PixelOS was draining batteries
and I did not bring it up on video.
So when the maintainer of PixelOS and crDroid,
at least for now,
spoke about it in the comments
of that previous Android video,
check it out, link in the description.
He said that he was working on some stuff
and needed a whole lot more polishing
before it goes out to the public.
It was around that week that he
was just about to roll it out.
Few days after the video goes out,
it happened to be the day that
he wanted to put it out as well.
So I wanted to try out Android 14
now, now that I'm done with crDroid,
because there really isn't much
for me to mess around in crDroid,
except for the fact that I do have
one personal complaint about crDroid.
Maybe it's a LineageOS thing,
but Dolby Atmos integration on Crdroid
and LineageOS are a little bit funky
in a way that when you're up on a certain
volume meter, it gets stupid loud,
but then you take it down a step, it
suddenly becomes really, really soft.
I don't know if it's something to do
with software compensations or something,
but it is something that I didn't really enjoy
accidentally disturbing the neighbors
while I'm watching YouTube on the toilet.
So I want to explore somewhere
deeper and look around Android 14,
because currently on this crDroid,
it's actually just Android 13.
So I want to take it up a step.
14.
Let's see what's new in 14.
Let's experiment with whatever that's
available for me and just have fun.
"Well, Mel, you said Android
is a freedom operating system.
That means you could just root and
mess around with something, right?"
Yeah, technically you're not wrong.
However, I have rooted for a while,
but it kind of brought me more personal
inconveniences than conveniences.
So like, say I want to root
to solve a certain problem,
but then comes another problem
and then I solve this problem
and then a new problem comes up.
It just keeps coming on and on and on.
It becomes a little bit impractical
for my daily use at some point.
While it does bring a whole lot of conveniences,
like say using our great sponsor SD Maid SE Pro
to clear up a whole lot of junk deeper
than what stock Android can get you.
But handling root related stuff like passing
SafetyNet and solving Dolby Atmos issues
and even just down to getting
fonts look just right for you.
It's starting to become really
technical that you start to weigh out
between how much time you spend on
researching and understanding it
to is it worth the amount
of time you spend doing it?
Is it rewarding?
It's basically what I want to say.
However, it started to become
less and less rewarding
and it started to become a lot more punishing.
Blame Google for that.
So instead, I'm just going to
go back to stock clean Android
and we're jumping to Pixel OS instead.
So if you do want instructions
for how I flashed to PixelOS,
check out that previous video
in the description below.
Because in this video, I'm
just going through like a vlog.
So as usual, we back everything up and
we're going to clean up everything here.
You don't really have to clean it up,
but I like to uninstall things first
before I leave this operating system.
Think of it as like a proper send off.
Like when you're about to move to a new house,
you would clean up the old house first
before you move into the new one, right?
So I like doing that pretty much.
And that's where I would like to
thank our great sponsor, SD Maid SE.
Especially my great friend
Darken, the guy who made it,
for sponsoring not just this video but
my entire life of content creation.
I wouldn't be here making all
these videos if it weren't for him.
However, even though it's just a one-time sponsor,
I still appreciate the app as if
it has helped me the entire life.
So please check him out in
the description below as well.
More about the app at the
end, at the sponsor segment.
Right.
Let's get right into…
Oh will you focus, baby?
Are you going to focus?
Right.
Let's get close enough and let's
start uninstalling some stuff.
So let's just yeet yeet yeet...
And we confirm deletion.
Look at that.
How it just clicks the uninstall button
for you and all you have to do is press OK.
Ain't that great?
Ooh, that's a lot of apps going away.
Ayyy, there we go.
We're back to really really clean one.
Heh heh heh.
Alright, fooling around aside.
We're going to get real serious.
And as always, I got them prepared already.
Since we're just jumping to PixelOS,
we're not really doing anything.
We just need the usual stuff.
Odin, PixelOS, and PixelOS Recovery.
How simple is that?
Right, let's get right into it.
I can't believe I'm going to be doing this
because I'm sitting at the edge of my chair
just squishing my camera stand like
how I would do to an anime degenerate.
And as always, the instructions
are always available on XDAForums.
Please do check it out when
you need more references.
And according to the instructions,
it says to make sure your
device's bootloader is unlocked.
Let's check that.
Wait a flippin' second, I
don't even need to check that.
It's already unlocked.
Because you need to have your bootloader
unlocked if you need to have custom OS.
However you can lock your bootloader,
but you would need to tell the bootloader
the signature of the OS it needs.
Which is usually a massive hassle, so
nobody really does that realistically.
So let's skip that.
Power off device and get into download mode.
Okay, let's get into download mode.
Here we go.
Let's press the power button.
Power off.
So much faster than before.
Download the recovery image for your device.
So we're going to be on PixelOS's website
and we're going to scroll down to Galaxy
Note 10+, at least that's for my device.
And we're going to get the recovery,
which will take us to SourceForge
and we get the latest version as usual.
Oh while you're here, you might as well download
the latest build as well of the ROM itself.
Don't forget that.
And over here we're going to need to
rename the image file to "recovery".
Keep in mind that this has
to be called "recovery.img"
because Odin is going to read
inside a layer of an archive
and know, "oh this goes straight
to recovery, okay I see."
Because for whatever weird reasons, we
can't put image files directly into Odin.
We have to archive it into an archive called tar.
How dumb is it?
Press okay and there should be
a resulting tar file as usual.
And now we open up Odin and we're going
to get this baby into download mode.
So volume up and down, which
I can mash with my fingers.
And the USB cable.
Eyyy...
Going into download mode by pressing volume up
and we're here as usual.
Now what we need to do is click AP, get
into that folder and click "recovery.tar".
It has to be on AP, keep in mind,
or else you'll brick your device.
And now we just send her.
Wee!
You would sometimes accidentally end up getting
back into your Android OS after flashing,
but that's perfectly fine.
As long as you still have access to
your recovery, that's perfectly fine.
Restart, recovery, we're taking this the lazy way.
While you wait, you can also close
Odin, we don't need that anymore.
But instead, we're going to need our terminal.
We'll get to you in a moment.
Okay, we're in PixelOS recovery as
you can clearly see, PixelOS up here.
And what we're going to do is [Factory reset],
which means we're going to wipe
everything real clean again,
just like I said in that video.
So here we go.
Format data.
Format cache.
Right, now that we're all cleaned up,
[Apply update] and [Apply from ADB].
And if you remember from the previous video
or any other Android flashing guide video,
then you would know by now.
[adb sideload]
Then the file name.
And we send her.
Now with PixelOS, GApps is built in.
So we don't really need to install
MindTheGApps at all, so we just wait here.
And then we'll be done by then.
It's real dead simple.
If you want a root, you might
also want to flash Magisk as well.
Uhhhhhhhhhh.
Uhhhhhhhhhhhh.
Gosh, if flashing could be any faster, honestly.
I'm talking about you, Apple and Google.
Gosh.
Oh, fuck.
I'm going to stop complaining.
I'm just going to sit here and wait.
Maybe drink some water.
I don't have my tea this time.
Six thousand years later.
Ah, finally, we're done.
Now we just Format data once more.
And just reboot.
And in theory, we should have a clean PixelOS,
and everything will be happily ever after.
Just as I thought you were about to be finished,
that was almost misleadingly fast.
Damn, the loading bar takes a
while for you to come out, eh?
You cheeky little bastard.
Oh, that was fast.
There was no warning right there.
What the fuck?
Okay, let's get through the setup as usual.
Hopefully this should be fast.
I really just want to finish recording
and start playing Blue Archive again.
Oh, you bet it will take a few minutes.
Gosh darn.
Oh, finally.
Finally, we're moving.
My camera is almost running
out of batteries, holy shit.
I'll get to you later,
and I'll get to you later,
later.
Screw your locations.
There we go.
PixelOS.
That's pretty much it.
There's really not much for me to say.
It's just your old bog standard PixelOS.
But now I'm going to set this up off camera,
and that's pretty much it.
Thank you all so much for watching.
Be sure to subscribe, be sure to
press like, all the usual yada yada.
And I hope you enjoy my other types of content,
which are gaming content, VTubing content.
And I appreciate the massive
amount of new subscribers
that I've been getting from
that previous Android video.
So thank you all so so so so so much for watching.
And with that said, it's ya girl Melori,
and I'll catch you guys on
the next video or stream.
Otsu-Melo!
See ya!
Oh yeah, with that said, be sure to
check out our sponsor, SD Maid SE.
Here you go.
Tired of slowness and long loading?
Want to make more space for your stuff?
Well SD Maid SE is here to help.
SD Maid SE is a junk cleaner made
by an indie developer named Darken.
Some apps tend to leave leftover files we
don't need after we're done using them.
That's where SD Maid SE comes in to help.
Now you can do that manually, but time is money.
With SD Maid SE, you can
automate a good deal of that,
and leave precious times to the
things that really matter the most.
Unlike other system junk cleaners,
SD Maid SE does not collect any
form of personally identifiable info
that could be sold to scummy
data miners for profit.
Nor does it bombard you with a
fuckton of ads that waste your time.
Like I said, time is money.
SD Maid SE heavily relies on the generosity
of the community to stay alive and going.
App improvements happen with
the help and contribution
from the great community in GitHub and Discord.
So if there's any bug with
the app, you're never alone.
What are you waiting for?
Get your phone cleaned with SD Maid SE
on the Google Play Store or
GitHub in the description below.
Oh, maybe I should clean my phone screen too.
With that, thanks to Darken Development
for encouraging me to walk
forward in content creation.
Catch yanext time!