Imagine this,
you're a technician,
and you got a whole lot of computers to completely reinstall operating systems.
but they all vary from one operating system to another.
Say one guy wants Windows 10 and the other guy wants Windows 11.
And then this other dude wants Ubuntu Linux.
And then some weirdo wanna install RedStar OS!
(North Korean Anthem Intensifies)
Now you won't have to format your USB drive again and again and again
because this is where Ventoy comes in.
It is basically a bootloader that loads up
ISOs that you can save in bulk in that same USB.
(Windows noises)
Potentially saving you time, saving you space, whatnot.
We're just gonna cut the crap and get straight to it because...
there you have it!
That's the video.
(Outro Music)
(Sike)
What?
You're expecting more?
Alright, fine.
I'm recording this in daytime anyways,
there's gonna be lots of noise in the background.
But yeah, here are all the features that you'll be expecting.
but to put it in layman's terms: Very flexible, very customizable.
Simple as that.
How about we get straight into it?
So first thing what you got to do is click on Downloads,
and based on the operating system that you're currently on, pick them.
If you're on Windows, then you you gotta be on Windows,
duh.
And you should expect your files right here.
And the first thing you want to load up is Ventoy2Disk.
This will need your admin permissions.
So obviously you're going to need it on,
and then you get yourself this thing.
This is where you plug in your USB of choice.
Back up everything on your USB because you're gonna lose it all.
It's going to erase everything in the drive.
Now we got it plugged in.
Let's refresh and we get ourselves the USB that we want.
And now what you want to do is look into the options
because there may be some things that you might want.
So say for example: you want secure boot because you already had secure boot on,
for say, the motherboard or the chipset you're on.
Then you would want to have that.
Otherwise, you're gonna need to turn it off whenever you use it.
And then on to partition style.
This would be very dependent on the type of computers that you usually service.
If you're maintaining devices that are primarily really really old
that are some time around 2013's and earlier,
you would want the older style of partition called Master Boot Record (MBR).
Otherwise modern devices would be fine with GPT aka GUID partition table.
I'm not gonna elaborate into that
Eheheh~
And then when you get into partition configuration,
this is where you can customize the file system that you want for for the USB.
I highly recommend, if possible, avoid FAT32
because FAT32 as a file system has a 4GB limit per file.
And some installers these days are larger than it
Say for example a particular ISO of Windows
that has both 32-bit 64-bit Home, Pro, Home N, Pro N...
Pro K, Home K and so forth.
(Basically all the variants of Windows)
So in those cases you would prefer exFAT or NTFS
Though, I would recommend exFAT
But I'm going to use NTFS for my own case.
And then you gotta press OK to confirm that obviously.
And double check the settings that you have for Ventoy in package
to make sure that this is exactly what you want.
Because when you click install, there's no turning back.
Warning: The device will be formatted and all the data will be lost.
Continue?
Yes.
Double check.
Now it's doing its job.
We're gonna give it some time
Congratulations: Ventoy has been successfully installed to the device.
Great
So in the future if there's a new Ventoy version,
you can just download the same installer and click update instead
and this would just update the Ventoy bootloader
into the USB without affecting your settings
Right before we get into the drives, we're gonna figure out what's going on
So we're gonna need Disk Management.
And what's really going on is that Ventoy has created two different partition,
one is particularly for for the for the motherboard to boot into,
and a separate one that is specifically where you store all the ISOs,
and this is currently visible right now as it is mounted.
So we're gonna get into that.
Now that we're here on the Ventoy folder,
as you can see it's currently deserted and really empty.
This is where you start piling up your ISOs.
You can do it however you like.
The same way as how you keep them in your hard drive.
It supports any kind of directory style.
Just do it and just go ham until you run out of storage.
Now, with that said,
We're gonna get into the second program that we can see right here
It's called VentoyPlugson.
Basically Ventoy comes with a plug-in system that you can customize your Ventoy installation with
So we're gonna run that.
And just before anything starts,
It's going to ask which drive that you want Ventoy Plugson to connect to
Then you start it,
And then your browser will open up a new tab
that takes you to the Ventoy Plugson UI.
This is where you start customizing.
So the first page starts with everything about the information about your drive,
and then following next is the Global Control plugin.
Basically, what this does is that you can change the default settings
of how Ventoy behaves on the menu.
So you can change the menu language.
You can also change where it starts to search from
and tell it whether to bypass Windows 11's check by default
same goes to NRO aka network requirements in case you don't know.
And you can also set menu mode.
Say for example, you have a cascade of folders.
Then you can set it to tree mode so you can go in by by the way you do your folders.
Rather than list view mode which lists everything it sees from top to bottom.
And then for menu timeout,
basically, what it does is it boots automatically
to your currently selected image in that said countdown.
Should be pretty much the same as when you dual-boot stuff or
when you're loading into some operating system in some way.
And there's a whole slew of of different settings that you can set,
And they all have descriptions that explain to you what it does.
So that's pretty cool
Now following next is my absolute favorite: the theme plug-in
So in case you don't know, Ventoy is based on grub, a bootloader made for Linux.
Well, mostly Linux.
So since it's based on grub, you could in theory
just look for themes through gnome-look.org
and look specifically for grub themes
and there there will be a whole lot of choices of amazing themes
that you can customize the look of your Ventoy with.
You can also do the same with the normal grub
because they're technically the same thing anyways.
However, we're not gonna follow whatever's over here
because that's for normal grub.
We're using Ventoy,
so this is going to be a special case for us.
Say for example, you have found a theme that you wanted
and then you want to apply it to your Ventoy.
How do we do that?
It's really really simple
First up you got to download the theme file.
Now different themes would have different file structures.
Say for example, you want it on 1080p
then they will call it fullHD.tar.
But it is the creators choice to how they sort out their files.
So you're going to need to pay attention on the file name
Right, let's get straight to downloading.
Once you're done downloading
we're gonna need to start extracting the archive.
Choose your favorite archive manager and extract the file.
If possible, go even deeper into the .tar file as well
Because what we need is the folder.
Following everything that it has
and the most important one: the theme.txt file.
Because the theme.txt file consist of information
that grub needs to apply as a theme.
So what we need to do is take this out
and if you feel like it, for organization purposes,
create a folder called themes
That way it's much neater for you
You can put it anywhere even in Ventoy's own folder
and put the entire theme folder into this.
So now we got the theme and the theme.txt file.
What we need to do is get back to Plugson
and add the directory to the theme as an option.
So we paste it here...
and you gotta make sure you have theme.txt on as well.
Now it has found the theme it should apply on its own.
You can also add different types of font that you like,
and you can also set the graphics settings for this.
For which default resolution grub should run on,
I'm gonna set mine to 1080p for convenience.
But hey, it's your choice and theme's choice
Now below here are all different types of plugins
that personally I have not really used.
But they do seem really really useful
Especially with particularly auto install.
Say, you have a lot of different machines
that you want to install at bulk
but you don't want to go through the setup
because you're getting really lazy.
So, auto install just does the whole installation process completely unattended
completely unattended so things gets faster for you.
And then you also got the password plugin
where you can lock your ventoy with specific passwords.
So when people end up stealing your drive
They can't get into it,
or at least get into booting it to say the least.
Right. Now with that said.
We're gonna close Plugson.
And don't forget to stop it as well, and exit.
And now it's the matter of populating your drive.
So I may kind of be a data hoarder in some sense,
where I collect a massive size of ISOs
so huge that it piles up to the hundreds
So I'm probably gonna copy a small handful of them
just to illustrate an example
Let's see... I'm gonna copy Ubuntu.
Maybe a bit of Manjaro.
Oh, oh ,oh.
Maybe maybe a bit of Windows 11
Maybe one of my favorite toolbox ever HirenBoot (Hiren's Boot CD).
Basically, it's kind of like system rescue (on Linux) but Windows
Maybe even memtest64+ just to illustrate
that I may be that one technician that might want to do some testings
And of course with every USB drive
they always take centuries to transfer.
So we're gonna sit right here and wait
Narrator: Two hours later~
Right, now that I've populated with the ISOs that I want to bring in.
We can now just unplug the USB and boot off from that USB.
Let's do it
ERGH!!!
(Windows Disconnect sound)
Just get 'er plugged in...
With Ventor now plugged in, we're gonna power it on.
And get straight to the BIOS
Awh, drat.
And we're gonna boot into the BIOS.
Now that we're in the BIOS, you can see that in the list of boot devices
There is my USB so we're gonna try to boot into that.
And there you have it
If you remember that we have previously set a theme
This is the theme that we got.
If you do not wish to have a theme momentarily
and you wanted more clearer view of the grub controls.
You could just press F7,
and it should give you the plain version of grub again.
And as you can see it shows everything that I have.
And there's a whole slew of options that you can use
such as you can you can shut it back down as well,
you can also look at look into your hardware info,
set resolutions, set your display modes and so forth.
This is all what we've been coming for.
The ability to enter any of these OSes without having to format your USB
That's where the convenience comes in.
So say for example, I'm in the mood of Manjaro.
Let's just boot it in right now
And here we are.
We're in we're kind of in Manjaro's bootloader.
And we can just pick our usual choices and stuff
and install the operating system as we please,
just like a normal operating system installer.
Say for example, I'm not feeling like Manjaro
How about Windows?
Yes, you can.
And there we have it, a Windows installation media.
So like I said, Ventoy is a very versatile bootloader.
So, I have my own USB stick that I'm actually actively using
as my utility toolkit for these kinds of things.
So I'm gonna show you how mine looks like
So I basically set mine to have a theme of Honkai Star Rail
and a whole slew of different kinds of themes.
And I've also have tree-mode enabled,
so it'd be sorted by the folders I've set.
So like say, I've sorted it by Linux and Windows.
So, if I want Linux I go in there.
Just like how you usually navigate a folder with...
Say I want... I want Ubuntu but Ubuntu is based on Debian.
So I sorted it that way, [Debian] and then [Ubuntu].
And then all my Ubuntu is over here and so forth, that kind of way.
and then we got Windows, we got Windows 10, Windows 11...
It's all pretty simple
Now say I still don't want this kind of theme.
I could just do that
See, now everything's simple again.
Now say I don't like the current theme I'm on.
You could just select the theme
and this is all the installed themes I've currently got.
Say I'd say I'm not in the mode of Black Swan from Honkai Star Rail at the moment
I'm more of a Sparkle simp.
We can turn on Sparkle,
re-enable my theme and there we have it. We got Sparkle.
Now say if I'm not into Sparkle
and I'm not into Honkai Star Rail at the moment.
I can just pick any other theme.
Like say a simple just black theme, you know.
A very very simple one, nothing too complex.
Or a very 8-bit looking style kind of theme.
But yeah.
With that said, that's pretty much all I can show you about Ventoy.
But if you do know better use cases for all the other plugins,
let me know in the comments below.
and hopefully more people can understand what you can do with Ventoy.
And with that said,
I'm gonna link the resources in the description below.
And thanks for watching and I'll see you guys next time.
OtsuMelo deshita (It's been ya girl Mel).
See ya~
ERGH!!!
(Windows Disconnect sound)