(Emotional music)
We've come a long way.
Ever since the start of the channel (201 subs),
where I've began creating videos regularly.
It was tough. (436 subs). But I persevered.
One day, miracle struck (706 subs).
And you guys joined in on the ride!
You all have been my motivation to keep doing what I love.
This, right here, is you all. Ones who joined, rode
and walked through the journey with me.
I am at a loss for words. All I can say is, thank you.
(Fireworks)
Thank you all for sharing me around,
chatting with me, supporting me.
Despite the obstables and struggles I've went through behind
the scenes, you 've always stuck with me, looking after me.
I hope for better progress in the coming years.
And I hope you'll still come along with me.
Have a Happy New Year of 2025.
And as always, おつメロでした.
(OtsuMelo deshita, It's been ya girl Mel.)
See ya in 2025!