Did you get the hint?
Still not?
Is that enough for you?
Not enough?
Still not enough?
Oh fuck, it stopped the recording!
Fuck!
Take 2
I wonder if you got the hint.
Still not enough?
Is that not enough?
More?
That should give a hint.
Kon-Melo!
It's ya tech wizardess girl, MeloriTensei!
And as you can see with this chaos clump of technologies right now,
you may not understand what this means.
Why is there two VR controllers
and one, two, three, four devices,
and one more to come later, on the table.
Well if you've read the title of this video
you would understand that yes,
I'm strapping these things on my body.
For what?
For VR.
So if you don't know, there's this project out there called SlimeVR.
So what SlimeVR does is that they basically took what's already
in the technology of the phones,
like the accelerometer, the gyroscope,
and all kinds of motion-related sensors in the device,
made it simpler in a tiny PCB, a dedicated one,
(Correction: "Simpler in the sense of making out of inexpensive components on a PCB)
and booyah, you got a tracker.
(Credit: Sorakage033 on GitHub)
And then if you combine five of them,
you got yourself a full lower body skeleton.
Why five of them?
That's because primarily the data that is available for the accelerometer
is not enough to form up three, like say two legs and a hip.
Unfortunately that's not enough because it doesn't know precisely how far it goes,
but it does know approximately how far it goes.
So it's not position perfect.
There may be a bit of yaw here and there,
but that's something that can be fixed pretty easily honestly.
However, what if we take this, we take whatever SlimeVR has done
in the current time, and we return to the monkey days
(SlimeVR Docs also points out that the experience I'm attempting will be "subpar")
and use the very device that inspired it.
(Not really "inspired". Idk why I said that >.<)
So we're going to put this away and maybe make some room for this.
Let's give the iPhone a spotlight, I suppose.
So you haven't watched the prior video of mine
of replacing the battery for this phone,
then you wouldn't understand why this phone came to be.
So I've done some more experiments, jailbroken and stuff like that.
That's primarily because I was trying to archive the app in question,
but to no avail, I'm still not at that level of expertise
to archive the app just yet.
But that's fine, that's perfectly fine.
I am in no rush of doing it.
So the app in question that we're looking for right now is…
OwO-
Track.
Are you okay?
Hello?
Oh, it doesn't work with this tip.
Hold on.
Much better.
There we go.
So the app in question that we're looking for is OwOTrack.
And as you can see, it shows motion sensor, accelerometer,
gyroscope, magnetometer.
It's using every available sensor that has something to do with motion
to create a positional data to send to a central server,
but not external central server, just central in the way that
it is in your computer to create a skeleton.
But we'll get to that in a moment.
We'll explain how that works in a moment.
But first things first, what we need to do is we have to
go to the connect tab and type down the IP address of the said device
that we're going to be on.
However, there are some things we still have to do prior.
So what we need to do is create a wifi hotspot
from the PC that you want to have your VR session in.
Well, that's mostly for latency reasons,
but if you're really, really close to the router,
you don't really have to do that at all.
But because I'm kind of far away from the router,
it may be a necessity for me.
So we're going to get into that.
Right.
It's been a while since we're back on the desktop.
So what we want to do is we're going to have our settings tab.
And what we want from here is we'll create a mobile hotspot that is on wifi,
specifically on 2.4 Ghz, because you'll thank me later in the future.
But it's mostly because it's far easier when it comes to coverage wise,
if you're a little bit far or if you're in a radio noisy environment
or particularly 5 Ghz, especially when it's in the trend these days,
then 2.4 might be a good option sometimes.
It may be particularly 2.4 Ghz noisy in some other places,
but depending on the situation of the wifi in your area,
feel free to choose accordingly.
But in my specific case, it would be 5 Ghz noisy.
So I would choose the other instead
where it's a little bit quiet on 2.4 at the moment.
So with that said, let's turn on the mobile hotspot.
And what we want to do is we're going to try to connect to it right now.
After some time of connecting all devices to the same network...
Now depending on whether you're using a mobile hotspot from Windows
or you're on your local network, this might differ a whole lot.
So in my case, specifically on a Windows hotspot,
since the computer in question is hosted on exactly the same machine
where the skeleton server is going to be,
which is known as the SlimeVR server,
we only need to refer to the address known as the router.
However, if you're using your existing local connections,
then the local IP for the SlimeVR server would be your answer.
So once you've typed down the IP address that you're looking for,
we're going to prepare the other devices to also all do the same.
And hello, Redmi.
So if you've seen the previous video where I talked about holding onto a Redmi
as a contracted phone, then you know that I was going to plan to do something
with the device.
However, for this very video, we're going to be doing something a little different.
Considering this video being a SlimeVR video,
we're heavily focusing on using the phones as the way they are for a tracker.
So currently it's on crDroid in case you're wondering,
because LineageOS has been discontinued for this phone.
Not exactly discontinued, more like there's absolutely no maintainer,
so there are some maintainers on the good guys at crDroid,
so I'm just settling in crDroid for the time being.
It won't be on crDroid for long.
But regardless, we got OwOTrack installed on Android as well,
as you can see, it's not just iOS, Android has it too as well.
So we're going to do exactly the same.
So we're going to input the IP address for the SlimeVR server,
and then we just, we'll press connect later.
We're going to hold onto it for now, and push that aside.
We're going to do the same for the other devices that we have,
and sometimes auto-connect works.
Oh, it filled itself in, let's go.
That is if you actually have SlimeVR already turned on
in the background on your computer.
And finally, the big ol' iPad.
Oh damn.
Hey, Vei.
Okay, we got all the IPs written down,
and you could also do a test connection if you already have turned it on prior,
like I did just mention before.
And now we're getting ready.
So we're going to need to hop over to the computer side of things
to take care of this.
Right, so now what we've got to do is, we're going to open up SlimeVR.
Feel free to put it on full screen if you feel like it,
so let's get it all set up.
And usually with traditional SlimeVR equipment,
you are expected to type in your Wi-Fi credentials first
because what it needs to do is to apply these Wi-Fi settings through cable,
because these tiny custom PCB chips are instructed to do very, very specific things,
and this SlimeVR program is meant to program these things to do so.
However, since we're putting those IP address ourselves,
we'll have to skip the Wi-Fi settings for now.
And what we want to do right now is,
we're going to turn on every single one instance,
so like all of these down here.
Alright, once everything's connected,
we're going to start setting them accordingly.
So this is where you're going to need to know
which device goes to which part of your body,
because we're going to need to start assigning those trackers accordingly.
So for now, we're going to need to set a lower body set because,
or you could set the core set instead,
because we're going to need the hip tracking instead of the chest tracking.
And I'll explain why later.
(I ended up forgetting to explain: The iPad can't mount on my body, unless I use tape, it hurts.)
So first up, I'm going to decide that I want this iPhone to be my left ankle.
So the good part is that as long as you're connected to SlimeVR,
whatever movements you're doing, it can be seen on SlimeVR on the computer.
So you can see that it's glowing,
that's because I'm doing intense motion like this.
("intense motion")
So it's showing some form of activity.
So we're going to need to click on that,
then we know that it is this tracker.
So now that we've set this one,
we're going to set it aside and get onto the next one.
So I probably want this one to be set to my right ankle.
So let's do this.
And we know that it is this one.
We can rename that in the future,
but for now, we just don't have that choice just yet.
And then probably we would want that for the thighs.
So maybe this one for the left thigh.
Right.
We got that one taken care of.
And we got one more, that is the hip.
Okay, now that we got all the parts, wait a second.
The right thigh is not even set, but I ran out of device on my table.
Hmm.
One moment.
I canibalized my tracking iPhone for this vid.
You won't expect this phone to be joining the SlimeVR video.
That's because this is actually my real daily driver
and I don't really show my actual stuff because of privacy reasons.
Well, welcome to the gang, I suppose.
And we're going to connect it and assign that to the right thigh.
All right, with everything set up,
we're going to head on to the next step.
So right here is where it's expected you
to have already mounted the devices onto yourself.
So, but Mel, they're phones.
How do you expect to strap devices onto yourself?
What are you going to use?
Fucking tape?
I got one better than you.
Wait a second.
So I went to AliExpress and looked for the cheapest thing
that I could use to strap phones on myself.
So I got phone straps.
And all we got to do is get all these devices placed into the straps.
Like this.
Right, once you got the phone in the phone stash thingy-majig,
you're going to want the phone, the upper side of the phone,
like facing up like this.
We're going to want it to be,
hello,
(Leg reveal? O.O)
on your legs, facing upwards towards you.
Kind of like when the leg is flowing up towards you and your body.
So you're going to want it in that general direction
when you put phones on yourself.
That applies to every single phone, including the thigh one and the hips.
So you're going to want to do that
because primarily this is the best for its tracking.
Same could be applied for even the general Slime VR tracker.
You're going to need that as well.
Now it can be a little bit difficult to walk in phones
because that's not really the actual intended use of a phone.
So you either just get used to it or, I don't know,
engineer something, I guess.
Now that we got all strapped up,
what we're going to do is we're going to try to
get to automatic mounting and make sure that all your trackers
are set up correctly.
So that includes putting on your headset
and moving your hips and see if your hips are
also doing all that job.
Your legs, your feet, your thighs, and your hand controllers.
So I'm controlling this interface right now
using the SteamVR desktop interface right now so it'll be more easier.
So what you want to do is I have my all trackers on
and what it wants you to do right now is stand straight,
like put your hands on the side, and also stand up straight
so that it detects everything for a full reset.
Once you've done that, what you want to do is get squatting.
You're going to need to squat, which could also mean destroying my phone straps,
but whatevs, it's for a video.
So you're going to need to squat down really, really hard.
You can see on that next panel that I am trying really hard.
And we're going to need to get them a little back,
like as you can see, this curves in the hand like that.
It's almost like you're actually skiing, so do that.
And once you've done that, in theory it works.
However, if you're wondering what's with my hands overlapping each other,
that's just a bug in which controller it actually is using.
It's kind of hilarious.
It's having difficulties differentiating what's left and what's right.
So, eh.
But now that you look carefully,
you'll notice that it's actually fully working now.
Look at that.
How cool is that?
Ah, I almost dropped the phone.
I gotta be really careful.
And I can kind of move my thigh as you can see,
kind of, to some extent.
So I can also move my ankles a little bit.
Let me try to move over to the side.
I mean not to the side, to the front.
Like I can kind of shift my ankles like that.
It's kind of janky, but to be fair, it's a phone
and you can't really expect too much from it.
If you want a more precise tracking, it's always better
to use a more proper SlimeVR tracker.
However, as it currently stands, it somehow works, I guess.
This entire section of video was rejected for being INSANELY INACCURATE.
Thus, here's Editor Mel.
Simply, the job Body Proportions does is measuring the trackers
so the measurement is accurate matching the real world to SteamVR.
Start off with checking whether your tracks (including your hand controllers)
are working. Then, do a full reset as instructed.
Back to the Video Mel!
And it's gonna want you to do very specific instructions
and you're gonna need to follow precisely what they want on the screen.
You gotta follow the steps.
So you can feel free to pause this part of the video
and read what they have there, but I'm going to follow it as it is.
(The next part is skipped for privacy reasons. Please use your accurate height)
(to avoid offsetting the virtual trackers it's gonna deploy on SteamVR)
Now that we got to this step, you can feel free to press play
and then it's going to tell you what you want to do.
So it has to be specifically these steps in sequence
and then repeat the whole cycle again.
(Until the recording is over)
Because what it's looking for is a specific pattern to how you're moving
and then based off of that, measure out the proportion of your body.
So you gotta make sure you try not to screw it up.
So have a little rehearsal before you do this process.
Once it does the whole thing, it should give you a result.
Unfortunately, I am terrible with the numbers,
so I'm just gonna assume that they're correct.
And there you have it.
We got kind of a result that we may want.
You can see that I can kind of move my thigh like that
and I could probably stand on something
and you'd see that I'm standing on something.
So we're kind of all set.
And that's pretty much it.
This is how you strap phones onto yourself to play VR.
Right, let's get on VRChat.
Right, now that we're in the world in VRChat,
what you want to do is we're going to click on "Calibrate FBT" [Full Body Tracking]
because the trackers are not linked to our avatar just yet.
So what you're going to do is stretch your arms.
Here's my other controller and you might want to look around
and make sure that your trackers are aligned to your avatar
and then click both triggers.
And now it's clicked in.
Now we can move around.
Although it's a little bit janky, it's not exactly perfect.
These are some things that you might want to set in the Slime VR settings
to fine tune it so that it'll be almost perfect.
However, I don't really have all the time to set it up primarily
because this setup is not actually my real full body tracking setup.
I actually have a real full body tracking setup that is also Slime VR
but by concept, this is one of the funniest ideas I've ever made
(*"made for a vid")
that is technically possible by documentation officially
by Slime VR themselves.
So I'm basically just making a video so people know that,
hey, you can use your phones as trackers if you don't mind
the huge chunky phone on your ankle.
But yeah, I hope you like this fairly weird lackluster video
that somehow needs to take quite long to edit
and put out onto YouTube, I guess.
And oh, by the way, if you move the hip tracker, it works.
But yeah, with that said, I don't know what to tell you.
It's just one of the dumbest videos I have ever made in my life.
But I hope you enjoy this well outside phone tech kind of video
that I have made for the past three videos
and I hope you enjoy this video and be sure to subscribe.
Be sure to press the like button,
be sure to press the bell notification
so that you won't miss my future videos
and be sure to check out my Ko-fi.
Donate me financially so that you can support me
and I'll be able to continue making this crazy videos like that
and hopefully, eventually, I might be able to hire an editor.
Who knows?
We'll never know for now.
But also check out my Discord
if you want to keep in touch with me
and have a good chat about anything tech.
You can also check out my live streams
because I'll be playing some games
and also have some chat yap-e-rinos.
This is where I basically have fun
and do content that I can't really do on video
because it's not really good for the algorithm.
So I do it on the live stream
because sometimes it's a lot more fun to do it
on the live stream than to do it on video.
But you know, you get the gist.
And with that said, thank you all so much for watching.
Oh god, this is such a stupid video.
There's so much things to clean up.
Not to mention the phones I've strapped onto myself.
I gotta take it all down and everything.
But yeah, see you guys next time.
OtsuMelo deshita [It's been your girl Mel].
See ya!
Bop!
Blep Blep Blep Blep Blep.
[Ko-fi] Thank you for supporting me financially!
Member: Jo.
[MeloriTensei 転性メロリ] Thank you for watching!
Check out my other contents!
Ah, the phones!
It's so hot.
The phones are somewhat heating up.