Kon-Melo~
Fuck.
We should probably relocate a lot of this stuff.
It's not getting my face well at all.
That's the funniest part.
Kon-Melo~
Today, what I'm planning to do is
just record a simple trigger test.
Trigger test.
Trigger test with none other than a
really old Razer Seiren microphone
that I have repaired just not long ago.
Fuck's sake.
This table sucks.
So basically, what the Razer Seiren does is…
It has a stereo mode and an omnidirectional mode.
However, it's trying to be a Blue Yeti copycat.
Which honestly, I felt really
cheated when I didn't know about this
and I bought it to the Razer price premium
because the Blue Yeti in today's market price
is half the price of what I
bought this piece of junk at MSRP.
You can tell how pretty pissed I was…
when I learned about the
existence of the Blue Yeti.
However, considering how Razer tried to
be an absolute copycat of the Blue Yeti…
I basically tore this mic down and I looked into
basically the internal components
of this microphone and I found that…
This microphone is more or less
identical to the Blue Yeti.
Just with cheaper quality parts
compared to what the Blue Yeti uses.
It has the same amount of pickups.
It has the same amount of daughterboards, I guess.
I'm not really too sure about that one.
And pretty much, internally, it felt nothing
more than a flat-out Blue Yeti copycat.
Even down to how Blue positions the pickup.
Which is why, when you're listening to the right
side, it felt less direct than the left side.
Because how the right side was being
picked up is not directly on the side.
Hence why they can't really call
stereo "binaural", to say the least.
The left side is directly on the left side.
But the right side has like
a cross-shaped pattern.
That's something you can find
on a Tascam pickup but worse.
This ASMR trigger test serves to be a sample test
for myself and hopefully future
ASMR enjoyers on this channel.
Should I make more ASMR content?
If you've got triggers or roleplay ideas or
anything that I am within my comfort zone doing…
Please let me know in the description…
I mean, fuck.
Please let me know in the comments below.
I would be happy to give it a shot.
This is the first ever setup
where I didn't have to complain
about absurdly loud laptop noises
that sound like fucking jet engines.
So, the only thing I can complain about,
if anything, is my air conditioner.
So, let's get started with
a few basic key triggers.
For monitoring, I'm using the Salnotes Zero:2 IEM.
And I store it in this earphone case,
which is pretty much just
a cheapo TRN earphone case.
Because the moment I bought the
Salnotes Zero:2, I ran out of money.
Regardless, the Salnotes
Zero:2 is an amazing piece.
And it's really, really good
when it comes to budget IEMs.
Special thanks to sonic_idk
for recommending this to me,
and the fellows in the IEM community on Reddit.
And also crinacle for tuning this piece.
It's amazing stuff.
Anyways, let's proceed.
Okay.
I got a pair of barber scissors…
in hopes that I eventually learn how
to trim my hair and style my own hair.
In an environment where I don't have
that many supportive allies in person,
I had to do all this in secret.
Today, the recording time is June 4th.
It's pretty much Pride Month, but…
I don't really do anything
for Pride Month, to be honest.
Aside from just saying, yes, I'm a trans girl
in an unsupportive environment,
that's pretty much it.
With that said, let's get on with the video.
Sometimes, when things start to rain,
and you feel like you're feeling a
little bit sleepy in the background,
you thought to yourself:
"What do I want to sleep to
on top of these rain noises?"
So I thought to myself, let's go to AliExpress
and buy a cheap Kalimba.
Oh, shoot, I missed a note.
I was going to do You Are My
Sunshine, but I'm tone deaf, sadly.
Sorry, not tone deaf.
Just note illiterate.
So the notes I see on my Kalimba,
I don't really know what is what.
You know what?
Let's try doing this by playing
Kalimba in a nonsensical way.
No way.
I just did the ending part for
Can't Help Falling In Love With You.
Holy crap.
No fucking way.
What the fuck was that?
I wonder what song I should play out of this.
Let me know in the comments below.
I'll try practicing a few songs.
And maybe play a few for an ASMR.
To be honest, had I practiced more Kalimba,
it would actually be really therapeutic.
Moving on.
Oh, fuck.
There was plenty of dust in there.
So, I used to major in a university.
And they had a certain assignment where
it needs you to start getting some stuff.
And kind of upsell some stuff for charity.
The profits that we make out
of the upsells goes to charity.
And I happened to contribute to one of
them by just buying one of their products.
And coincidentally, it's none other than just
some custom printed mug that has Bongo Cat on it.
Pretty sturdy, innit?
Now I'm more or less running out of triggers.
Because this video really is done in a whim.
In hopes that I can make videos faster.
So I got extra time to save for a bigger project.
I hope you look forward to those bigger projects.
Because regardless, this video
is still part of an experiment.
for what type of content actually suits me.
But if you do enjoy it, please do
let me know in the comments below.
Regardless, I'm hoping to make probably
some no-talking triggers eventually.
But I need enough sets of triggers to have
an excuse to record a no-talking session.
So if you got a suggestion, please
let me know in the comments below.
It would be greatly appreciated.
If you remember the ASMR that I had,
something about "Senpai catches
up with assignments with you".
There's a point in time where I
actually did a small little headpat.
What I did is basically I wrapped
this microphone with shower cap.
A fabric shower cap.
Because this mic, unlike the Blue Yeti,
if you touch the Blue Yeti on its
own, it may sound very therapeutic.
The problem of the Razer
Seiren is if you touch it,
it feels like scratchy
plastic and metallic noises.
Metallic on the body, plastic on the wind guard.
So if I were to replicate
whatever the Blue Yeti is doing,
I needed that shower cap to
simulate that I put foam on it.
And along with it, I need to make sure
that it doesn't cling onto my hands
because it might make a really awful sound
if it clings onto bits of my peeled-off skin.
So I use a different kind of cloth and
just rub against each other like this.
So now that you know how left and right
sounds like, here's the proper headpat.
Get the picture?
Good.
Now how about some mouth sounds?
I know on YouTube, the TOS for it may
be a little bit on the funny side.
So if you like something
along the lines of licking,
I hope I can do that for you somewhere
else on a different platform.
Probably on a certain popular
audio platform or something.
But if you do want that
anyway, please let me know.
I'm actually looking forward to this.
I'll do what's allowed for the time being.
Mouth clicking sounds or whatever they call it.
Onomatopoeia, I guess I forgot
how to pronounce it actually.
Hilariously I know how to read it,
but I don't know how to
pronounce it or remember it.
I wonder what creates a lot of clicking
sounds like the word "click" itself.
Click, click, click, click, click.
Tick, tock, tick, tock, tick, tock.
Tick, tock, tick, tock.
Maybe a little bit of blowing.
Peter Piper picked a pepper...
A couple of tongue twisters might work.
She sells seashells on the seashore.
バス、爆発。
(Bus, explosions.)
Wait... is that correct? Sorry.
Y'know what? I'll search for it next time.
And finally, we're gonna momentarily close it off
with a simple roast to Razer
For barely innovating completely
brand new products around that time.
At the time of the creation
of the OG Razer Seiren,
the reason why you have not seen this Razer Seiren
that you're seeing on screen right
now on their product page is because
they were really embarrassed by the
criticism that was given to them
from the quality to the insane price premium
that they charge on this very product.
So they basically erased this product
from the face of their own website.
The only last place you get to see
this product is in their support page.
There is only one page for it.
And pretty much almost around that time,
I bought their Razer Blackwidow Chroma V2.
And as much as I enjoyed it around that time...
Once I discovered the world of custom
keyboards, I've never looked back.
However, I do have a piece of memorial
for the dark emo Razer times that I had.
this...
is the Razer Green Switch keychain that
you get on some of the Razer keyboards.
And I pretty much held on to this keychain until…
well, today.
Can you hear the ringing in the springs?
It's insane.
It honestly sounded like
the galvanized square steel.
I don't know.
I genuinely don't know what
galvanized square steel actually is.
I just know that it sounds horrendous.
So that's it.
I hope you enjoyed this ASMR trigger test.
If you do enjoy more of this, or you want
more kinds of different kinds of ASMR,
maybe roleplay or something like that,
please let me know in the comments below,
what do you want to hear out of this microphone?
Possibly a test, or a roleplay, or a
livestream, or anything of the sort.
I'm open to suggestions.
Because I really do enjoy
ASMR as a listener myself.
And I feel like I deeply owe to the ASMR community
for consuming a criminal amount
of ASMR in my entire lifetime.
In fact, just after recording this,
I'm just gonna slap my head on the
pillow and tune in to some ASMR.
Have a good night.