Ayyyy, it's Gamer Socks!
It's not like I like to hear your orders or anything.
Hmph.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Too far.
I don't accept that.
No!
Oh my god, I couldn't see in front of me.
Get out of the waaaaay!
Sorry!
I'm not listening!
Wait, what the?
Wait, what?
What's going on with the bots?
Oh, we got wheelspin.
What are we getting?
Ayyyy, it's Gamer Socks!
We'll drive this car straight to the site.
ANA: In 100 meters, turn right.
Okay, I was a little too far off already.
We're driving a Batmobile.
Or so I thought.
It's not a Batmobile.
Let's take shortcuts.
Wee!
Ah!
In 200 meters, turn right.
Wah!
No.
We're going- we're taking it Horizon style.
Ah!
Sorry!
I find it hilarious that- ah!
Hello!
Oh, that's a wall!
That's a wall, that's a wall.
We gotta find our way in somewhere.
Are we up yet?
Yeah, we are up.
Okay, let's go!
Nope!
You think I'm actually gonna follow you, Anna?
I'm gonna- I'm just building up speed.
It's not like I like to hear your orders or anything.
Hmph!
Ah!
Overshot it.
Alright.
Damn you, Alberto!
Get out of my way!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
too far!
Wha- I'm all the way to back right now?
What the hell?
I'm all the way to back just because I missed the turn.
Oh, shit!
"Hit or miss.
I guess they never miss, huh?"
Oh, that's a dead meme.
And I'm not finishing either.
Please, let the pity system work for me!
Ah!
Dang it, I only- I only got past one guy.
Let's try out- Let's try out the Hot Wheels event.
See how it's like.
See how this is like.
Ooh, it's gonna be a long route.
The Senna is nostalgic, I gotta be honest.
Oh, oh, oh!
We could literally have some like drift montage of this guy.
Ah, calming, relaxing race.
I mean not race, more like just driving.
Nope.
I don't accept that.
No, no.
"The extreme driving ahead."
So basically it's say- It's simply put, it will be nauseating inducing
if the settings were not auto applied.
Woo!
Oh my god, I couldn't see in front of me.
Oh, it's clear as day now.
Here we go.
Oh, here we go.
Oh, so that's the roll indicator.
I get it now.
What happens if I'm in the-
What?
What, the cockpit is a little-
I don't know what I'm feeling about this.
It feels weirdly slow
from a first person standpoint.
But then it looks fast when we get into the far camera.
Get out of the way!
Sorry!
Okay, now we're-
Ooh!
Haley: Watch out for the jump! Stay in the middle!
Stay in the middle?
Sorry, I'm not listening.
Woo!
It's the boost.
Speaking of Hot Wheels, I used to play Hot Wheels.
Like, not the video game, but the cars itself.
Except I don't got the track.
Because in where I'm from, tracks weren't sold at all.
So, "weren't" as in before.
But now they do.
So I didn't get to live off of the Hot Wheels childhood.
Ow!
Whoa!
Okay.
Holy frick.
No!
Okay, we're good now.
Wee!
Woo, beautiful, really.
I like the look of this place.
For real.
Ah!
Holy!
What was that?
Ha ha ha!
Holy!
That caught me off guard.
Vamos!
Wee!
Shooosh!
That was sick!
That really was sick.
Holy crap.
Chat: "There's no way she's gonna drill a bank account
to buy the Ultimate Edition."
I did.
I literally did.
I drilled my bank account.
"POV, you're the character from the movie Cars made by Disney."
"Can I talk to you about our lord and savior, Lightning McQueen?"
Ha ha ha!
Gura: Hello, ma'am, do you have a minute to talk about
our Lord and Savior, Lightning McQueen?
Ooh, rewards.
Oh my god, it's a wheel spin.
It's a god dang wheel spin.
Oh my god, I can't see!
ANA: You have arrived at your destination.
Wait, I went past it!
I went past it!
Hold up, hold up, hold up!
So I just have to…
It's a speed trap, isn't it?
Yeah, it's a speed trap.
Okay, gotcha.
Simple goal.
Don't…
Don't hit any walls.
That's the simple goal.
Oy~
Ah, I slid off!
Ow...
Okay, let's go.
Okay, so here's the speed trap.
How much?
Two…
Aw, two stars.
Oh, we're so close!
Okay.
Let's try to wrap some cars.
Let's go…
Let's head off and wrap cars now.
Finally.
We're home.
The first car I want to make it pein [peko].
I want to Itasha it.
This, this Supra.
Download and install.
It's gonna cost me, like, how much?
Couple 10ks?
I can't afford that yet.
Okay, we'll get into the liveries first.
Let's see what anime designs we have.
Oh my god.
I know a certain someone that would like this wrap.
Holy, there's a lot of anime design cars.
You know what?
I'm gonna make her happy.
Because why not?
Let's check out the car horns real quick.
Wedding March?
Halo theme.
That's not surprising.
Minecraft theme?
Oh no.
I was not expecting that at all.
What the heck?
That is hilarious!
Oh, no, I didn't mean to-
Why? Is it because I own Forza Horizon 4?
That you gave me this?
Wait, I have these on my soundboard as well.
Hold on.
I got this.
It's right here.
And this.
Oh, the Windows Tada.
That's like the Windows XP or 95 one.
Yeah, it is!
It is that one.
Oh my god, that's so nostalgic.
Holy crap.
So the only novelty horn I actually have is the Royal Fanfare.
Just because I own Forza Horizon 4 is it.
That's hilarious actually, I gotta be honest.
Let's head on to a normal event again.
That was so goddamn distracting!
But it's fun too!
Holy shit.
Chat Player: "Why am I using the Bad To The Blood?"
Oh!
Oh damn, okay.
Wait, what the?
Wait...what...
What's going on with the bots?
Player Chat: "The game bugged, bro."
Okay, we have to restart this event.
Oh, ayo.
Hopefully it's not glitched, you know.
I'm gonna drive it safe.
Ow.
Play it safe!
No, no, no!
I will not resist!
I mean, I will resist your temptations of overtaking me!
Shit, I couldn't speak English properly!
I couldn't resist the drift in this one.
No, no, Raven, no!
No, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no.
CURSE YOU, PERRY THE PLATYPUS!
Hahahaha!
Thank you.
Hahaha!
We can do this, we can do this.
No!
Damn it!
I'm carrying 100 points at least!
Phew.
Tanoshikatta [That was fun]!
Thank you all so much for watching.
Be sure to subscribe.
And be sure to hit the notification bell.
Hit the like button so that the algorithm knows
that my videos are pretty awesome.
I mean, my streams are pretty awesome as well.
God damn it, you!
And I'll see you guys next time!
See ya!
OtsuMelo deshita (It's been ya girl Mel)!
Goodbye!