Hey, Kon-Melo, Kon-Melo, Kon-Melo.
It's ya Tech Wizardess girl, MeloriTensei!
Melori Valentine desu~!
Right, let's go through some stuff
because here's an important note for people
who have been in the Half-Life,
as in Half-Life, like, universe as a whole.
The keyword is: I have not touched anything about Half-Life,
so Half-Life Alyx became my introductory instead.
So I may not know about anything about the Half-Life lore altogether,
so hopefully you guys would be patient with me.
So we're at Half-Life Alyx now
and I have never really, really played Half-Life Alyx before
and I don't know anything about Half-Life as a whole.
I only know that Half-Life is just...
it was an engine to me,
(Meme: STOP FUCKING WITH THE MICROWAVE!)
but I didn't know about the whole main game lore.
I know the existence of Gordon Freeman at least,
I hope that's bearable with some people,
but with that said, let's just get straight to it.
Let's start.
Movement - blink.
No, I like Continuous Movement.
Weapon hand - I'll have it on the right hand for now
because even though I'm left-handed,
there's plenty of stuff that I do with my left (*right) hand.
Let's try playing at normal difficulty.
Let's see how hard can it be.
I mean, just like Clarkson says, "how hard can it be?".
So let's get straight to it.
This is my completely raw experience,
so I don't know what to expect at all.
Like this is going to be the rawest of raw experience to me.
Oh my god, the loading times are quite long, don't you think?
Ooo, okay, here we go.
It is five years before the collapse of the Citadel
and the end of Eli Vance.
Subject: Alyx Vance.
Age 19, female.
Affiliation: Human resistance
Current Assignment: Reconnaissance
How do I move in this?
Or am I not supposed to?
Presumably I'm not supposed to, yet.
"Push to move."
Oh, oh, oh, we're finally told to move.
Let's go.
Can I not..?
Can I touchy?
Let me try touchy.
Can I tap that?
Can I...?
Oh?
Anything here?
Nada.
That's fucking useless.
Yeet!
Wait, can I open this? Hold on.
Oh, oh, fuck.
Wait, what's, what's my thumb doing?
My thumb's doing something funny.
My thumb is doing the funny.
Look at that.
My thumb's doing the funny.
I wonder what happens if I chuck it at some flyby airplanes or something.
Oh, a pigeon.
God damn it.
Felt eraser.
Multi-purpose.
Wait...
Oh, this is the drawing board itself.
Oh, it actually erases.
Oh, hey, a mug.
What's inside?
Nothing?
Ah, what a morning.
What a morning in the United Kingdom.
(Imitating slicing noises)
Let's receive a call.
Whoever this is.
Eli: Alyx! How's it looking up there?
Eli: What is it, Russell?
Alyx: What'd you?
Alyx: Terrific.
Okay, wait, can we call him back?
No?
Attention, citizens, you are about to be completely dictated
and ruled by yours truly.
(Grunting)
Oh, that was heavy.
Plug.
Oh, trophy.
Touchy, touchy.
Light switches.
Woah, блядь (fuck)!
Woah, what the fuck?
Oy, what the fuck, who dat?
Dang, I should have threw that bucket at him.
Здравствуйте (Hello)?
Uwah! Блядь (fuck)!
Okay, hello.
So are we supposed to...
"not coffee".
Oh, it's the feed for the bug.
Here you go.
(Steam notification)
I got an achievement to feed the pet.
So how much am I supposed to feed?
Oh, can I carry him?
No, I can't. Okay.
It's time to do some cleaning.
What if we go to other floors?
It won't work there.
Won't work here...
It won't work here.
Unknown person: Alyx.
Bonjour (Hello)?
Come on, give me some time.
What's up?
Alyx: Yep, they got the reactor, easy peasy.
Alyx: I'm headed back to the safehouse right now to meet dad.
(Sirens blaring)
Alyx: Go! We'll be in touch.
Unknown person: Stay safe.
Unknown person: Alyx, over here!
Alyx: What is it?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown person: This doesn't seem like a routine sweep.
Unknown person: Are you sure everything went okay?
Alyx: One hundred percent.
Combine: Come on through.
Unknown person: Something's got the CPs riled up.
Alyx: Keep your head down and be smart.
(Something caused the game to freeze, more into this soon)
Is everyone okay?
Combine: You. Get in the van.
Combine: We got 'em.
Huh?
Who's that?
Why were you looking at me weird?
What the fuck?
Are you all right there?
Are you all right, man?
There we go.
Combine: Behind you! Hands up! Don't move!
Alyx: Whoa whoa whoa whoa, wait wait wait!
I just... I just live here!
Combine: Probable Anti-Citizen.
Get those hands up! Get a scan.
Alyx: Wait w-wait wait. Don't shoot!
Combine: Area secure.
Combine: Bring him in.
Holy shit.
Combine: She's clean.
Combine: Give us names.
Eli: We didn't steal anything!
(So, I crashed right here.)
(The PC at the time of stream was facing a series of fatal issues,
this crash was one of them.)
(I recommend checking out my latest Devlog vid
for more context regarding my PC.)
(Apologies for the inconvenience.
Let's return to the regular programming.)
Quack!
I think we're back.
Combine: What is that?
INCOMING!
What?
Combine: GRENADE!
Get it!
I don't see it!
It's under the seat!
I'm looking, I'm looking!
Combine: Get it, get it, get it!
I got it!
Throw it, throw it-
I'm throwing it n-
Holy.
Drone: YOU-HAVE-BEEN-IN-AN-ACCIDENT.
Drone: TAKE-THE-HEADSET.
Huh?
What's in here?
Russell: Alyx! You there? You-You've got to get moving.
Alyx: Russell? I've been in an accident.
Russell: I know! I caused it!
Alyx: Wait. Where's dad?
Russell: He's fine. Follow the drone.
Oh?
Alyx: Do we know where they're takign him?
Russell: Criminal holding.
Russell: And then when they realize he's Eli Vance…
to Nova Prospekt.
Russell: But I'm already waiting on a plan to get him back.
Mel: Can I just... wait...
Russell: You're close to my lab.
Jump indicator?
I'm trying to understand.
What in the world do they mean by jumping indicator?
Oh, okay.
That's what you're supposed to be doing.
Okay, I get it now.
Oh, scheiße (shit)!
Fuck.
Russell: Alyx, everything cut out for a second!
I lost the headset video feed. Can you see my drone? Is it okay?
Alyx: Uh, sure. Yeah. I'll be there in a minute.
What the fuck is this?
Russell: Alyx, great. Okay, let's - wait. My drone's okay, right?
Mel: Nope.
Alyx: Nope. It exploded. I'm fine, by the way.
Russell: But. The good news is, we've got something they dont.
Alyx: Which is...?
Russell: My plan to get him back!
Alyx: Great. Let's hear it.
Russell: Now. Pretty soon they're gonna realize
that your dad is not gonna talk.
Russell: And when THAT happens, he's off
to have his brain sucked out.
Alyx: Russell.
Russell: Potentially.
Russell: Maybe not, though. I mean, he could-
they could -
they could just drill into his-
Alyx: Stop.
Russell: Oh, yep. Still your dad.
Russell: Well, what they WILL do is take him by train from HERE.
Russell: This is Eli... to Nova Prospekt.
Alyx: And if he gets on that train… that's it, right?
So we hijack the train?
Russell: Not necessarily. Grab something that represents us.
Huh.
Russell: Yeah, just grab anything.
"Anything", you say.
This?
Russell: Okay, that's you.
Russell: You take your train, get there before his train,
and hack into the controls.
Russell: That'll let me take over the system.
Train comes to a halt. You deal with the Combine situation.
Russell: And we get your dad back.
Mel: Huh.
Alyx: Sounds good. Where's the train I'm taking?
Russell: Out the back, through the yard.
It's decommissioned, but I think I can hack into it's controls.
Russell: Oh. And get yourself a pair of "Russells" on the way out.
Huh?
Alyx: "Russells"?
Russell: The gloves, Alyx. You know, the gravity gloves.
I have a few sets through there.
Russell: You can calibrate them out by the shed.
Alyx: Got it.
Russell: We can do this, Alyx.
Mel: Huh?
Russell: You got that, didn't you? That I said we could do it?
'Cause we're gonna do it.
Alyx: Yeah, we are.
Russell: I'm with you every step of the way.
Woah.
Okay.
All right.
I don't know how I'm supposed to be walking out, but you know.
(Glass smashed)
What did I do?
Russell: Aim at something with your hand open.
Russell (semi muted): Yep, you're tethered. Make a grip.
Russell: You've got it. Just a little flick of the wrist.
Catch it.
Whoa.
Russell: Boom, yep. Try again.
I almost froze the game.
Russell: That's it. We're done.
Russell: Ooh! Oh, wait! I-I almost forgot.
Russell: Alyx! Up here! You're gonna need a gun!
Russell: Don't worry, it's unloaded!
(Gun shot windshield)
Russell: It's unloaded now!
Really??
Russell: Oh. Almost forgot, guns need ammo.
Russell: Here you go!
(Steam achievement)
"Catch Russell's guns ammo before he hits the ground."
Oh, that's an achievement?
No fucking way.
(Gun shot)
Russell: Oh, you uh, took care of that lock, then. Good. Great.
(So, I crashed again. I swear it won't happen again)
Russell: (I) Did have the key for it.
But should've given you that, that's...
that's on me.
Russell: Hello, Alyx? We MIGHT have a problem. Probably
nothing to worry about, but-
What is it?
Russell: Did the train stop? It stopped, didn't it.
Alyx: Yeah, what happened?
Russell: Ugh, it's jammed. When the Combine shut down
the Quarantine Zone, they might have tightened security.
Wurgh...
Who the fuck is that?
Alyx: I got a dead zombie here. I-I though the Combine sealed up the QZ?
Russell: Ah, this one must've squirted out. I heard they've had
trouble with barnacle spores outside the containment area.
Russell: But not about fellas like this.
Russell: Ahh... Would you look at that. Resin.
And if there's resin around here,
there should be a Combine fabricator.
Russell: Keep an eye out,
we might be able to upgrade your firepower a bit.
Oh, um...
"Use the multi-tool on the power source."
Alyx: Huh, I think I can reroute this with my multi-tool.
Russell: Your what?
Alyx: It's a tool with multiple functions. So, you know - multi-tool.
I don't get it.
Oh, we stick the gun in or something?
No?
Oh, wait, it's right here.
Oh, it's a puzzle, innit?
Oh.
Okay, okay, I see.
So we're- so we're gonna-
Russell: Alyx, that thing's incredible!
You need an incredible brand name!
Mel: Ooh.
Russell: Something that really sells it!
Alyx: Who am I gonna sell it to?
Russell: The Combine's not going to be here forever.
You should be thinking about the future, Alyx!
Alyx: Well, how about I call it the "Alyx"?
Russell: Hmm. It's a little derivative of the "Russells", but yeah...
Provisionally, sure, the "Alyx".
Alyx: Yeah, the "Alyx".
Russell: Oh! A health station.
Alyx: Russell... the Combine use these. Are they safe for people
Russell: Yeah, they're great. Look, honestly.
Just pull the handle and put your hand in there.
Alyx: Hey... you were right. These are great.
So they squish these headcrabs to heal.
Can I try again?
That's it.
They look fine.
"Pick up heavy objects with both hands."
Russell: Careful of that barnacle, Alyx.
Oah.
That's a barnacle, huh?
Ew.
Ew, they're fucking gross.
So, we were up there.
Russell: Yeah, yeah, that's where they keep it.
Alyx: I'lllook around for a control panel to open it up.
Oh, are we supposed to climb in there?
Ugh.
He's- he's fucking awake!
Right? No?
Just to be safe.
Yep.
He's fucking dead.
Push and hold...
...while moving.
Okay.
But I think it'll be better if we can push him out.
Fuck... off!
Just in case.
Oh hey, control panel.
Ooh.
I expect it to have a screen.
Yep.
That's a screen, alright.
Now we just have to power it up.
I assume.
So we're supposed to navigate our way to-
There we go.
Stay there.
No!
Stay right there.
Oh, that's what it needs!
Like that.
Just a little- there we go.
Okay.
Ooh.
Alright.
Awh, what the fuck?
What in the fuck are these?
Oh!
Alyx: Oh boy.
Russell: Yeah. That's... That's the way we gotta go.
Mel: That's a zombie.
Alyx: No shortcut?
Russell: Yeah, that IS the shortcut.
Hopefully, no Combine is in the way.
Can you be dead for once?
Russell: Alright, that seems to work. Let's keep doing that.
It would be nice if we could wear it on.
Oh, we can! Holy!
That's so cool!
Oh, oh right.
I do not bode well with horror games, honestly, game.
Whoever I was speaking to.
Oh!
Jeez.
When are you gonna be dead?
Fuck's sake!
Russell: I think that's a Combine fabricator.
Russell: Put something in it. I want to see how this thing works.
Alyx: Got it.
Ooooh.
We get it close enough and all points meet. There we go.
Okay?
Put the gun in the cradle.
Alyx: Enh, I don't have enough resin for any of this stuff.
Russell: Ah, well you know what they say about resin, Alyx.
Alyx: No. What do they say about resin, Russ?
Russell: Um. "Look... for... m-more resin".
Alyx: Ohhh-kay. I'll keep an eye out.
Russell: Yeah, that's the one... "Look for more resin".
There's three shots.
Never mind, he's agro-ed.
That's bad.
We really should have used it.
Shut that door.
No, fuck's sake!
Okay, keep running.
No, that's even worse!
We got another one!
Quickly!
I don't got anything!
Run, run, run, run, run, run, run.
Run while we can.
Did it work?
Oh my god, we're THAT low in health?
No freaking way!
Okay.
Hopefully no more zombies.
'cause...
I'm genuinely out of ammo.
Am I just really screwed for once?
No, that's a fucking resin!
This guy!
Fuck!
Oh.
What…
is that?
It looks quite like there's a strong presence of something in here.
Alyx: Russell, are you seeing this?
Russell: Ah, possibly. Are you seeing floating garbage?
Alyx: It looks like it's just... cardboard.
Russell: Right. Well, seems harmless.
Alyx: Yeah. Weird, though.
Huh...
Mel: Whoa.
Alyx: What IS that?
It's like a cult.
I wonder what does it do?
Okay, so we need to press the right combination. Gotcha.
There should only be one box
that has three (*two) of the combinations, right?
Is there anything I'm missing here?
Wait.
Is it trying to tell us something?
Is it trying to tell us that these two are the keys itself?
Just two buttons.
Is that it?
Because I can see two lights, so that means…
this…
and…
this. (gasp)
Mel: All right.
Overwatch: Attention please. Access is not permitted.
Overwatch: Anti-citizen scavenging will result
in immediate capital prosecution.
Russell: Alyx! You alright? What's wrong?
Alyx: I'm fine, Russell, what's up?
Russell: I'm losing your signal! Alyx? Alyx?
Russell: If you can still hear me, keep heading in the same direction,
and-and try to get above ground!
Alyx: Russell? Russell?
Alyx: Whoa, this is weird.
This is definitely weird.
Oh, is this their entry point?
Alyx: Oh.
Vortigaunt: The Alyx Vance!
Mel: Ah.
Vortigaunt: You received my messages!
Alyx: I did?
Mel: Huh.
Vortigaunt: Come! Enter.
Alyx: Okay...
Alyx: Thanks.
Vortigaunt: You are welcome!
Alyx: So, what's a Vortigaunt doing here?
Vortigaunt: (sniffs) Mmm!
Mel: Uoh.
Vortigaunt: Cooking!
Alyx: Right, but I mean in general.
Vortigaunt: I have a brain injury.
Alyx: Oh. I'm sorry to-
Vortigaunt: My brain is injured!
Alyx: That's terrible, and I hope-
Vortigaunt: Ow.
Alyx: Look, I'm actually pretty busy looking for my father...
Alyx: ...Eli Vance...
Vortigaunt: The… Eli Vance! Yes.
Alyx: The Combine have him, and I really do need to get moving.
Vortigaunt: The Combine. Yes. Do not go yet!
I must show you something!
Alyx: Look, I appreciate-
Vortigaunt: This way!
Alyx: I can't stick around, I-
Vortigaunt: It is important!
Alyx: I'm sure it is, but-
Vortigaunt: The Alyx Vance must go this way anyway…
Alyx: Okay.
Mel: (sigh)
Oh.
So he's the magic…
sorcerer.
Vortigaunt: The Combine have other of my kin.
So I assume these cardboards are rebuilt of these guys then.
Vortigaunt: Held, like the Eli Vance.
Vortigaunt: The Alyx Vance will free them!
Alyx: I would help. I really would.
Mel: He's trying to tell a story.
Alyx: But the Alyx Vance is honestly very busy saving her Dad.
Vortigaunt: You will not save him. He is dead.
Alyx: What?
Vortigaunt: Or he will be...
Alyx: Is? Or will be?
Vortigaunt: It is a matter of perspective.
But Alyx Vance alone cannot prevent his fate.
Alyx: I- Look. Thank you for... everything. But I really have to go.
Alyx: And I'm sorry, but I really don't have time for riddles.
Vortigaunt: No riddles! The Combine drilled here.
I do not know when I am.
I am severed from the Vortessence. I am alone in my head.
Alyx: I'm sorry. Look, if I can, if I run across your friends, I will see what I can do.
Vortigaunt: You have saved my kin!
Alyx: I... havent.
Vortigaunt: Then you will.
Vortigaunt: Rraaagh!
Vortigaunt: Courage, Alyx Vance!
Thank you.
Vortigaunt: I will help the Alyx Vance! Look to the Northern Star.
Alyx: Why?
Vortigaunt: For guidance!
Alyx: Okay. Thanks. Are you done? Helping?
Vortigaunt: I am not! Here. Sustenance!
Alyx: Uh... I'll eat it later. Thanks for the help.
Vortigaunt: You will be welcome.
I'm even more impressed that this guy…
this gentleman's a lot more friendly than I thought.
Russell: Alyx! Alyx! The signal's back! Can you hear me? Are you okay?
Alyx: Russell! I'm good! How's Dad?
Russell: They've got him on the train. He's on the move.
Russell: You gotta find Fairview Junction before they get there.
Alyx: I'm working on it.
Russell: So anything happen when you cut out?
Alyx: You're not gonna believe this, but I ran into a Vortigaunt.
Russell: A Vortigaunt? What was he doing down there?
Alyx: Hiding. I think he escaped from the Combine.
Russell: W-what did he say?
Alyx: You ever meet a Vortigaunt? He said crazy Vortigaunt stuff.
Heh, okay.
Perfect.
I wish we had a more of a melee weapon that we can use.
Let's go.
'kay, that opens it instantenously.
Alyx: Oh, that Vortigaunt I met? He did give me a headcrab to eat.
Russell: Oh! Great! What did it taste like? Tell me how you f-
Alyx: Russell. Russell- I didn't eat it.
Russell: Right. Of course you didn't.
No, that's... that's the right decision.
Yeah...
We're not the same species to begin with.
Alyx: Oh! That zombie has a shotgun!
Mel: (heave)
Alyx: Come on...
Wait...
Oh, shotgun pellets.
Why is it clinging onto him to begin with. What the heck?
Just to be safe...
Ow...
Fuck.
Alright.
Idiot Mel tries to (not) get the shotgun for 10 minutes gay.
It's not like we can…
Are you serious, game?
It wasn't… It didn't allow me to do that earlier.
So, we wedge it in there...
So in theory…
There.
Now, we don't need to use the gravity gun
because we can just reach it for it.
Perfect.
"Open shotgun."
"Pull slider."
Oh, there you are.
Russell: I love this gun.
How much do we have?
Ooh.
Screw it. We'll make good use of it.
So, there's gonna be a machine and this guy.
Oh, more of you!
Uwah!
Fuck!
Phew.
Oh.
Did you see that?
Hol' up.
Oh, so that's what that was for.
The thing I threw away and…
Awh, we can't use it because we don't got the thingy.
Awh, fuck.
We should've carried one with us.
There we go.
Wonderful.
We've unlocked it.
Huh, neat.
I would love to upgrade the shotgun
but we're that low on ammo so…
Don't think that's gonna be feasible for me.
"Reflex sight. Adds a display that highlights tactical targets."
No.
Maybe shotgun?
What's for the shotgun?
"Laser sight. Adds laser projector for better targeting."
Oh?
Oh, they stack.
That's interesting.
Oh, neat.
Russell: Oh! That should come in handy.
Oops.
All right.
We'll progress from here on the next stream.
All right, with that said.
Thank you so much for watching.
Be sure to subscribe.
And this is my first time trying out a completely different game so…
I hope you genuinely enjoy what I do.
I kind of want to span out and try as many variety games as I can.
Be it VR games, computer games,
like any sorts of games that I can imagine.
So if you got any suggestions for any other games,
please let me know.
Because I would look forward to trying it.
Check out my Patreon [*Ko-fi].
That's another way to support me.
And I also do have my personal commentary,
like what's been going on with me and stuff like that.
I don't really like talking about it
on the community posts or on Bluesky.
So I usually like talking about it on Patreon [*Ko-fi] instead.
So this is where I would be getting really down to earth
and honest about myself.
And also be check on my Discord
because that too is another way I get a little bit down to earth.
But less concise and just more short things here and there.
With that said, thank you so much for watching.
It's ya girl, Melori.
And I'll bid you a farewell.
Otsu-Melo deshita.
See ya!
[Ko-fi] Thank you for supporting me financially!
Supporters: Jo
[MeloriTensei]
Thank you for watching!
Check out my other videos!
(Gunshot)
Really?!