It was a midnight,
all quiet and calm, with nothing but just the computer running.
I figured, it would be the right time for me to work on my model.
I sat down, opened Unity on the project I've been updating my model with.
As you may know, hairs and skirts are among the things that have physics,
and it is always up to the model rigger to make sure they work as intended.
So that day, I was planning a work on improving on those.
Thus, I do a series around checks,
by getting into play mode, and moving my body parts.
Hair looks good,
skirt looks good, until I move the leg up.
I figured it was just a one off, so I wanted to double check with both legs.
The skirt was flaring up.
This is where I got confused.
Thus I got onto Google.
Frustratingly, with no definitive info about it,
I spent weeks upon weeks of research,
until I stumbled upon this Twitter thread, in only Japanese.
It explained everything I need to know.
I couldn't find any useful articles
on skirt collission measures for VRM Spring Bone,
so I would like to summarize my findings so far in my own way.
VRM Spring Bone in comparison to Dynamic Bone:
- The direction of the bone's motion will not be fixed/constant.
The size of radius cannot be changed individually
(The size within the same size group is always constant).
However, since there is currently no means
to solve these problems at mass.
I chose to "brute force" my way to find out.
However, for the aforementioned points,
if the collider is simply placed along the mesh shape of the legs,
the radius [of the skirt] will spill out
along the spherical surface of the collider.
so, let's add one more row (or more) colliders
inside the foot placed along the legs.
That way, the skirt [colliding] radius will be pushed out by the "board,
so there will be less spills than with just a "sphere".
In this case, each collider should be small,
and the accuracy can be improved
by arranging many colliders in a row.
The main reason "why" the colliders are placed "on the inside"
is that if they are placed on the outside,
they will interfere with the skirt when you're standing still
They also brought up a tool in booth that automates the whole process,
but we'll get to that later.
If the hit radius is a bit too large,
and it sticks out a bit due to its interactions with the collider,
adjust the settings by adjusting the Gravity value, etc.
to make the behavior more natural.
VRM is a standard that shows the design concept
"specialized for standing figures"
when viewing in official applications such as VRoid.
However, in recent years, third party apps
have appeared one after another,
and there are more and more situations
where intense motion is needed.
I would like to conclude this thread
with my sincere hope that major action will be taken as soon as possible.
We may still be in the process of researching,
but we believe that the demand to create VRM avatars
from non-VRoid application will increase in the future,
and we hope that this will be of help to those people.
Now, if you don't understand much of it, bones are the points A to B
that determines how an object morphs.
Whereas colliders determine how it should touch each other,
and not pass straight through.
But in VRM's case, it is usually only a sphere.
With the two in play, becomes something that gives us the visual representation
of an object is touching another.
With that, I checked how the colliders between my legs and skirt…
Uh…
Yeah…
Something's gotta be done about that.
Considering this being a model issue for me,
and others who have generated their models in Vroid,
we have to take that to Blender to fix it.
Now, if you didn't understand what that was,
the starting point of the bones are a little too low to allow the skirts
to properly work when the legs move at an extreme angle,
such as squatting and sitting.
To fix the skirt rigging, I recommend you to check out
Pierrick and Kana Fuyuko's skirt rigging guide in Blender.
But to put simply, I'm gonna summarize what I've done here.
Separate the dress, clean up unnecessary vertices and bones,
make sure they're symmetrical, if your model has two layers of skirt, join the vertices,
create new sets of bones and rig them and weight paint them,
rejoin the skirt back to the model, test them out, and then finally export it.
Now that we're through this part, let me hand this off to LiveMel.
Thank you, VoiceOverMel!
Right, so we have imported the package of UniVRM,
and I've also imported two different versions of my models,
so I can show you how it actually makes a difference.
Right, for this first phase, we're gonna do it the wrong way.
So have we not re-rigged the model,
this is how it's going to look like.
So now that we've put it in, you can see that the line starts here instead of up here,
and there is a couple of colliders only on the thigh region, as you can see.
If we do it as it is, if we leave it as it is, and we try compiling this,
we're gonna have the exact same result as what we saw from the very beginning of this video.
So we go down to hips, upper leg, and move it up, you can see that it's flaring up.
Well, to explain what happened, this is what happened.
If you look into this branch of this leg that we just pulled up,
you can see that the skirt bones are under it,
so that means when we rotate the leg, the skirt's following suit.
Well, technically, you could just ask yourself,
Oh, gee Mel, why couldn't you just take these things and throw it to the hips?
So if we do that, when we move the leg up,
you can see that the skirt's phasing through.
That's because if we look into the secondary,
which is where all the colliders for objects go,
you can see that if we just look from the front,
that the bone completely phase right through the colliders of it,
and then the collider ball just misses it barely,
as you can see, like this, this barely, this amount of barely.
Like if we click on the character, you can see it barely misses through it.
And you may ask yourself, we could just increase the size of these balls.
Sure, we can.
So we go up to the skirt section, and then we raise the radius like this.
But this could result in this, this thing flying out of control.
That's because the starting point is under, I mean, I wouldn't say under,
but right on where the thigh is at.
And the ball is just outside the thigh,
so it's literally interacting side by side with the thigh.
Now, no matter how we do it, no matter how we fix it,
it's going to be really, really hard to fix it if we don't re-reave the skirt.
But I'm still going to show you how to fix that.
So first up, we're gonna create something that I would call the bowl method.
Because if you refer to that Twitter thread earlier,
they say to make it in the plane method.
In my opinion, the plane method could end up just sliding far off.
So I prefer the bowl method so that we can have like,
kind of like if you look from the top,
a bowl-like shape that will contain the bones of the skirt in place.
But that definitely would mean if you move your thighs to the side,
the skirt will follow suit.
But honestly, this is the spring bones limitation.
So that's as far as we can go.
However, it still solves some bit of the problem.
Right, let's begin with one thing.
Since we know that the starting point of the colliders are further down,
we're gonna take down the ones in the top.
We kind of don't need that because there really isn't a point for that.
Let's just remove that.
And then, we create a brand new one for the second, like this.
And then we'll try to copy as much of the parameters as we can, like this.
And then now we create a brand new one that goes to the side, like,
not like that, like this.
And then we just move that forward a little bit,
and then create a new one that is on the other side of that collider.
Like, kind of something like this.
Like, you can grasp the concept.
Something along that concept.
Now, repeat that for a few more layers.
And then after that, you go to secondary.
What you want to do is to go to secondary,
and then assign the leg to those skirt colliders.
Now, this is where another new problem comes up.
Since we've did it with the leg,
that means the entire skirt is going to interact with that bolt.
How do we prevent that?
Well, simple.
You just right-click on the leg, and you create a new child.
An empty GameObject child.
And we call it, say, for example, ForSkirtFrontLeft.
And then, instead of using the upper leg spring bone collider group,
we move this thing to this thing,
and then we take these to the secondary as the collider groups.
However, this can be quite a tedious task,
especially when you need to do a couple of rows for each of the angles,
like, say, front, back, left, and right.
So I'm not really going to do it on this tutorial.
However, I have pre-made one for myself.
This is an example.
So if we go into the legs,
you would see that I have created a dedicated section called upper leg colliders.
Each of them have, say, we have the center one,
and then we have the ones for the sides.
Front, left, front side.
Basically, I've covered this much.
If you look at all the circles together,
so 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, kind of that.
This much angle.
And then we appropriately assigned it to the skirt colliders
according to the bones that it is facing,
so that it only interacts with that set angle.
So we haven't changed anything with the skirt colliders yet,
but we have changed something with the legs.
You can see a little bit of puffing.
That's because I've done colliders on the upper end as well.
So it may have accidentally interacted with it a little bit.
As you can see, something like that.
See?
It kind of touched it a little.
I probably shouldn't have done that.
Right, so let's move a leg up.
You can see that it is still going a little wild.
That's because I got the upper row.
If I have removed the upper row, and like that.
Okay, we've removed most of the top, the upper rows.
Now you can see that on that side, it's no longer puffing.
So now let's move the leg up.
You can see that it is kind of hugging onto it.
This is what I mean by the bowl method.
So you can see like this side and this side is hugging onto this one,
and it's carrying it in a straight line.
So when we're moving it to the sides like this,
it may kind of phase out.
That's primarily because, as you can see,
the starting line is still...
Let's just say this particular row of legs have gone
way too far that it has been pushed out.
But at least you can see the idea of what I meant,
and also what the twitter thread is talking about.
However, I do think that the twitter thread explains it way better than I do.
But do let me know in the comments below
if you think my explanation is sufficient.
Try to improve on the bowl method,
and try to have slightly smaller colliders with more sets of rows.
That way it would make it way more precise for the way skirts are behaving.
But aside from that, this is actually the proper solution to it.
Which honestly, in my opinion, it really does suck.
But because Vroid is quite a restrictive format,
primarily because of its initial purpose,
we can't really do anything about it for now.
With that said, there too exist automated tools that automate this,
such as this tool from Fuji Sunflower.
Right, so I'm gonna demonstrate this tool that I found by Fuji Sunflower.
You can see that as well in the Twitter thread.
And because of this Twitter thread, I actually went in to experiment with it,
to see whether it suits my case.
To use this, make sure that you know which version of VRM that you're using.
Say for example, if your model is in VRM version 0,
please use Auto VRMColliderGroup, the one with the word in group.
Because Fuji Sunflower will provide two files,
one's called AutoVRMCollider and Auto VRMColliderGroup.
The one with the "Group" is for version 0,
and the one without the "Group" is for version 1.
With the package from Fuji Sunflower installed,
let's head on up here, where we have the only item called Auto VRMColliderGroup.
So let's test this out.
And there will be an option for English, so do press that if you speak English.
And this is where you'll be given a whole lot of settings that you can adjust to.
For example, how large the radius you want to be,
and how many colliders you want it per section to be.
And you can also have a preset for that as well.
For example, the radius, would you like a default 1?
Or would you like a multiplier of 2 for that?
And would you like individual fingers for colliders?
And do you like the colliders to be on the right, center, left, or extra?
Okay, while I'm recording, I just figured out what these adjustments actually do.
So these are just categories for where things are.
So say for example, on the left it would be for the left arm, left finger, left leg,
and right for the for the respective.
And center is mostly for the center of the body.
My bad.
Forgive me for the mistake.
Now on to the regular programming.
However, I'm going to do this from the perspective of an idiot like me.
But from my perspective as an idiot,
what I think is that I'm going to clear out all the colliders I've had.
So now we have no colliders on the legs.
And then we automatically add them.
So now there will be a preset collider that the plugin is using.
Which looks relatively okay honestly.
Though it may be a little over over stretching a little bit.
We could adjust that with the preset like this.
Then we just add auto.
However, the 50% is a little bit on the smaller side I gotta be honest.
So I'll switch back to the 100%.
And let's inspect the leg.
Bang on size for the thighs,
but a little bit on the larger side for the lower legs.
I'm not really too sure what Fuji Sunflower is working with.
But yeah.
And then we scroll down and there will be a button for fixes for skirt.
This would add an additional, a few additional colliders in the middle.
That serves kind of like a play method in some way.
So if we press play right now and try to move the leg up.
It looks like it has flew off to the sides.
That's because its play method is only focused on the middle.
And this is also why I've explained why the play method is still a little bit flawed.
Because even if your starting point is above the thighs.
All the other bones down the chain can also fly off to the sides, no matter what.
So this is only best suited if you happen to be, say, sitting I guess.
So if we move this leg up, it would follow suit.
And then it will hug in the middle.
However, it would work as well for skirt with bones that are like side to side as you can see.
As you can see, one of them flew off to the side as well.
So that's not really too good.
Yikes.
Which is why I always encourage the bow method.
Though I haven't really seen anyone use the bow method.
So yeah, your mileage may vary with this particular plugin.
So with the thigh adjusted, we extend one on the left and the right.
And hopefully we could bring up also a back as well.
This would create kind of a pseudo-bowl method that is similar to what I've just done.
And as you can see, the bow method proves to be kind of working.
Though the thigh collider for the auto-generated one may be
a little bit on the slightly larger side so it's not captured in the dead center.
But it kind of does work to some extent.
However, if your upper thigh region has colliders that are a lot bigger,
it could also make this part of the skirt puffed up.
So again, your mileage may vary.
However, if you press the fixed spring bone button,
it expands the bones to pretty much as large as it can
until it barely touches one another to basically make sure
that there's full complete coverage of the bones.
However, I don't really quite recommend it
because it's on the slightly larger side.
And there's this too, which should do the same thing.
Now I've cleaned up my project and imported
VRM's SpringBoneTool and VRM's SkirtTool from NALULUNA.
Now with this particular one, if you want to fix the skirt issue,
you have to have both of the tools imported into this project.
And you have a brand new tab that is called VRM tools.
And there will be three sections of it, which is the SpringBoneTool,
and then the SkirtTool, and then the cleanup tool.
So what does the cleanup tool actually does?
Well, it basically whatever it has done but has left over kind of,
like say for example, it has created a child, like I said previously,
that has been left over and never been used by this thing.
Like say for example, you have removed all the colliders,
then this tool is made to clean it all up.
Whereas what we're going to be focusing right now,
since we're starting from scratch,
is we're going to begin with the SpringBoneTool.
Start with that,
and then let it auto detect your model that is in the project.
And it's going to want you to unpack the prefab first.
So we're going to press that for now,
and then have it auto detect everything.
So everything that has bones that are meant to have colliders are detected.
And then on the bottom page,
there will be load optimal settings and load extreme settings.
However, if we scroll up a tiny bit, since we completely missed that,
you can see that there will be parameters that where you can set
all the colliders for everything you need to know.
Say for your upper chest, for your torso, because this is a two-in-one pack,
so you can take care of colliders relating to your head as well and your hair.
So say for example, if you have issues with
hair going around your body,
you can also take care of those as well.
So we're going to be very focused on the lower body then.
So you can mess around with the parameters,
but I'm going to keep it default for now.
As I've mentioned previously, I am pretty much an idiot.
So we're going to click on load optimal settings.
And it's going to set some default parameters that are suitable for this model.
And then we create the spring bones like this.
So you would see that it has created a huge set of colliders and bones for it.
And everything seems to look fine.
So we can mess around with that a little bit, play around a little bit with that.
But we're not there yet.
But let's just play around so we can understand what we're dealing with.
So as you can clearly see that the colliders are still not yet in any form of method,
like a bowl method or a plane method.
Nada.
None of that.
So that means when we do bring up the leg,
it's going to slide off.
However, with this plugin, you get to see which bones are being interacted with.
So you don't have to click out to your model to be able to see it.
You can do it in real time, which is pretty awesome with this particular plugin.
You can see it as it blinks, which is quite freaking cool.
And you can also have in the play mode,
this plugin window will automatically switch
to something that's like an auto poser.
And it will auto pose for you so you can do some testings like say walking.
And it'll walk on its own and you get to see the result.
And you can make it run as well.
You're gonna make it do some dances with it.
And you get to see the bones in action to see if it's actually behaving correctly.
Though the first two is heavily focused on mostly on the upper body's end.
As you can see, things look pretty good in hindsight.
So I guess we'll just leave it at that for now.
So, let's just stop it right here and let's get back to focus.
So now that we're done with the base spring bones,
we're gonna hop over to the next tool, the SkirtTool.
And now we're gonna need to make it auto detect this model once again
and auto detect all the skirt root bones.
So if you're in a situation like mine
where the SkirtTool literally couldn't find the skirt bones,
that's because it's expecting a certain set of names but it found nothing,
then you'll have to find it yourself.
So in my case, when I rigged the model, I put it in the spine
because I believe that in terms of bone arrangement,
it is more suited to be on the spine than the hips.
So I put it there.
So that means we gotta bring them all here like this.
So we just drag it in.
Boop.
So now we got all the skirt bones in green dots as you can see right here.
It's properly detected now.
So now let's scroll down
and then there will be three sets of recommended settings.
So these three recommended sets of settings
are basically what determines how we should make the colliders behave.
So there will be documentations included in the downloads section
and it will be to the Google Docs.
However, it's in primarily Japanese
and the English documentation they provided is super Google translated.
So I'm gonna try my best with my interpretation of my understanding to explain what it does.
So the first setting is to make it humongous but the interaction is quite negligible.
So basically, despite the huge size, it behaves kind of like a soft push.
So when we press play, the sides may puff up a little bit but that's okay.
That's just the way I rigged my skirt accidentally.
But if we move the leg up, you can see that they're interacting properly.
Almost properly, I would say to some extent.
And then we can kind of move the leg out a little bit.
It may phase out a little bit primarily because that's how I rigged the skirt.
Sadly, if I had rigged a corner one, it would also interact accordingly.
So the more precise you have rigged your skirt, the better.
However, it is doing everything correctly.
It's going up and down rather than hugging it like the bowl method that I did before.
So that's one thing that's interesting.
And when we have it do walking and running, the hands may face some issues.
Primarily because the skirt was puffing up from up here.
But I'm sure I'll be able to solve it through settling some parameters in the skirt too later.
So say for example, if we put it on dance mode,
you can see that the interactions with the leg seems like it's actually doing its job.
Almost.
When I said almost, I mean literally almost.
But it is quite impressive.
It is definitely way better than my own implementation to this.
So once again, like I said in the previous tool,
your mileage may vary, but I do think this particular tool is significantly better.
Right, let's get out of the play mode and let's try out the second settings.
So if we do the second settings and we try to remove all the colliders for now,
and we apply the second settings and we create skirt colliders,
it's going to do this um weirdly angled kind of plane method to some extent.
A plane-ish bowl method.
As you can see by the lines, it looks kind of like that.
So when we press play, this time my top of the skirt didn't puff up.
So that's probably what suits my situation.
And when we move the leg up, you can see that it's actually spreading out correctly.
And say for example if I move my leg to the sides, it may kind of phase out a little bit,
but that's because these bones are interacting with these by accident.
And also I am also bringing the leg up in such an extreme unnatural angle.
But if we do it like in a natural angle,
something like this may happen if we move like that.
That's because of the way I rig my skirt once again.
But yeah, we're gonna reset the pose and have it walk and run.
So as you can see when walking, it looks pretty fine.
The hands are actually pushing the skirt as we walk.
And then when we're running, it's actually interacting properly.
So a little teeny tiny bit of phasing as you can see over there, but it is not as bad.
And then when we have it to dance,
it looks pretty decent.
We're gonna have it move a little more extremely so we can see how things go.
And honestly this would be the best that I would give it,
but I really do think this particular two,
this particular bundle of two is definitely worth the money.
Right, let's get out of the play mode and let's try out the third method.
I haven't really tried the third method, but I would love to try the third method somehow.
Okay, so it's like multiple rows of method number two.
Right, let's see how it's like when we turn it on.
Okay, on the upper end it seems to puff out a little bit, but that's not too bad.
How about walking?
So the same outcome as we faced on preset number one.
So it's kind of like a mix of one and two with one with many rows,
and then two with the smaller collider size I assume.
So what if we have it running?
It's not too bad.
Right, let's get back to T-pose and let's bring up a leg.
So it kind of is puffing up primarily because of the back colliders right here.
So the reason why there's three different collider settings, that's because of that.
So many different rigs may have significantly different scenarios.
So it would be either of the three that would suit your case.
So for my case, it would be the second settings.
But yeah, let's have it dance so we can see if it looks fine anyways.
I know it's already not that good when we put the leg up,
but at least it's kind of worth having a short look to see how it's like.
Well, that's actually not too bad, but still,
there are still a little bit of jankiness going on.
But yeah, we can't really do much.
We gotta work with what VRM has provided us.
So for my case, I would have to clear out the colliders
and set the second settings instead.
So the second settings would be for me instead.
And there you have it!
A fix for the skirt issue!
I hope this solves your issue.
If it does, do press like and subscribe
for more tech videos and stream highlights and gaming videos.
If you do wish to financially support me,
please do check out my Throne and Ko-fi,
preferably through Stripe over PayPal, so I can make videos like this.
With that said, I'd also like to give a special shout out to my biggest sponsor!
Want to make more space for your stuff?
Well, SD Maid SE is here to help!
SD Maid SE is a junk cleaner made by an indie developer named Darken.
Some apps tend to leave leftover files we don't need after we're done using them.
That's where SD Maid SE comes in to help!
Now, you can do that manually, but time is money!
With SD Maid SE, you can automate a good deal of that,
and leave precious times to the things that really matter the most.
Unlike other system junk cleaners,
SD Maid SE does not collect any form of personally identifiable info
that could be sold to scummy data miners for profit.
Nor does it bombard you with a fuckton of ads that waste your time.
Like I said, time is money!
SD Maid SE heavily relies on the generosity of the community to stay alive and going.
App improvements happen with the help and contribution
from the great community in GitHub and Discord.
So if there's any bug with the app, you're never alone!
What are you waiting for?
Get your phone cleaned with SD Maid SE on the Google Play Store or GitHub in the description below.
Oh, maybe I should clean my phone screen too.
With that, thanks to Darken Development
for encouraging me to walk forward in content creation.
Catch you next time!