AirPods.
That's right, in case you were
wondering, I was a former Apple user.
Even though I still use the iPhone 12 Pro Max, the
AirPods is a pretty disappointing device for me.
Because in my personal opinion, it sounds
pretty good, but not for its price.
The only reason why I held on to a pair of AirPods
is primarily because I used to have
issues having earbuds in my ear.
So if you know these kinds of in-ear earphones
that we all currently know and actively use,
I have severe issues getting either
of them into my teeny tiny ear canal
that would just make these earphones slip out,
which is pretty fucking sad for me.
And lucky for me, a pair of AirPods still has
these classic designs that are not in-ear,
which is also why I picked up a pair of
AirPods 3rd gen instead of the AirPods Pro 2.
Now recently, I've ran into a problem.
The AirPods are crackling.
The AirPods made a crackling noise,
and I don't know where it came from.
All I know is that whenever
I play some bassy noises,
it starts making serious level crackling noises.
And since I'm already using my
iPhone as my tracking camera,
there are no other better device that
I can use to illustrate this problem.
Look who's back.
Now if you've seen my previous AOSP video,
you would know that I announced that
I'm going to daily drive
crDroid as my primary firmware.
And ever since then, I've started doing a
lot of tweaking to suit a certain theme.
That's right, it's Ruby Rose from RWBY.
Now you may be wondering to yourself,
why the hell am I using an Android
phone to illustrate the problem?
The truth of the matter is, I don't give a damn.
Or more accurately, I do not
have any other Apple devices.
So to solve this problem, I've
got an AirPods companion app.
And thanks to our great
sponsor at Darken Development
for making my content creation possible.
So if you've heard of my
sponsors for the past two videos,
particularly the Skirt video and the AOSP video,
then you would know that SD
Maid SE is a great junk cleaner.
Now this time, I'd like to
have a little plot twist.
Since we're talking about the AirPods,
I'm going to promote his other app, CAPod instead.
So CAPod is basically Darken's AirPods companion
that you can use alongside your AirPods.
Though because of Apple's limitation, you
can't really do much, but let's be real.
Whatever this app can't do, other apps can't do.
So this means the CarPod app is one of the
best AirPods companion that I've ever seen.
Now let's just start illustrating
this idea real quick.
So I've opened up the lid and
immediately it should show up on screen.
Ey, there we go.
We got the battery information.
We got all that stuff.
There are times where things get a
little bit funny, but that's fine.
As long as you can see your own,
where you can see the left pod and the right
pod are fully charged and the case is 60%.
Well, this number 60% is not necessarily accurate.
Because on my iPhone, it says 69%.
That's primarily because Apple
has done a couple of tomfoolery
that restricts data that can be seen by other
devices that are outside of Apple devices.
So basically anything non-Apple would end
up seeing other stuff or just false numbers,
such as the battery info being one of them.
So I'm sorry, fellow Android fans.
There's nothing much you can do about this.
This affects everyone.
Now getting straight back to the
point, let's take out one of the pods.
We've got the right pod out and we're going
to play a particularly bass heavy audio.
As we play out this horrendously bass heavy audio,
you're going to be able to hear ridiculous
sounds coming out of this thing.
And I'm going to put it near the microphone.
You can clearly tell this
is not the intended effect.
Isn't it ridiculous?
Right, so today's video is going to
be, we're going to crack it open
and find out what's wrong
with these pairs of AirPods.
Oh, did I mention this problem
shows on the other side as well?
So we're probably going to crack
the other side open as well.
Right. With that said, we're going to
shut off this device as usual.
I'm going to move it away, get it out of
sight because we don't need it at the moment.
Enter your little companion, iFixit toolkit.
That's right. I've been the owner of the
iFixit toolkit for a while now.
And when I say a while, I mean
like many, many years actually.
So I figured, let's put it to good use
and see if we can dismantle at least one side
of the AirPods and figure out what went wrong.
Because I hear pretty much exactly
the same issue from both sides.
So I assume this issue is going to be,
if it happens on one side, it should show
up the same on the other side as well.
Now I may be no expert at opening up electronics,
but I have done some bits of research
and you're going to need a spudger
tool and a pry tool of some sort.
And when things get really difficult,
you're going to need some tweezers.
I highly recommend plastic tweezers if possible,
but the iFixit ProTech Toolkit
only includes these sets for me.
I mean, there are more, but these are
the ones that I can work with so far.
So I'm going to try to pry it open.
So according to the guides that I see online,
many of which needed you to
have a vice or a knife tool.
However, in the middle of some nights,
I woke up and I realized
something hectically ridiculous.
If you have sheer muscles and you
squeeze from the bottom and the top,
you would notice that there
is an opening in the middle.
Something that the knife
tool should have gotten into,
but for some reason, mine was cracked open.
So we're going to try to pry it
by sheer force by pressing on it
and get the spudger tool in there.
Oh, oh, did you see that opening?
Did you see that opening?
Did you see it open for a brief second?
Did you see that?
What the fuck?
Holy fucking shit, this is nerve wracking.
We cracked open the AirPods.
Let's see what's inside of it.
So according to a guide, it
says to be extremely careful
because there are ribbon
cables that are nestled inside.
So we're going to go in with extreme caution.
I don't think the direction matters, I
think, as long as you manage to pull it open.
Well, there we go.
We got it open.
And then you can see like there's
a Z-line ribbon cable like that.
So when you pull it open, try
not to pull it all the way
because you can see that
this cable is hyper fragile.
Really really fragile.
So I'm going to start assuming things.
Presumably, right here is the battery
and over this side is the driver.
So that means if we want to figure
out what's wrong with the audio,
we're going to need to get into the
front of the driver, which is right here.
So what we need to do is,
presumably from the sight of it, I can see
some glue looking paste around this thing.
So presumably we'll have to cut through
it or pull it out in some shape or form.
With extreme caution, I'm probably going to
resort to using one of the angle tweezers
to try pull out presumably any of the glue points.
Holy crap, it's really really hard
to work with on a pair of gloves.
Let alone working barehanded, holy.
Oh wait, I'm looking at the wrong side.
Oh wait, I see some sort of opening.
If you can see, somewhere around the opposite
of where the driver is coming out from,
like back here at the back, there is
like a little tiny slit that seems like
you can kind of pry into
without hurting the thing.
So I'm probably going to get this plastic
pry tool to see if I can get into it first.
I'm not, I can't really guarantee success,
but I think we could be able to get
something, some infos out of it.
Okay, this thing is a bit too thick.
We probably need to get a
thinner tool like these tweezers.
Now working with electronics
like these are really fragile
and they tend to break off really
easily, so please please please,
if you don't know what you're doing,
please do not, do not attempt this.
Take it to a professional
and have them do it instead.
Even if they charge you like crazy, it's
often worth it if it's really complex.
Oh, I think I got it in.
I think I pried it.
Oh, wedge it.
Not too hard, just enough to stick it up.
Oh, it's going up, it's going up, it's going up.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, it's going up.
Look at this.
Oh, there we go.
It's coming up.
You seen this?
Right. So, there should be, according to the guide,
another ribbon cable that's
for the skin detection sensor.
Oh, I found it, I found it.
It's along on the same side where it went in.
Where that ribbon cable went in, it's
on the same side coming out that way.
Errgghhhhhh, eggghhhhhh, look at that!
Errrrhhhhhh, what the fuck is this?
What the fuck is this dystopian shit?
Look at this blue stuff right here, what the fuck?
I think a dye just fucking, I think a
die (diode) just fucking melted or something.
Jesus fucking- Errghhhh, eeeerghhhh, eurghhhhhh.
Okay, okay, okay, right.
Let's continue our diagnosis.
There is a piece of foam
thingy looking inside here.
That's what audio people call it, the filter,
which is kind of like, it blocks
objects from entering the thing,
but still allows sound through.
You can kind of see it's really, really thin here.
Let's get the Airpods case to compare.
It's really, really thin, and as you can see,
it's kind of chock full of solid
looking thingies, thingamajigs.
Presumably, it might be my
earwax, I gotta be honest.
I mean, I've used it for four years now, but
I honestly think it could last way longer.
At least we know that the filter is
doing its job, so great props to that.
We're gonna put this aside, and we're gonna
investigate right into the root cause.
Presumably, the audio driver.
And from what I can see,
this is clearly not natural.
So what happened is, um, usually,
usually speaker drivers are
completely covered from all around.
But as you can see, the main
driver in the middle looks intact.
But if you look outside, you see that
there's supposed to be a ring around it?
Yeah, on this curve right here, it
does not exist anymore, it seems.
So what happened is that, presumably, the
crackling noises we've been hearing so far
has been that the main frequency
has been flapping along,
but because of that, the vibration
is passing through these openings,
which causes no audio,
but at the same time, it causes these things to
flap so much that it makes funny crackling noises.
Let's try playing that same audio from
earlier, and see if that's the case.
Let's have a look at the driver
itself, when that happens.
Oh yeah, oh yeah, did you see that?
Did you see that?
The coils came out too.
Everything's coming out.
It's completely out of whack.
If I try to press it down, press it
down to where it's supposed to be,
it's flapping in its space.
And you can hear that this is exactly
what's making the crackling noises.
So that means, in conclusion, what happened
is that the diaphragm of the speaker driver
has completely cracked open that
renders it completely useless.
Though not to worry, I'm going
to, if I do have the money,
I'm planning to pick up some replacement
audio drivers from AliExpress.
It may not be as reliable, but I
think it would be the best for me,
especially after I've been
using it for a long time.
Not to mention, if you actually look at the
service fee for the Apple service centers,
they usually cost, if you have to repair both
sides, almost the cost of a brand new unit.
Isn't that fucking insane that I just
bought this device for so much money
and to replace a speaker driver that
it's going to cost me a brand new unit?
I could have just bought a fucking
new pair of AirPods instead then.
So that point of time, with my money really,
really tight, when I say really, really tight,
I mean like genuinely broke
tight, I went out of my way
and do some research in the audiophile space.
And with my extremely tight
money and a sub $25 goal,
I've picked up a pair of Moondrop Space Travel.
Honestly, the Moondrop Space Travel
is a really nifty pair of earphones,
albeit the mic being really bad,
but they sound really, really good.
They're also my entry point for in-ears because
they have this body that clings into my ears,
similar to how the original AirPods do.
And then you got a bit of silicone in-ears,
which could train my ear canals
to get used to the in-ears.
So this may be a great entry
point for in-ears for me.
Not to mention, I've done a lot of
research and people have said that
the Moondrop Space Travel is the
budget king of its price range.
So after a whole month of using,
I honestly am really, really impressed by its
audio quality for that kind of price range.
I've saved myself eight fucking times the price
of the AirPods unit itself, and I got this.
Isn't that fucking insane?
Yeah, I honestly do think so as well.
I'll probably open up the left
side pair of the AirPods off camera
and I'll tell you the results on screen right
here if I actually do have open it up and see.
But yeah, honestly, I'm really fucking
disgusted by what Apple has done so far.
Apple, you really need to
make your AirPods genuinely repairable
for your own service center people.
I don't care if you don't make
it repairable for third parties.
Make it repairable for your
own people as well, idiots.
Right, with that said, thank you so
much for watching this little vlog
of me yapping away about my pair of
AirPods that I have and regret buying.
And be sure to subscribe for more tech videos
and probably a series of gaming
videos if you're interested in those.
Do let me know what you want to
see from me in the comments below,
and I'll catch you guys next time.
I'm so sorry for that really, really
short video, but I'm really, really eepy.
But I still really want to get through this video
because I really want to get
people to know what's been going on
with my set of electronics
and let my voices heard.
So thank you guys so much for watching.
OtsuMelo deshita (It's been ya girl Mel).
Catch you next time.
Oh, also don't forget to
check out my buddy at CAPod
as well on top of SD Maid SE, which
is what he initially sponsored me for.
CAPod is a really, really neat piece of app,
and I highly recommend you check it
out if you use AirPods on Android.
With that said, catch you guys next time.
See ya, OtsuMelo!