Oh God.
(Clapboard claps)
(Mousemat slaps on the floor)
Fuck.
(Mousemat slaps on the floor again)
God damn it.
[VTuber washes her stinky mousemat]
poopy
Kon-Melo, it's your girl MeloriTensei
and as of recording this video the PC is currently down
and I've sent it to a repair shop for repair
and I'm hoping to see it come back completely recovered
and hopefully, I don't feel as devastated about whatever fatal crash happened
during the Zenless Zone Zero stream, but for now
While the PC's gone,
I decided to do stuff that I had otherwise not been able to do
because I've not been free lately
So, here's one of the things.
(Mousemat flaps while being moved)
Get the fuck over there.
We're cleaning my mouse mat.
To those cheeky little boys out there,
sorry, no feet pics.
I got my tights on. Hehehehe.
However, we're just gonna have a little chill vlog
(Plastic stool clops)
Have a little sit down and just clean away at the mouse mat,
but before we do.
(Bucket lands on mat)
We need a bucket and we gotta get ourselves some soap
(Laundry powder dropping into bucket and onto mousemat)
'right, without further ado, let's get some liquids onto it
so we can start scrubbing away
Maybe we can have a little short talk about this
(Drops scrubber onto mousemat)
(Water sprays into bucket and onto mousemat)
Now to some of you who are wondering
Gee, Mel, you're wearing tights.
Why the hell are you wearing tights in the bathroom?
Well, that's because I fucking like to.
Now on to the second question, why the hell am I wearing gloves?
That's because I fucking want to.
I don't care if I'm gonna need to wash it after this video.
I just like to put them on
because I can't give two flippin fucks about this.
So let's get it soaked in
Ahh~, my gloves are wet. Hehe.
Whatever, we'll get to scrubbing anyway.
Here goes nothing.
(Scrubbing noises)
So I want to start from here going all the way to that side.
I'll probably answer some Q&A's
Well, as I'm in the middle of scrubbing...
(Scrubbing noises)
(Sped up scrubbing noises)
Alright, let's start with the first question
To those who are wondering, what the hell actually happened to the PC,
during the Zenless Zone Zero stream.
So to answer that question, it all started with possibly a hardware error.
But what happened is that the screen kind of just blacked out
(Take note that the Power LED is still on)
but the PC stayed on and I had no idea what's going on
(but the whole PC is off)
because when I got back to check the event viewer,
nothing came up and it kind of got me in the panic
because I don't know what could possibly be a problem.
(More sped up scrubbing)
Eugh...
(Imitating the meme) Brother, eugh... (laugh)
(Even more sped up scrubbing)
Oh my god, the more I scrub towards this side, where my hand is at,
it's getting dirtier and dirtier
Jesus fucking Christ.
I really wished I hadn't waited this crazy long just to scrub my mouse mat.
(Sped up scrubbing again)
I wish you could see the state of this, Jesus Christ.
This is an abomination.
Right. So as I was saying,
so I had no other options that I thought to myself:
"Okay, it's about time
I give the diagnostic work to a third-party technician."
Even if it means breaking my bank once again.
As you may know as a struggling creator,
I don't really have much money and I'm heavily still relying on the donators' money.
So, special thanks to my Ko-fi one-off donators, Mint and Canadian
and also my brand new first-ever Ko-fi member, Jo.
Thank you so so so much for your donations.
If anything, I greatly appreciate your donations.
So on the story about the technician,
I thought to myself "how hard can it be?"
They have plenty of spare parts to try this on
(Sped up scrubbing xN I lost count)
I told the technician the full story about what happened to the PC
and whatever happened prior to it.
The technician told me his estimation
is that this may take extremely long to diagnose.
Considering how this is the second ever rarest case
that this technician shop has ever suffered.
And the shop I have been to is not just any other shop
that is just like in the corner of some alleyways.
It is a shop with a pretty good integrity and really high reputation.
So, considering how they've worked with a whole lot of PCs
and yet this is the second ever most difficult case ever.
I knew I'm gonna be in for such a wild ride for a PC diagnosis like this.
But still I told the technician:
"do whatever it takes and just give me the answer"
I'm not looking for repairs yet because I don't got the money for repairs
But for you viewers, if you're sympathetic for me
and you want to see more pretty good content from me
that's based on what you saw on my previous content.
Feel free to check out my Ko-fi for membership or one-off donations.
Feel free to do any any of the either.
You'd be greatly appreciated because I'll be spending those money
on possibly replacing the parts first so I can hang on to it
and actually do proper content.
So I can make contents that
where you guys can determine whether it's actually worth the money
to actually donate to me in the future.
(Sanic speed scrubbing)
To the fellow existing viewers who have noticed my series of yap-a-thons on Discord,
I hope you don't feel too disturbed by the messages I posted on Discord.
At that time, I was really really on a dark place
because I thought "the PC is dead and it's over", that kind of feeling
because the PC to me is like one of my closest sidekicks ever
and the PC to me is kind of like my entire life to me.
So it was a little bit hard to accept
that the PC really is "sick" and it really has to go to the "hospital".
So, it took me tons of courage to actually take it to get a diagnosis.
So as of filming, it has been days since I sent it.
So, all the best for it, I guess.
(Scrubbing goes brr...)
(Slowly scrubbing in One Direction)
(You're insecure~)
(Slowly scrubbing in one direction)
All right, we've done plenty of scrubbing.
Let's give it a little slap.
(Mousemat plops)
Well, that wasn't as satisfying, isn't it?
(Wringing my gloves)
Ooh, that was soaking.
'Right, let's give it a rinse.
(Sped up rinsing the mousemat)
All right.
(Remaining water dripping onto the mousemat)
(Now on the floor, hah...)
Oh my god, look at how soaked it is.
I can't really show just yet. But...
Right, let's hang it up to dry.
Hey, don't tell me you haven't seen feet before.
You're not a real OG if you haven't seen my skirt video.
(Wringing the mousemat and dripping onto the floor)
Oh, fuck me...
Crazy soaked.
Ah, I'm gonna spend a lot of time trying to clean this up.
Whatever, job done is a job well done.
(Wringing my gloves)
Right, let's get 'er up to dry
and we'll see if it still has any of these disgusting things
on my mouse mat after that.
Let's skip forward to when it's dry.
(Feeling the mousemat)
All right, there we have it.
'right let's get the keyboard over here.
Voilà!
Clean mouse mat.
Don't mind whatever that is. Um...
I got something a little sticky on that.
So I've screwed up.
That's not coming off anytime soon. Ehehehe.
Right, let's get some random sharp object.
Like say my microphone (jack).
(Light scoring on the mousemat)
Check that out.
Absolutely no dirt on the prominent areas like the mouse.
Albeit, there's a little bit wrinkling here, but don't worry about that.
I'll try ironing that out.
But yeah, there we go.
We got a clean set up once more.
Anyways, thank you guys so much for watching.
Be sure to subscribe and be sure to check out all my other videos.
And if you like it, please do financially support me.
I really do need to get back on the video journey
and possibly more live streams and hopefully to continue to entertain you
without having to worry about cash flows and money and stuff.
So with that said I'll see you guys nex-
(Door bell interupts)
Huh, who is that?
I wonder who could that be...
(Ominous music)
(Door opens)
(She's back...)
(I live)
(Thank you all for believing in me)