In this long episode, a Burger will be given
I'M GIVING YOU BURBURGER
A kitchen will descend to chaos
Ting Ting Ting Ting Ting Ting Ting Ting Ting Ting Ting Ting Ting Ting Ting
And everything goes to shit
OH
OH SHIT
HAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHA
Kon-Melo!
This is going to be my first ever non-stream highlight video
Basically, this was recorded on a whim without involving a stream
I got sent a game that caught my attention
that I can't pass off not making a video of
And here's how it went
So I found this game
It's called One Armed Cook
To put it simply
Chicken recommended me One Armed Robber
But then I saw the developer's page
And they happen to have One Armed Cook
Now I'm a kind of big fan of a cook game sometimes
So I thought,
Why not drag Chicken himself along this stupid journey
Chicken: 'Ello
Chicken: Yes. This is One Armed Cook.
Yes
It's basically, well if you've heard of One Armed Robber
Well this is the cooking version for it
Chicken: Yes, looked interesting
Yup
Chicken: So, why not play it?
Yup, let's give it a try
But first
Chicken: C'mon invite me
The stupid part right is that
When I opened this game, there was something that caught my attention
There was a button down here and I clicked on it and
Stupid enough
It's fucking loot boxes
So in my inventory I currently have a coolie hat
Ah yes
One way to truly explain the fact that I'm Asian.
(Stereotypical Asian BGM)
Very nice
Chicken: I had a broccoli hat
Nice
Right
So we're gonna create a multiplayer and we're gonna figure out
how this game goes
Because we've never really played this before
So this is entirely just
hardcore figuring out I guess
Oh wait we haven't select a lo-...
(Mel stutters)
We haven't select a map
Let's start simple, shall we start like
With say hot dogs I guess or burgers or something
Chicken: Ah yes, the "easy" one.
Yeah let's do burgers
Chicken: Why not?
Chicken: Till this day I still don't know how to put a patty in a bun
(Mel giggles)
You just put, literally you just put
Here let me show you
So first things first, according to the tutorial
you're supposed to toast the buns first
So we put them inside
Chicken: nYes
Chicken: Hamburger
Chicken: Cheeseburger
Chicken: That's three hamburgers
Chicken: And a cheese hamburger
Chicken: Holy shit you have a rice hat
Yes I have a rice field
Chicken: Nice.
I have a rice fields hat, yes
Chicken: Nice
Mel & Filthy Frank: Welcome to the rice fields, motherfucker
Chicken: I now know what you mean when you said that.
Yes (Laughs)
You have to take it to the chopping board
Chicken: Wat?
And then you grab the knife and slam at it
Chicken: What???
Yes (laughs)
Chicken: Wow..
(Mel laughs)
Then you take the patties and you just put it on
Literally
Like put it on
And then you close 'er like that
Wait, wait, hold on what kind of burger were they asking for, like...
Chicken: Three normal burgers
Put that on...
Chicken: PLAP!
Put that on
Now we serve it to the customer
Mel & General Ock: Now we serve it to the customer, there you go sir
Can I stack plates?
No I cannot
I have to bring those plates back
I assume we have to wash it
Oh yeah we definitely have to
Hey at least we don't have to use the sponge
(In VRChat, there's a similar cooking game)
We just dip it in the water
(that requires the sponge to clean the plates.)
We got clean plates now
That we can use
I'm surprised it's on without the door open
Oh hello
Bacon cheeseburger
So we need bacons
Let's pre-make some
It's not like it's gonna go cold
There's no mechanics for that right?
(Oven beeps)
Uh
We got some toasty-
Chicken: Oh, it can burn. Damn...
Where's the rat?
Chicken: Welp, not my fault.
Here
I'm giving you burger
It would be fun if we could toast these rats though
Chicken: Bruh, imagine.
Actually what if we do that
Chicken: I mean, you could.
Oh my god
(Mel in disbelief)
Chicken: Is it working?
Yes
It's actually flaming
Nice
What the fuck is that?
Chicken: Ahh yes, firery hot rat.
Chicken: Oh shit. Everything's on fire!
Oh shit, hold on.
Chicken: The bacon's on fire
Chicken: The floor's on fire
Unclean!!
Chicken: UNCLEAN!
(Mel giggles)
SovietWomble: Can you stop washing each other?
Tom: Unclean!
Zeis: Unclean!!!
Zeis: Dirty fucking filthy peasants!
Crisis averted
Don't worry
This loss is negligible
(N*jisanji 2k24)
Also we can check for the orders over here
There's an order list right here
Look at that
(Truck honks twice)
Oh hello
Chicken: Honk honk.
What is this?
I ordered one of each
Oh I see
Hello, Ratatouille.
Oh they (the customers) eat it so fast.
Can I just-...
Chicken: Just a "nom", and they're done.
Oh wow, you just throw it (mouse) in the trash.
Just throw the guy in the trash and he'll disappear
Wait what?
Chicken: waw...
Chicken: Where the buns at?
The bun-
Wait
I'm bringing in the buns but I'm stuck
Okay
Here, bun-
Chicken: Where de buns??
Buns
Did we just chuck this down here?
Oh okay
Chicken: Oh shit, they left.
Waste management
Cheese... cheese...
(James May slams cheese on table)
Mel & James May: Cheese
Ham
Chicken: (imitating James May) Cheese.
Oh there's cheese
We got slices of cheese now
Normal hamburger on the way
Who ordered for that?
Okay
(Plate collides with tap)
Ah dishes
Right
Water
Oh my god
It's going rogue
Chicken: I think we need more buns
Okay
More buns
Right
Ordering that
More buns have arrived
Chicken: Holy shit
(Mel laughs)
Chicken: That did not go as planned
(Truck honks twice)
Open up
Okay
Buns
We're calling optimization
No, don't drive away with my one bun!
Oi
Chicken: lol.
There's one bun inside (giggles)
(Fire alarm beeps)
Uhh...
The buns are flying away
Don't worry about that
Everything's under control.
Everything's under control!
Gotta make sure nothing of a value is lost
Chicken: Oh, trust me. EVERYTHING of value was lost.
What did you order this time?
Oh
Meat.
Chicken: They're all leaving!
Oh shit
Chicken: One star.
(Mel laughs)
Read reviews
"So tasty"
"Fantastic meal"
"Wonderfully flavourful"
"This isn't what I ordered"
"There were rats in the restaurant"
"Really tasty and satisfying"
Chicken: waw...
"Restaurant was dirty"
"Couldn't even order any food
"Waiters too busy"
"Waiters too-
"Didn't take my order"
"I didn't get to order my food"
Wait
(Mel laughs away)
Chicken: Ahh, yes. Very professional.
Very professional indeed (laughs).
Oh my god
You want to try that again
Or do you want to try a different food?
Let's try optimizing the burgers first
Like let's get good at it
Chicken: "Get good at it"
(Mel laughs)
Let's get good at it
Now that we figured out the game plan
We cook all the buns beforehand
Cook everything beforehand
Chicken: Ordering beforehand, heh.
Yeah do everything beforehand
The customer will roll in anytime anyways
Ready these buns...
Okay, these buns are cut.
Cheese are cut
Okay I'm going to get the orders
Uh two normal hamburgers
Let's take care of these first
Okay, let's get the patty.
Patty on
Top bun
Okay burger one coming up
All right next burger
Here you go
Burger
Chicken: Borgar~
Let the cleaning be done
What's the-
What's the other order?
Uh, bacon cheeseburger.
Chicken: Oh, shit. Everything is flying away.
Wait, hold on. How does bacon cheeseburger look like?
Burger and-
Okay, everything then.
So bottom bun
Patty
(French Mel) Bacon~
Cheese
And then
Bu-
Top bun?
Where's the top?
There, there's the top.
Did you order bacon cheeseburger?
Yes, you did.
Very nice
Right what did you-
Uh, two bacon cheeseburgers...
Even if it looks weird it actually-
It may work
Chicken: Yeap
Yep it actually works
Regular hamburger
Oh shit, where's the bottom?
Where's the bottom?
There's more tops than bottoms
Where's the bo- Where's the-
I couldn't find the bottom
Are you tending to normal ham-
Oh yeah bacon cheeseburger then
Right
Chicken: Cheese
James May & Mel: Cheese
There there's the che-
"This isn't what I ordered"
Wait what?
"Cheeseburger, cheeseburger, hamburger" okay.
Who ordered for cheeseburger?
Who's ordering for cheeseburger?
Chicken: "Isn't what you ordered"?
But it's a burger
(imitating French accent) "Incredible food"
I had a random thought
Chicken: Wat?
Do you wanna-
Do you wanna stream Overcooked with me one day?
Chicken: Sure
All right
Who ordered for cheeseburger?
Cheese, cheese, cheese, cheese...
You!
Okay
"Great meal" it says
"Isn't what you ordered"
What do you mean?
Ayy, that's an improvement.
We got two-
We got one extra star
Very nice
Chicken: Horrendous, absolutely horrendous.
Why do they keep saying "it's not what they ordered"
Even though IT IS what they ordered.
I wonder
Chicken: They're scamming me.
(Mel giggles)
All right let's try out-
Let's try out hot dogs
Let's see let's see how-
How hard can it be you know?
Chicken: Who knows?
Hot dogs
Chicken: Henry's hot dogs
Okay
Chicken: Oh, joy...
Chicken: There's no space to move
Scusi
Chicken: It's a clusterfuck.
I don't think this alleyway is meant for two people
I think one's supposed to be working on the waiting
Sausage and a plain hot dog
Chicken: You're a sausage, sir.
What??? You're supposed to chop these hot dogs...
To make up a hot dog
What?
Uhh, plate.
There we go
We got plate
In, in you go.
In you go
Dang it
Does it work though?
Chicken: Yes.
Very nice
As long as it's on the plate,
it's all we need
Sausage and bread
Plain hot dog
Very nice
Chicken: "So tasty~"
Mmm so tasty
Wait
Chicken: Move your fat ass!
There's cheese-
(Stutters) There's mousetraps
We could make good use of these mousetraps
But there's no cheese in the inventory right?
Yeah there's no cheese in the inventory
What's the point?
(Truck honks twice)
Chicken: Honk honk!
Oh, we're out of meat. I see.
I'll get to you
Ah. No, get out of the way!
We don't have space anymore
Bread
Sausage
Sausage and bread
SOSIG
RADAL: SOSIG~
I can look at the orders on the screen here
So that's kind of a good thing
Oh shit
Get out of the way
Oh I'm putting the plates up to the front
So it'll be easier for us later
Chicken: Ahh, yes. Let me just toss the boxes in there
Chicken: Wee~
Okay
Oh my god
Chicken: So far so good, I suppose.
So far so good,
Smooth sailing.
Sausage
(Mel laughs)
Chicken: Hehe, it's flying all over the place.
Chicken: Get your ass off the grill.
Sausage!
Chicken: Bruh, its not even ON the plate.
(Mel laughs)
Welp, I don't know how this is ON the plate*. But it works, I suppose.
(Mel giggles)
Chicken: By some sort of sorcery?
I'm a magician. I'm a wizardess!
Chicken: (Bri'ish accent) "You're a fooking wizard, Harry."
(Bri'ish accent) I'm a wot?
(Pissed Bri'ish) I'm not a fooking wizard, Hagrid.
(Mel laugh)
Chicken: (Bri'ish accent) "You're a fooking wizard."
Reference, if it ain't goddamn obvious enough.
"Hagrid": For God's Sake, Harry. What is with this language?!?!
"Hagrid": You're a fucking wizard!
"Harry": I don't give a fuck, you fat hairy bastard!
"Harry": I'm not a fucking wizard!
What is with the sausage and the sausage and breads?
What the fetch?
What?
Oh shit, no!
No no no, I didn't mean to cut that. (laugh)
I held the knife (laughs)
Did you hear that double slice?
Chicken: I saw that
It went SHING SHING!
Mongral: SHING SHING!
(Mel laughs)
We're gaming
Sausage gaming
(Plates colliding result of a glitch)
Ting ting ting ting ting ting~
Chicken: Nice, a big ass plate and a single sausage.
Hot, hot...
Nope, that's not hot.
That's not dogs.
Now, that's a dog.
(NFL on FOX Theme)
Chicken: Welcome, let me molest your face while you order.
Oh, ohh, yes. Oh, yes~
Chicken: That's a good boy.
You know what I got an idea
Let me just put all the sausages and the bread on one place
Leave the knife over here at the ordering table
So when we need it we could use them
And I'm gonna start cooking here
Is that raw?
(Slip sound)
(laughs) Why did the plate just fell right into my crosshair?
Chicken: Who knows...
Oh?!
Chicken: YOU BURNIN' SOMETHING?!
Don't worry
Crisis averted
Don't worry about the dumpster
It's fine
The dumpster is fine
Chicken: Into the trash you go, rat!
I think it'll work
Ayyyyyyyyyyyyyyyy
Chicken: Eyy, stonks!
Ayyy we got 3 star let's go
Chicken: Three stars! Bro... depressing.
How's the review though?
Incredible food there were rats in the restaurant
What are you supposed
What are we supposed to do?
Okay.
Chicken: Mousetraps everywhere, of course.
I put a mousetrap at the door
How the hell did the rat miss it?
Chicken: 'cause he's smorter than you
(Mel pssh's)
You want to try a different food?
Chicken: Sure
Alright, pizza.
Chicken: Pizza, let's go~
Whoa, okay
So we got pizza plate thingy
Chicken: We got ham, we got cheese*, we got pepperoni.
Okay, that's the ordering place.
This is the front door presum-
Oh my god you're already here
Hello
Nice to meet you
Am I supposed to click something for that?
Oh okay
Mozzarella and diavola
Which is like mozzarella but with "pepeloni".
Chicken: Oh, so you're supposed to put the dough in there.
Brrr...
Then, I guess tomatoes...
Sauce... How do we...?
Do we need a knife or something?
How do we
Is there a can opener that we can use or something?
Oh, it's right here!
We chuck it here and then it just do that
Oh that's hilarious
Then we do that
Every pizza should have a tomato sauce
This is like "Work in a pizza place" but different
Chicken: More chaotic.
Yes. Hehe.
A whole lot more chaotic, actually.
Chicken: Wait, how do you pick up the pizza?
Chicken: Oh, you're supposed to use this paddle.
Yep
Oh wow, how does that work?
Chicken: I can't stick it in. I can't stick it in.
Downwards.
Chicken: I can't stick the dick inside :)
No
How do I stick this...
Hold on, wait wait wait hold on hold on.
Put it, lay it down.
Nani?
Oh oh oh
It worked for a second
Hoo hoo, what are we supposed to do?
Drop it in, I guess?
Wait how do we drop- (laugh)
Chicken: EAT YOUR FUCKING PIZZA! ARGHHH!
How do we drop it in is the question.
Hold on, wait wait, no no no.
I, wait, hold on hold on hold on.
Uh, let go.
(Slips)
Oh.
Chicken: Oh, what the fuck.
Oh shit. (laughs)
Chicken: You... you just thrashed it.
(Mel laughs loudly)
Chicken: Bro...
(Mel continues laughing)
Chicken: We've already cocked it up!
(Mel laughs more)
Chicken: We've already cocked it up...
Chicken: We've reached the point of no return.
(Mel laughs so hard)
(Laughs calming down)
I love this game (laughs).
Also, there's a rat.
Aite, aite aite.
Nay
Off you go
Come on, let me in.
Really?
There's only one can of pizza sauce.
Okay fine
I won't even care then
How are we doing so far?
Chicken: "This isn't what I ordered"
Chicken: Of course, the cheese fucking flew away.
(Mel laughs)
Chicken: Oh my god...
Chicken: We've already failed. Haha ha.
Chicken: Uhh, the mozzarella pizza has uhh... went to hell.
Ascended?
Chicken: It has descended to hell.
Chicken: I think it may have been possessed by the devil.
(Mel pssh's)
Okay, we need cheese.
Shit...
Chicken: Uhh, the pizza's in the shadow realm.
(laughs) Shit...
Really? You don't- the box?
Wow, it-
Chicken: How do you even put it on the plate???
Wow the-
This sucker 180's
Chicken: Why can't we even hold the pizza?
(Mel laughs and raspberries)
Chicken: Oh ho ho ho, I think we need to restart.
(laughs) Yeah, this whole thing is a shit show
We've earned nothing (laughs).
Chicken: Bro...
(Mel continues laughing)
Chicken: We're so bad at this.
I know right
This is gen-
A genuine shit show
One review of "This isn't what I ordered".
Chicken: Reason being: [The cheese flew out of the pizza]
(Mel pssh's)
Chicken: AFTER it was cooked and plated.
(Mel sighs)
My god...
Alright
Chicken: This shows Asians don't know how to make pizza.
(laughs)
Right, let's try it again.
Chicken: What? The pizza one?
Yeah let's see wh-
Chicken: We're going to fail! Trust me.
Chicken: Wow, I've already spilled like... most of the tomato sauce.
(Mel laughs) Okay.
Chicken: So, haha, I think we need more tomato sauce.
More tomato sauce coming up
(Chicken laughs)
Oh shit, there's only like one ladle left inside.
(laughs) Shit...
Oh shit
Chicken: It just barely burned it.
(Mel pssh's)
Chicken: I was just about to take it out and then it burned.
Damn
Chicken: Is this working? No it's not.
Chicken: It got sent to the shadow realm. Nevermind.
(Mel laughs)
Chicken: Everything's going to shit.
Chicken: This is horrendous
This IS horrendous.
Okay
Chicken: How do you even put the pizza on the plate?
I wonder
I keep right clicking and it gets sent to the shadow realm
(Mel laughs)
Chicken: Bruh.
Wait where did it go? Hold on.
Wait, there's this thing...
What does this thing do though?
Chicken: I don't fucking know.
What are we-
What are we supposed to do with the frying pan?
Chicken: Who knows.
But there's no stove.
Except for this
Like hold on
Can we pick up pizzas with this?
No we can't
What is this supposed to do?
Chicken: But you can knock everything off. Haha.
(Mel laughs)
Chicken: Bonk, bonk.
Wait, there's the pizza. Here's that pizza.
I found the pizza
Why can't we just pick up with our hands when it's done cooking?
Cause it's stiff.
Chicken: I don't fucking know.
It's stiff
Chicken: Stiff like my peepee.
(Mel pssh's)
(laughs) What the fuck!
The plate is just flying all over the place
What is going on anymore?
What?
Chicken: I don't know.
Hold on can I just...
Nope
Chicken: I can't even pick up the pizza and put it on the plate
(Mel laughs)
Chicken: That's how bad this is
Oh my god
Chicken: Oh I picked up the tomato sauce.
How???
Chicken: I don't know.
(Mel lols)
My god
We're shuttering our business.
New item unlocked!
Chicken: Bro, the pizza one is broken as fuck.
Let's see what we're getting in the loot box.
Ah yes, sci-fi glasses.
What else?
Hot doggers
Are they shoes?
Tell me they're shoes
Oh my god they are shoes
He heh.
Available items
Let's see what they have...
Oh my god
Chicken: Fish shoes, lets go!
They have balaclavas
(StreetmanTV's Balaclava On The Beach)
Balaclava on the beach
Balaclava on your bitch
(Giggles)
The pizza was genuinely a shit show honestly
Chicken: You can't even put it on the plate
Chicken: It just...
Yeah it's fucking unplayable
Chicken: It just spazzes out and goes to the shadow realm
Jesus
Right let's try-
Let's try Freddy's fried chicken
Chicken: Let's see if we fuck this one up
(Giggles)
Right uh...four piece nugget menu
So that means four nuggets and the fries
So... Fries
Wha-
Come on last one
Cook already
There we go
Four nuggets done
Right... um...
We're supposed to have it on the tray like this
Wait, is it possible for us to dump it out?
Oh yes, we can!
We just right click it
Chicken: Nice!
That's easy
Fries are cooked, so that means we can serve it to this guy
Nice
Okay what's next
Two piece nuggets
30 seconds left
Chicken: I'm making the two piece nuggets
30 seconds left come on
We should pre-made those fries
We should have pre-made those fries honestly
Chicken: I did
Nice
I mean nuggets sorry
Not the fries
You can't move these tray- these plates
Damn...
What is-
Why- why is it so yellow?
Chicken: Who knows, It’s chicken
Is this chicken with gonorrhea or something?
It'll be fine I guess
It'll be fine
Wait, does it work if it's just on the plate?
Yes it does
We don't need to stack those burgers at all
Chicken: Yep
Chicken: We're out of nuggets
Oh shit!
We gotta call for them nuggets
I got- I got a genius idea
Don't even bother using those trays
Just use your hands
Chicken: Lmao
(Fryer beeps twice)
I'm gonna do some cooking
(Fire alarm beeps)
Chicken: Wait what's burning?
Oh shit
Uh... Nuggies
Don't worry about that
The restaurant won't burn if- if- if- if no burning logic exists
Oh I know what these food trays are for now
Chicken: What?
It's for transfer of pre- pre-done stuff
I figured it out now
Chicken: Nice!
Don't distract me
Chicken: What's burning?
Whatever happened here-
I genuinely don't know what's burning
Air is burning
That's all I can tell
"Something's gonna want someone burnt." -Melori, 2024
Chicken: I'm helping
(Laughs)
Ohhh! this is what's burned, okay
Chicken: What?
Nuggie
Chicken: I see.
Chicken: Oh shit
Chicken: Where did it go?
♪ Where did it come from? ♪
♪ Where did it go? ♪
♪ Where did it come from, Cotton-Eyed Joe ♪
razioff (in nugget form): gedagedigedagedo-
Oh a single piece of nuggie
Okay
Chicken: Chicken borgar
Fries~!
Eeghhh
Get out of the way
Damn it
How are we doing is the first question
Not mentally well
Chicken: Oh, we’re probably doing terribly.
(Giggles)
Chicken: I think we’ve lost money
Chicken: heh
We clearly have
Yeah we haven't made burgers either
'cause we're out of burger patties
Wait hold on, did you check the truck?
Chicken: Uh... I haven't taken the stuff from the truck yet
There should be some-
There should be some...
Some patties there that we've ordered
(Steam achievement sound)
Cook 100 ingredients
Cool, game, cool.
Nuggies~!
(Laughs)
Chicken: Owh fuck.
It will be fine
Chicken: All is well, heh
All is well, all is well, all is well!
“Rancho”: However big the problem is,
“Rancho”: Just tell your heart "All is well".
Raju: Hmph.
(Back to ya regular programming)
Chicken: This is already a horrible...
It's a horror show
Chicken: It's a shitshow, that’s what it is.
Yeah, it'll be fine.
It's not like it's gonna explode this whole restaurant
Chicken: ♪ Till the very next day~ ♪
Mel & Chicken & Bryant: ♪ Pom, pom, pom, pom, pom, badam. ♪
This just speeds up cooking you know
This just speeds up cooking
Chicken: I’m sure it does.
Chicken: We need more nuggets
Chicken: We're missing nuggets
Shit
Chicken: Get me more nuggets
We need more people
Chicken: We need more slaves.
Pssh...
Okay I think I think we figured things out
At this point we should by now figure things out
for our next attempt.
Oh, you can click on them, okay.
That's fine
It's fine
Everything's fine...
Chicken: Oh god...
Everything's fine
Let's restart, let's restart.
I think we figured this out
I think we figured it out
Chicken: We figured out how to fuck ourselves over. That’s what we figured out.
(Giggles)
We made a profit of negative hundreds
Okay so,so,so let's figure it out
I mean let's think about the strategy
So what I'm gonna do is we're gonna put some-
We're gonna put those-
Put nuggies in the tray
In the grill thingy or the fryer
Put them put them in the fryer tray first
Then we put them in the fryer
And after that we dump it onto those re-
Those static red red trays that we cannot move
These will be our prep table
Chicken: Nice, all right let's go
Let's go
Right... I'm dropping them nuggies in
Chicken: Chicken burger
Oh shit!
Whatever I'll figure it out later
(Giggles)
There's an oddly specific piece of-
Of patty that's not done
I'm gonna get that done first
Okay what are we short of right now
I need-
Tell me what I need to cook first
Chicken: Ehh, more patties
Patties okay
Oh my god this physics...
Okay, nuggets in
Chicken: Oh, we need more fries
Okay, just drop this baby in first
Oh shoot
Chicken: We need more...
Chicken: ...we need more of everything
Everything?
Chicken: Yes
♪ Anything and everything all the time ♪
Why can't they let us dump from the box straight?
Chicken: Who knows.
Chicken: Nice
Oh that's smooth
That throw was smooth
Chicken: “Served 50 perfect dishes to customers” achievement get.
Nice
Oh my god, please, game, please...
Let's see what are the boxes
I'll chuck these out
I'll get to you later
Anymore? Nothing here.
I'll tend to you later
Chicken: Welp, I found a very efficient way to put the bun, that the burgers in.
What, just throw it onto the tray?
Chicken: Throw the bun on (to the tray)
Chicken: Take a knife, chop it, and then just bring it (to the customer).
Done
Fries and nuggies
Okay
Oh, come on!
(Laughing in panic)
Chicken: Chop
I hit my hand and, at least half of the nuggies that we’re in a tray, went into the trashcan!
Chicken: Well done. You’ve done well, my friend.
(Laughing)
What is with all these
What is with all these accidents with me!
Chicken: Well done my friend
You're welcome
(Laughs)
At least we got a spare box which is a good thing
Chicken: Wait, where's the knife...?
(Laughs)
Chicken: The knife is missing
Chicken: Can we order a knife?
(Laughs)
No
Chicken: Owh, I found it.
Chicken: Fries, patties, holy shit. Everything went flying!
(Laughs)
Chicken: O, shit!
One nuggie came to me!
(Laughs)
There's one nuggie right here!
Okay calling calling upon everything
Chicken: Calling upon God and Anime
(Laughs)
Oh my god
Game, please don't do this to me.
Patty is good
Chicken: Nice
Stop picking up the box
Game, stop picking up the box.
Chicken: The trays are flying everywhere
Chicken: They've gone rogue
They've gone sentient
I hear the fries done so
Oh!
Chicken & Mel: Three star?
Chicken: You gotta be kidding me.
Oh my god!
(ISEGYE IDOL - KIDDING)
♪ You gotta be KIDDING, KIDDING, yes! ♪
♪ ahh yea, ahh yea! ♪
yes, im a little isedol fan >.<
You want to try the next food
Chicken: Sure
Mexican food
Chicken: Ahh yes, I'm sure we won't fuck this one up here
Why do we need to cook the taco shells
Oh wait, whatever.
Oh wow, that's fast.
Chicken: Two chicken tacos.
Where do we get chicken from
Oh...here chicken breast
Mexi chicken bowl
How do you make chicken bowl that's the question
Chicken: I wonder
Chicken: Err, It’s one of everything
That I wonder till this
One of everything?
In a bowl
Chicken: I guess?
Chicken: Oh it's tortilla and all the...
Chicken: It's tortilla, chicken, avocado and tomato.
Okay
Uh... oh wow!
We need to slice things as tortillas as well
This is the weirdest question I've ever ever wanted to ask
Why do we need to cook the chips as well
Chicken: I wonder
Onion
We need to chop them so-
What!?
Chicken: Lmaooo
That much!?
Oh my god this is a shit show
This this requires more people than we think
Chicken: Damn this is crazy
Yep, that's crazy.
(Fire alarm beeps)
Wait what!?
How the fuck!?
These onions cook fast
Game, please.
(Fire alarm beep)
What!?
Okay, so, I think we're not supposed to cook the onions
We're supposed to just drop it in
Chicken: Damn
We're supposed to just drop her in
As-is
I assume this is what makes a-
What makes a taco
This isn't what I ordered
Ah shit...
I remember there's a cookbook
Oh, here it is.
There's a recipe book
Uh...
Chicken taco, 2x cut... raw, cut onion
Oh, chicken has to be diced!
And then taco shells
Okay I get it now
Chicken: Bruh
So dice chick
Okay...
Chicken: Heh, the boxes are out of bounds!
Chicken: Nooo!
Nooo!
Okay I think we got it all figured out
Hold on
Chicken: Do we? DO WE?
Do we?
Chicken: Do we? Good question.
Wait wait wait!
There's a cookbook though
Here here here here!
Look at this
We got a cookbook here
That teaches us how to cook
(Ironmouse noises)
(Laughs)
Chicken: Nice
I'm sorry, Mousey.
Okay
Okay, I think we figured it out now.
I think we figured it out now
You want to try again?
Chicken: Sure
All right
Oh we got we got loot boxes
Chicken: Loot boxes, nice.
Octo hat
Chicken: Monocle
Like...
Oh yes~ Good taste, sir~
Is there... "Browse servers" Hold on, how...
Oh my God, there's servers.
Chicken: Find game > Browse servers
Chicken: Lmao
There's servers
I'll-
How about you do the cooking this time?
Just like-
We'll just alternate positions every time
Chicken: Hm, alright
Like last time I was doing the cooking
And you were doing the prepping so
The rest is raw
Chicken: Holy shit
(Giggles)
What just happened?
Chicken: Holy shit
Chicken: Everything's flying away
Oh
Chicken: Bonk, bonk.
Did you hear that?
(Frying pan bonks)
Oh, sheet.
Beef taco
Tasty
Alright, everyone loves a chicken
(Shelby's Legendary Shawarma)
Yasser Ali: I love bobbing za bubbles!
Chicken: Incredible food!
Chicken & Eddy Wally: Wow!
Wow
Chicken: Why is there cooked chicken in the sink?
(Laughs) I wonder
Chicken: Who is responsible for zis?
(Giggles)
Taco taco
Wait, hold on, what is this ground beef doing here?
Chicken: I wonder
Fuck the pan
If it cooks on grill, we'll do that.
Never mind
Chicken: It just burns
It burns it
Okay never mind then
Chicken: Where is ze onion? There it is.
It's flying out.
(Giggles)
Chicken: Everything's going to shit.
Chicken
Chicken: Chicken taco
Oh shit hold on
Don't worry about it, don't worry about it.
It'll be fine.
Chicken: I'm worrying about it
Beef
Beef (Laughs)
It'll be fine
Chicken: Omg, hahahaha
It’ll be fine
Chicken: It's a shit show
Chicken: Where's the tomato slice? WHERE IS THE (unintelligible).
(Giggles)
Chicken: TOMATO SLICE!
Tomatoes!!
Here
Chicken: One is missing
Chop them
Chicken: Where's the sliced tomato?
Here
Out of time
Chicken: God damn it
Chicken & Mel: Zero stars!?
Chicken: We're so good at this game
I know right
We're too good at this game
Chicken: We earned $25.
My god
Holy shit
Do you think Mexican food is just-
Um...
Chicken: It's a nightmare
A very stressful one
Very needy of players
Chicken: That one definitely needs four players
Yep
Right, on to the next one.
Chicken & Mel: Sandwiches
Chicken: Oh boy
Simmone's sandwiches
Let's see what we can do with the sandwiches
Let's look at the ingredients
Uhh...
Chicken: Ah, it's by the beach
Oh my god
Chicken club sandwiches
Chicken: Holy fuck.
Cooked bread slice
Chicken: Holy fuck
Raw cheese
Cooked bacon
Chicken: Holy fuck
Raw tomato
Cooked breast
Chicken: Three tuna slice, fried cucumber.
Oh my god
That is ridiculously needy
Chicken: Two ham, cheese
The chef will need to rem-
No, the prepper will have to remember a lot.
Chicken: Damn, son.
A lot...
Let's cook the bread beforehand
Let's get the bread done
Chicken: Where the humans at?
Chicken: Where the HOOMANS at?
Chicken: Okay...
Oh my god
Please, game.
That way it's easier
Oh my god.
Chicken: WTF, how does that even happen?
What's even going on there anymore?
We'll put the knife here so it'll be easier for you
Nevermind
Uhh... psh!
(Giggles)
Chicken: Oh my god
Those noises
Chicken: Chicken club sandwich
Chicken: Holy shit
Club
♪ The club can't even handle me right now ♪
Chicken
Another chicken
Oh my god
We're just face planting every time
Chicken: “This isn't what I ordered” fuck you
(Giggles)
Chicken: Ham and cheese
Ham and cheese
Hammond
(Giggles)
Clarkson & Mel: Hammond
Chicken: Bruh the timer is... The name is overlapping the timer
(Giggles)
I feel like the fast food restaurant
and the burger restaurant was for us
The fast food and the burger restaurants for us
Chicken: I wonder.
Chicken: What the fuck!
Why can't we dump shit from the box?
I feel like this really needs a lot of people
Chicken: Yeah
Chicken: It's crazy
This is one of those where it actually needs a lot of people
Under this crazy cramped space
Chicken: Y'know, this would be so much easier in real life.
Yeah, it would be way easier in real life, honestly.
Even if it's one-handed, it'll be easier in real life still.
Chicken: Indeed
Hey hey hey hey hey
Hey
Get out.
There we go
Chicken: Wha... it burns SO FAST!
(Giggles)
Chicken: It burned faster than my future
(Laughs)
When your future is in shambles
Ham and cheese
Yeah, we this will definitely need a whole lot of people.
Also the floor is burning
My god...
(Steam achievement)
"Put out 50 fires", yes.
Chicken: God damn it, IT’S FLYING EVERYWHERE!
(Giggles)
Chicken: We've already failed man, heheheh.
Yep, we absolutely failed.
Wait the customer satisfaction is still okay though
There's no bad face on the on the word though
Chicken: Oh, it's a sad face now.
Okay, that's when we probably lost.
Oh, thanks for driving off.
Haven't even took the cucumber and they drove off already, god damn it.
We got all in control.
Chicken: Do we?
No
Chicken: This is absolutely terrible
Chaos
Oh shit
Chicken:God damn it!
(Mel laughs)
Chicken: We ain't getting anything out.
Wait, there's a cooked chicken breast here.
Oh.
Chicken: God damn it.
Hey, one star.  We got something.
Chicken: One star.
Chicken: Yeah, but we still lost money.
(Laughs)
Okay, you want to try the next one?
Chicken: Sure
Issac's Ice Cream Shop.
Chicken: Nice. Surely this one's easy.
Yeah, this one says 1-2 person though so.
I think we should do fine.
I think we'll do fine
Chicken: Oh, it even says the number of players required? God damn it.
Yeah, it does say so.
Coffee and strawberry
You got the wrong...
Chicken: Is that it?
...you gave him chocolate.
Chicken: Never mind, I'll do the left side, you do the right side.
Okay. Uh, your spoon's over there, way over there.
Chicken: God damn it.
Raspberry
Rasp
(Chicken Disco)
Hello
"Can't wait to eat this"
(Laugh) That worked.
Chicken: Heheh, magic, magic.
Chicken: Why are they not coming to the left side?
Blueberry
Chicken: I'm free.
Blueberry and vanilla...
You know what?
Hold on
Yeah, we do that.
Oh, you double layered it.
Chicken: I didn't know how you put it on.
They're all lining up in one- Oh, there's the other side.
But he's not coming forward
Bro, are you okay?
Oh well, someone just cut in line.
So we just serve it like that?
Chicken: Hehahah, I gave him an ice cream-less cone!
Chicken: Let's go
Uh, we're out of cone.
Chicken: Yeah.
Can't I just spoonfeed you the ice cream?
(Laughs)
I think the fast food service is for us
Chicken: Some cones are left behind!
Okay, we'll put the cones on the sides.
Like this
Chocolate
I'll just chuck them into the...
I'll just chuck them into the freezer.
Then, we'll grab them when we need them.
How far are you throwing these things?
Chicken: Heh, wee~!
Chicken: Oh, help help!
Chicken: The truck is sending me away! Arghh!
Wait! The ice cream!
They're going out of bounds. (Laughs)
The ice creams are going out of bounds.
Okay, vanilla.
We will need a refill for that-
Excuse me!
Actually, I'll come back to you.
Actually, now think about it.
I think it would be...
more optimized if you do it alone.
Chicken: Yeap.
When we run out of materials, I'll swap them out.
Chicken: But how do you take them OFF the cone?
Uh, right click.
Owh, hahaha.
Oh, vanilla's out.
Okay, let me just chuck in a new vanilla.
Wait
I have a vanilla over there
Right there
Now just chuck it in like that
Wow okay
That worked
Okay
Let's see...
Chicken: Wow...
Whoa, okay.
Chicken: Wow, incredible.
That's way better.
Chicken: The Ice cream is for us.
Chicken: Ice cream business (is) for us.
Yup
You want to try that again?
Chicken: Sure
All right
Hold on
There's more other...
There's more other stuff that you...
But they all require DLCs
Chicken: How much do they cost?
I don't know but we'll check them after the video
(Yeap, it's expensive. I'm not European)
(Vine boom)
What do you want to do this time for real?
Chicken: I don't know.
Hot dogs maybe?
And then
Wait, "cook off"?
Chicken: Cook-off? Ough.
"Compete against each other for coins"
Oh.
Chicken: Nice. What do the coins do?
I wonder
Let's figure out how cook off works actually.
"Waiting for players"
Chicken: We're just competing.
Yup
Right, how do we check?
How do we check the orders?
Hamburger
Okay, so we have to remember what everything is.
Shit
I'm glad we have went through this whole thing.
Glad, we went through company training.
Ha
"You served your 1. dish"
Okay, hot dogs next.
Oh, there's no such thing as.
Chicken: God damn it, it's flying away.
There's no such thing as dirty dishes
That's good news
There's no cleaning involved.
Is there a cookbook?
There's no cookbook, that sucks.
Third dish
Hot dog
Chicken: Bruh, it's flying away.
Chicken: Where'd it go?
Chicken: Huhh?
Chicken: Bruh
The good news is there's no cleaning involved
And the other good news, is that you don't even need to stack these things.
Just serve them.
Chicken: Oh, nevermind.
Ayyyy
I can't do it because it's not letting me do it.
Oh, loot boxes
Chicken: I'm getting scammed.
Midpart
Chicken: How dare you, you got bias.
Pshh...
Round spectacles, okay.
Chicken: Black sneakers and aviators
Rainbow rounds, oh wow. Okay.
Chicken: Iron hat.
Black sneakers, okay.
Chicken: Midpart.
Right, let's dress up.
Okay
I like to look the goofiest
The absolute goofiest
All right let's try out any other modes
See if it's there...
There's free play
Where there's no objectives
But I don't think we'll ever want to do that.
Chicken: Hmm...
So we'll just do another cook off then.
Let's try that again
Chicken: What about One Armed Robber(y)?
Maybe for another video
Chicken: Ahh, I see.
Hamburger
Hambagah
Chicken: I'm not in yet.
Wait, what?
Chicken: For some reason.
Wait, what the?
Okay, let's go back to the main menu.
This game bugged out.
Chicken: Bruh.
That is so weird
Alright.
Chicken: Bruh. Let's go!
Let's go
Are we in? Okay, good.
Chicken: Nice.
Hot dog
Ooh.
Nice
Chicken: Nice, another hot dog.
Nice.
Cheeseburger
Holy shit
Get sliced
Oh, nice.
Chicken: Eyy, let's go!
GG.
Oh
Chicken: It's quite short though.
Yeah, it is quite short.
Catering jobs
Chicken: There's no...
Wait, what?
Wait, hold on.
This is- Wait, hold on.
This is a...
(Gasp)
This is career mode.
Hold on!
Chicken: And you can do it in multiplayer?
Yeah, you can play it on multiplayer.
Holy shit.
Chicken: Nice.
Chicken: Let's go.
Let's go
Oh, you can buy new recipes and stuff.
Okay so we start...
We start off with hot dogs.
Chicken: Fast feet, Rapid Rinse (Power-ups)
Serve 10 customers...
Chicken: We're broke.
While getting 10 out of 10...
Without dropping any food on the floor
Don't drop any food on the floor
Okay, gotcha.
Chicken: Nice, *instantly drops food on the floor*.
Pssh...
Nope, we're not gonna do that.
Okay, hot dogs.
Uhh, normal hot dogs only.
So we only need to make normal hot dogs.
So, I think we're good.
(Windows XP Error)
Fatal error, crashed.
Awh...
Chicken: God damn it
Okay
Honestly, this game is filled with content.
Despite being free.
Chicken: There's also paid content.
Yea,but free on its own is actually really really good.
Okay, so...
Chicken: Ough, six hotdogs.
Yeah, just six hot dogs.
So I'm going to cook exactly only six hot dogs.
Try not to touch the pan at all.
There's only one pan.
Which is quite a pity.
No, we dropped what...
We dropped the food on the floor.
Chicken: Your fault, not mine. Hehehe.
No, it flew out.
Okay so I think...
I think I figured it out
Hold on, let's try that again.
Let's try that again
Chicken: You failure! (Pan bonks)
(Mel laughs)
Chicken: Heh, *bonk*.
I figured (laughs)
That bonk
That last second bonk
I figured it out now
Oh, new challenge.
Without dropping any food on the floor
Without starting any fires
We'll do one-
Absolutely one pair at a time
So that we don't make it fly like crazy.
Don't take that meat off.
Chicken: But it's on the stove
What do you mean, it's on the pan.
Chicken: No, the pan flew away (in my POV).
Heh? Where did it go?
Whoa
It looks fine for me though
No
Ahh, we dropped it.
Chicken: *stab stab stab* heheheh.
(Mel laughs)
We have to keep clicking new challenges for that.
Okay, 11 customers,
We have to get 10 out of 10...
From every customer
Wait what, satisfaction?
No dropping food on the floor.
Okay
The stove for my POV is fine.
So don't get any...
Don't take anything off of me
(Windows XP Error)
Chicken: Oh, fatal error.
Ah, dang it.
This game can sometimes be a little frustrating.
Chicken: Yep
Okay, I'm gonna do the...
I'm gonna do the cooking.
And then you do the prepping.
Chicken: Alright
No!
Chicken: God damn it, it flew away.
(Mel laughs)
Let's try that again.
Chicken: God damn it.
(Mel laughs again)
Chicken: Cringe.
Chicken: All that for $22.
Mr.Krabs hired us
Simple to say
Chicken: On my screen, the pan is on the floor.
Nope, it's fine.
The pan's fine.
I'm gonna put the...
I'm gonna put the bun in...
Clear of of any knives.
To make sure that that it's not crazy.
We're just working like factory robots now
Chicken: Yep.
Woah... (breathes heavily)
Chicken: You almost dropped something?!?!
Almost
I grabbed the pan.
The pan was almost going crazy.
Chicken: Only one more.
There's only one left
No!
Chicken: God damn it.
God damn it!
(Mel hitting her desk)
Chicken: Hehe, the very last one.
(laughs) FUCK!
Chicken: Bro...
Remember, no rushing.
Oh, this is stress inducing.
Chicken: Hehe.
This is truly stress inducing.
(Chicken & Mel laughing, losing it.)
We had to like watch each other's steps
To make sure we don't fuck this up.
Chicken: Slow and steady now.
Yes, steady.
Just steady~
Just keep it real steady.
Why is that...
Chicken: Wooh!
I was wondering why the-
Why was the bread floating midair.
Is this the last one?
Chicken: 'Right.
Chicken: I think so.
Chicken: Let's gooooo.
Yesh!!!
Yes!
Chicken: LET'S GOOOOO!
Finally~
Oh my god.
Chicken: TWENTY DOLLARS!
Chicken: LET'S GO! TWENTY DOLLARS!
Twenty dollars.
Chicken: LET'S GOOOO!
Wait, 10 dollars.
Chicken: My share, zero dollars.
Oh my god, we share that?
Chicken: We shared 0 dollars.
Wait, why is dropping food...
Why is dropping food on red?
What happened?
Chicken: Who knows.
Oh, we need 25 dollars to unlock the new location.
So we have to keep repeating that...
Until we get it.
We got spare ingredients.
Eyy, max reviews.
(In the tune of Queen - Don't Stop Me Now)
Don't stop believing~
Cut the fucking hotdogs.
We're burning them fries~
Wait, actually I don't know what I'm talking about.
I also don't.
Don't stop believing
We-
I believe
I believe we can do this.
I will show you the power of believing.
(Reference)
Cyanide: Why do you not believe?
Cyanide: I will show you the power of believing.
Cyanide: I believe I'm going to kill this man.
(Cyanide misses catastrophically)
Cyanide: No!
(Womble laughs)
(Thank you SovietWomble for making genuine memories.)
Prep that
Serve it
Chicken: Nice.
Ayy
Chicken: Let's go.
No
(Chicken laughs)
Oh, that was a close one.
Chicken: The light flashed before your eyes. Hehe.
(Mel laughs)
My entire life flashed before my eyes
NO!!!
Nani??
Chicken: What did you do???
(Mel screams in agony)
Chicken: What did you dooo???
The pan flew!
Chicken: What did you doooo???
(Mel slams her desk)
Chicken: What did you doooo?
We were so close to passing the challenge
Chicken: You are cringe.
Okay, that's fine.
Because we have unlocked a new recipe.
We've unlocked the hamburger.
Oh my god, I don't want to do this.
No, fuck you.
Let's do this instead
I don't want to do the challenge.
It's actually stressful.
It's stressing me the fuck out.
Chicken: It's cringe.
It's actually-
It's actually stressing me the fuck out
Wait, hold on.
I forgot to invite you
Holy crap.
Chicken: I know.
Chicken: I'm still waiting.
Okay, here you go.
The pay is $63 for 9 hamburgers.
Chicken: Wow, an upgrade.
Yep, a significant one too.
I have figured out ways to optimize this...
the usage of this pan.
Chicken: Fatal error.
Ahh
Denny's diner
Chicken: Multiplayer catering is so broken.
The proper multiplayer is better by a long shot.
Chicken: Yeap.
Chicken: Yeap
Yes
Touch my face with it.
Chicken: Bruh.
Very the nice.
It's a salmonella simulator
Chicken: Bruh.
Chicken: Where (are) da buns?!?!
It'll be fine.
Oh, shit!
That's fine.
Chicken: Stick it in the sink!
Chicken: The sink is burning!
God damn it.
It's fine, we're not doing the challenges.
Chicken: More flying away!
♪ Fly away, fly away~ ♪
Chicken: Where's the patty?
Chicken: Oh, it's there.
Patty~
I think this would actually be a perfect vtuber collab game.
Chicken: I guess so
Because of the insane chaos
that ensues in this kitchen.
Chicken: It's insanity.
Truly one...
Truly one of the games of all time.
Chicken: One more, only one more.
One bun
We don't even need to...
Chicken: Let's go~
Let's go
Chicken: Just throw them all in a plate.
Yush.
Oh my god
Just because we're playing together it means that the pay is split
Wait, you can upgrade the stoves as well.
Oh, power-ups.
Fast feet.
I think we can grind them off-camera or whenever we feel like it.
Because this is really grindy, this game.
Chicken: Indeed.
Yep, so you want to have a last...
Actually, you know what, let's go to the browse servers
and let's see who we can raid.
Chicken: I see.
Let's go to wine... "winecrooked".
Oh, they're gonna have a cook-off
winecrooked: play?
Yes
Chicken: nYes
Chicken: No la, just sit here and stare at this guy.
Let's see if they...
Chicken: Moment of silence.
Let's see if they're gonna actually play.
Chicken: Oh.
Oh my god
Chicken: "Freddy's fried chicken"
I'll get them nuggies down
There's voice chat, by the way.
Chicken: Nice.
And there's text chat.
What the fuck is going on with the physics!
The physics went ape shit.
Yes mawi, go, put it in.
You can do this.
That's right, in you go.
I'll prep the patties.
Which should be here.
Okay, patties are good.
Whatever the noise is, it's bothering me.
And getting me concerned as well.
I'm also wondering. Someone fappin', or something?
Oh my god.
These nuggies wouldn't budge.
Chicken: It's flying all over the place!
I know what it is.
I know what's making that noise.
The food tray.
The food tray colliding against each other.
Chicken: Damn, that's pretty gay.
Yep
No, why.
Chicken: Holy shit!
Don't collide with me god damn it
Chicken: On my screen, you're the one who went in front of me.
What the fuck.
So yeah, we have proven that the fried chicken service is actually...
Actually best played with four people.
Chicken: Yeah. All of them are best played with four people.
We haven't...
We don't even know who the fuck these two others are.
Chicken: Chicken nuggies
(In the tune of Bacon Pancakes from Adventure Time)
♪ Chicken nuggies, making chicken nuggies ♪
♪ Take the frozen nuggies and throw it in the fryer ♪
♪ Chicken nuggie, that's what's gonna make chicken nuggies~ ♪
Has anyone seen the knife?
Oh, I found the knife, I found the knife.
I found the knife.
I found it, I found it, I found it.
Chicken: Nice.
Okay, I'll leave it here.
Chicken: Holy shit...
Get to work, get to work, get to work.
One, two...
I went from cook to being the server.
We have to put the nuggets in the general area.
Some things are going crazy so please don't stack anything at all.
Don't stack the cook ingredients under any circumstances.
Oh, come on.
Chicken: God damn it.
A whole set of nuggies too.
What a waste.
Chicken: God damn it.
Chicken: Is this just gonna go on until we run out of business?
Yep
Chicken: Do we make an absolute mess of ourselves?
Do we wanna not cook at all and see how they react to this?
Chicken: Lmao.
It'll be funny if we just leave them, you know.
Chicken: Welp, let's see.
What if we just buy like all nuggets and just make us run our business that way?
and just make us run our business that way?
Chicken: Damn.
Holy, you can only buy a limited amount of them.
God damn it
Chicken: At a time?
Yep
Oh my god.
The nuggets are going all over the place.
In the box.
Chicken: We need more nuggies!
Nuggies are all on the floors
Chicken: WE NEED MOAR NUGGIES, NUGGIES!!!
The nuggies are all on the floor!
mawi stop stealing the damn fucking box!
It's going all over the place.
That will do...
That will do-
Please move out of the way.
Do you understand what latency means?
Chicken: Hehe, (mockingly) nope.
Okay
Oh, there we go.
Chicken: Finally, one star.
One star.
All that for one star.
Chicken: God damn it.
My god.
Chicken: We are so bad.
Indeed.
I can't even see the chat from here.
What is going on?
'Right
I've left.
Phew.
Let's open up some more boxes.
Chicken: Loot box. What's in it?
Pink shorts.
That's it?
Chicken: Balaclava. Holy shit.
Nice
So, what have we learned from this game?
Chicken: It's clunky.
Yes
However, it's free.
Roblox announcer & Chicken: It's free!!!
Though, it is quite fun, I gotta be honest.
If you're playing with the right person, just like Overcooked.
So...
Chicken: Yeap.
Yeap.
So, if you do want to check it out.
Do check it out in the description below.
And... this is my first ever gameplay video
that is recorded and not on stream.
So, I hope you enjoyed it.
And I guess I'll see you next time
See ya~
Bye bye.
Chicken: Buh-bye~
Chicken: Bye!
SOSIG!