(Aqours - Thrilling One Way)
Takami Chika: We want to shine!
(Watashitachi kagayakitai!)
Chika: -iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiine!!!
Mel: AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAA.
(lmao)
OG Love Live! fans, tell me you know this meme!
Tell me you know that reference earlier.
Oh shoot, dang it.
roger_von: Is is the one with the
"Motto motto motto" looping?
No, not that one.
Phoenix_Rain: Is  the meme you're talking about
Chika yelling about everyone wanting to shine?
Yeah, where she gone super saiyan.
That meme where she gone super saiyan.
(imitates Chika) We want to SHI-
(Watashitachi kagayakit-)
(imitates Saiyan Chika)-IIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIII
(-AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAA)
Just kept going until that (stutters) brief guitar moment.
That meme, it was just so hilarious.
Phoenix: I never saw-
Mel: Hold on!
You're missing out! Hold on, you're missing out!
(Typing) Thrilling... One Way...
Here we go, this one.
(Aqours - Thrilling One Way)
Chika: Watashitachi kagayakit-
(We want to sh-)
-AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAA
(-IIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIII)
(Mel loses it)
(Guitar solo)
(Mel loses it all)
Still gets me. >~<
(Mel's gone)
It still gets me!
(Yep, we lost Mel.)
roger: Riko got second-hand embarassment lol.
Oh yeah, I just saw.
And then Ruby got a moment of just playing the guitar.
Yeah, I know right. That was the greatest meme I've ever enjoyed
coming from this song.
(laughs & coughs)
Phoenix: I really like that comic that they turned
into a YT video
with that Nozomi and Eli song.
Phoenix: I got a kick out of that, hahahah.
Wait, what? What do you mean by that?
Wait what?
roger_von: Was it the "Gay or European"?
Wait, what? (laughs) What?
*Phoenix sent the link*
Ahh, that felt awfully familiar by that thumbnail though, holy.
Right...
Hmm...
Ah?
(Eli & Nozomi - Garasu no Hanazono / Garden of Glass suddenly plays)
Wah oh! Oh that's so...
Okay, that shocked me, holy crap.
(laughs)
Dayum. (laughs)
Uheheh.
Hehehe.
Uheheh hehe.
Dheheheh.
Dheheheh. Damn.
(laughs)
Oh, boy.
Ah? Aheheheh.
Ahoho?
Alright.
Hmmm? (laughs)
Heheheheh~
Ohohoh.
Oh my god, the level of yuri-ness.
Hihihih.
Oh my god.
Ho! (sucks tongue) (breathes out)
*Yuri excitement*
Fuwaaaaaaaahhhhhh~ Uhihi!
Ho!
(Breathes narrowly)
(Mel goes chimpanzee)
It's that- Uhehehe!
Oh, god. (Breathes heavily)
God, I love yu- I love yuri contexts a lot
and this is just top notch. (breathes in) Wah!
Hwah!
Wah!
(loses it)
I thought- (laughs)
(loses breath) (laughs even more)
Uweh!
*Yuri panic*
(Breathes heavily)
(calms down)
*Even more yuri panic*
(calms down again... only to...)
*Too much yuri panic*
Ohoho.
(Soft laugh)
Oh my god, I'm just... (laughs)
I- hihih.
(yuri panic breaths)
I love this.
I love this so much.
Oh my god, I'm a-
As a Yuri lover, this makes me wiggle so god damn much.
I don't care all the content is. It's the story that matters.
*Yuri panic*
I'm so sorry.
I'm going really nuts right now.
(excitement)
Okay
(Breathes)
You know what, you know what, no. I'm-
Save, create new playlist, private playlist.
"Absolute masterpiece"
(laughs)
You know what, you're making me want to play this song right now.
Let's go, let's fucking go.
Where is it? [Ga]... (searching)
Garasu no Hanazono doko?
(Where is the "Garden of Glass"?)
Doko, doko, doko...
I'm going really really slow, in hopes that I'll be able to see it.
Garasu no Hanazono
(Garden of Glass)
Yep, I- (stutters)
My eyes was kind of blind for a second. Heheh.
I had to double-check the YouTube video because
the YouTube video had a content ID detection so
I could see the spelling of the name there.
Hold on.
I want to create a brand new team and just
"Sort by", "µ's"
Oh wait, there's another Nozomi here.
Oh, there's another Eli here.
(laughs)
Oh, there's another Eli!
(laughs loudly)
We're slowly going to form a lesbian team at this point, holy fuck.
Oh, there's another Nozomi right here!
Is there any other Nozomi?
Any- There is!
(More laughs)
Phoenix: Oh my, what switch have I set off?
(laughs)
Oh, there's another Eli!
Come on, one more Eli, one more Eli.
Just one more Eli, damn it! There is...
We're just one Eli off, we're just missing one Eli.
(screams in agony)
(laughs)
Is it alright if I put someone random to fill up the space?
Who do you think I should put, who do you think I should put?
Nico, right.
Hehehe, here we go.
(Breathes in then laughs) Oh my god.
Wait, hold on. I got a- I got a funny idea. Hold on.
We're gonna swap positions between this two.
Swap this and...
Where's the other... swap this.
Ey, look at that!
We got- heheheh.
We got Eli surrounded by two SR Nozomis
(laughs)
Oh my god. (laughs)
What if I started? Hehe.
(calms down)
Oh my god, let's go!
Well better, we surrounded Eli.
Hehe.
I'm laughing so much.
My hands are not gonna be focusing at all.
This is bad.
Oh shoot.
Nope, we're restarting, we're restarting, we're restarting.
There's no way I'm letting this off.
Oh, what the shoot?
Oh shoot, dang it.
Ahhhhhh, okay.
(Slaps face)
Okay.
Relax, my hand is shaking right now.
My hand is like shivering.
Heh.
Let's go.
Holy crap
Let's go
We got it.
Oh, that was pain.
That was painful.
(calms down)
We got it, we got it, we got it, we got it, we got it.
Oh my god.
That meme was good, seriously.
I mean, not meme. That animation.
Serious, serious shit, I gotta be honest.
That's some good stuff. (Sound fades off)
Thanks for watching!
Be sure to check out my other videos!