(Bed, pillows rustling, fluffing)
(Wakes up, deep breaths)
What's wrong?
Can't fall asleep?
Hmm...
(Stretches)
Here you go~ (brushes your head)
There there, there there~ (continues brushing your head)
(more head brushing)
Still can't fall asleep?
Hmm...
Oh, I got just the idea.
Lemme just get my phone real quick.
(Reaches over you for my phone)
Come on in, closer to me.
(You scooch a little closer)
I'll whisper you a song.
See if you can fall asleep from it.
(Lightly taps your head)
You want that?
Great.
Here you go...
Shikanoko nokonoko koshitantan.
(My Deer Friend Nokotan.)
Shikanoko nokonoko koshitantan. (Nun!)
(My Deer Friend Nokotan [Noots!])
(Vocalizing instrumental melody)
(EN Translate from Jamong & Genius)
Shikanoko tokotoko, arawaru nokonoko
(The deer walked slowly, it appeared with a carefree mood)
Tsuno tsuno pyoko pyoko, mitamewa onya no ko?
(It's antlers moving here and there, it looks like a girl?)
Chikagoro uwasa no nakanaka kiwamono
(That's quite a strange thing to hear these days)
Otenami ikahodo, henachoko?
(Are you as bad as you think you are?)
Sugoku mukashi kara Japan ni seisoku
(She has lived in Japan since ancient times)
Shika senbei nara mugen ni kudasai!
(If it's deer crackers, please give me infinite amount!)
Tonakai wa nakama, kamoshika wa ushika.
(Reindeers are elks, antelopes are cows.)
Demo demo, matomete guuteimoku.
(But all together, they are even-toed ungulates.)
Nun no suteppu de odorou
(Let's dance with the Nun Step)
Yo ga akeru made (One, two three)
(Until the night is over [One, two, three])
Nando datte hansuu shite nu-nu-nun
(Ruminate over and over again nu-nu-nun)
Yosoku fukanou shikairo deizu
(Unpredictable deer-colored days)
Abangyarudo de oorai, kaosu mashi mashi
(Avant-garde, all right, more chaos)
Itsu no ma ni kuse ni natte nu-nu-nun
(It's becoming an addiction nu-nu-nun)
Hacha de mecha na shikairo deizu
(Crazy and chaotic deer-colored days)
Hatenkou bacchi, come on!
(Super outrageous, come on!)
Nandemo ari, ruuru nante nashi.
(Anything goes, no rules)
Kimi no egao de genki mantan
(Your smile fills me up with energy)
Moshi kashite unmei no ma, ma, my deer!
(Maybe it's fate, my deer!)
Kokoro no dokoka de koshi tantan
(Somewhere in my heart, I am still aiming for you)
Kimi to nara itsu made mo
(If it is with you, I'll always be with you)
Shikanoko nokonoko koshitantan.
(My Deer Friend Nokotan.)
(giggles)
Sleep well (brushes your head)
(Lightly taps your head)
(scritches your head)
You're still not asleep yet?
Oh no...
Do you want another round of it?
Shikanoko nokonoko koshitantan.
(My Deer Friend Nokotan.)
(You fall asleep)
(Thanks for listening to my shitpost XD)