Mel is now...
A "Partner" (Affiliate) of...
Proton (AG), Privacy by default
Wait
You mean like Proton...
The "Privacy by Default" company?
You mean the Proton that runs Proton Mail,
the email service that protects your privacy?
Like the Proton Mail that has no ads or trackers?
You mean the Proton that runs Proton VPN?
The No-Logs VPN and peer-to-peer file sharing friendly servers?
The Proton that's got Proton Drive
with end-to-end encryption and zero access?
And Proton Pass with encrypted passwords,
dark web monitoring, and authentication?
You, sir, must be on to some serious shit right now.
That's right, I applied for a partnership
and got approved to be a Proton partner.
So what does this mean for future videos?
Well, it doesn't do much, brutally honest.
But I do need more ways to support myself,
and the good part is,
Proton can't influence my reviews on products.
That means, I can be honest about what I think about the products,
all while promoting and you guys supporting me
through affiliate links.
And speaking of affiliate links,
vvv Down here vvv
you can check out all the links in the description below.
If you do support me through those affiliate links,
like Throne, you'll be eligible to access to my membership
as a thanks from your's truly for financially supporting.
As for the elephant in the room in the world of YouTubing,
"will the promotion be in all videos?"
No.
I'm choosing not to put Proton promos
if the main topic of the video
is unrelated to any of Proton products,
and I will put the Proton promotions
hopefully whenever appropriate in the video instead.
And most or all videos in the description too,
but not too high up in the description,
probably on the lower side.
I know people are bound to skip if they're not interested,
and if it gets annoying, believe me, I do that a lot too.
So that's pretty much all I want to talk about,
there's not really much change,
and it's gonna be in the upcoming devlog,
but I wanted to make this video
just so I can put all the Proton affiliate links out
so you guys can support me as soon as possible.
And I've pretty much delayed this announcement for way too long,
because I've actually got my approval on June,
Approximate approval date:
Mon, Jun 2 6:41am
Hehehaha
and guess what day it is today?
Filming date:
2025 August 27th
Hehehehe
But yeah, I've been real busy at work,
and there's gonna be a pretty heavily scripted video
incoming for the next video,
so I hope you guys look forward to it.
So this means pretty long delay for this upcoming video,
and I hope you enjoy that video.
But nonetheless, with that said, thank you all so much for watching,
and I hope you guys continue to support me through any means,
be it Ko-Fi, Throne, YouTube, and now Proton.
And I'll see you guys in the next video.
Take care~!
Woo~!
[Ko-fi]
StickTV
Xandra~
Robi
Natalie
Want to translate for Mel?
Check out the desc for link!
MeloriTensei
転性メロリ
Thank you so much
for watching!
Thanks for
supporting me
financially!
[YouTube]
Robi Kivi
Survil 321
Tessaract
veryslowgirl
My hand can't reach you guys.
Just... pretend I'm covering...
Pretend I'm covering the camera!
Cut!
Ooh, frick!
So much happened today.
Marques Brownlee revealed that Apple has
Marques Brownlee
@MKBHD
Apple September Event invites have officially gone out
Awe dropping.
Please join us in person for
a special Apple Event at the
Steve Jobs Theater
in Apple Park.
September 9, 2025
10:00 a.m.
Pacific (Daylight) Time
Please note invitations
are nontransferable.
RSVP
pushed out the email for the Apple event.
And I've installed the Japanese version of Uma Musume
just so I can get Still In Love.
Still In Love
VA: Miyashita Saki
That's pretty much it.
Thanks Proton!
Ehehe