Oh look, a new toy to mess around with.
Kon-Melo, it's ya Tech Wizardess girl, MeloriTensei.
And this right here is an 8BitDo Ultimate Bluetooth Controller.
Now, I'm gonna make it clear that I've taken money out of my own pocket
and spent 0% of the donator's money on this thing.
Primarily because I believe this should not be a donation goal
and rather more of something that I should take care of myself.
So let me set this scenario for you.
But first, we're gonna get this out of the way for now.
So if you've watched my live tab and watched me game on some games,
and you may notice that I'll be playing with a controller,
like particularly HoloCure and HoloXBreak,
then you might notice that I am playing with a very certain controller.
That's primarily because I'm playing with this PlayStation controller.
This right here is a PlayStation 4 controller,
particularly of the CUH-ZCT2G.
While this controller has been a great service for me for 6 years straight,
unfortunately, there was a point of time where
the battery of this controller bloated.
And following that, the left stick starts drifting,
like dramatic drifting.
So like when I pushed forward,
what came out on the screen was a dramatic wiggling like this.
So I thought to myself,
maybe I should get to fixing it eventually.
So what I did is I scoured around in my inventory
to see if there's any spares.
And sure enough, I do.
And this thing is the same model.
However, there's something a little different when I dismantled it.
A little more on that in a bit.
So what's so bad about this controller that prevents me from using it?
That's because I like the red color more than the black.
Like it's a lot more color vibrant.
There's a little more contrast to this, to the buttons, to the…
to the chassis.
And I'm kind of fond of this controller.
And also this little numbing is a little fucked.
Look at this disgusting piece of shit.
God damn it.
What have…
What have they done to you?
Or what have I done to you?
So I thought to myself,
well,
the potentiometer in the analog sticks here are not drifting.
And I don't want to spend money on soldering irons and learning how to solder and shit.
Primarily because I don't really have that much of that time.
And I don't really have much disposable income to mess around with these things just yet.
So if you would like to financially support me,
please check out my Ko-fi in the description below.
So I thought,
let's just do a board swap and the parts swap.
Maybe we could…
probably swap things here and there,
considering how these two are the same second generation controllers.
So swapping went really fine.
It was pretty fine because a lot of things were really more or less the same.
Until I was about to close this controller.
So what I realized is that,
is that in this controller,
this red controller right here,
when upon closing it,
there was like two notches that goes right through the PCB of the controller.
(Within CUH-ZCT2 , there's varying model iterations.)
I didn't realize that was a thing because on this black controller,
(I couldn't find images for what I'm looking for.)
there wasn't a notch.
So when I moved that over,
I couldn't close it and I couldn't figure out for the life of me
for 20 whole minutes straight.
And after I saw some damages to the PCB,
well, fortunately, no cracks, just a little bit of white strain, I guess.
So when you strain the PCB, the plastic stretches a little,
that kind of white strain.
So when I saw a little markings over there,
I realized that,
oh, there was notches on the sides because this chassis has notches.
So,
with absolutely no choice,
I thought to myself,
let's just snip it off.
So I snipped it off and it closes kind of fine,
depending on who you talk to,
because for some people,
this gap is a little horrendous.
But hey,
it still clicks.
It doesn't drift and it plays just fine.
I'm not complaining.
However,
on the subject of controller drifts,
I thought to myself,
well,
both of these controllers are more or less the same age.
It's just one is a little more worn than the other.
So I thought,
I figured considering that they're potentiometers,
they might drift as well.
So I thought,
let's just have a complete reset of a new device.
So we won't have to worry about anything else,
like the already loose micro USB port in the back.
So I went to a place that is not AliExpress,
but if anything, similar to AliExpress and through my trusty suppliers,
I have procured myself an 8BitDo Ultimate Bluetooth controller.
The reason why I said "similar to AliExpress" is because
AliExpress has these things where you have coupons and shopping credits.
And in Asian markets,
they tend to have something like these a lot.
So I took advantage of the shopping credit system and grinded to living hell.
And I gotta be honest,
I may or may not be a psychopath
because I brought down the cost of this 8BitDo controller
down to the price of what you would get out of a 2C in MSRP.
You heard me right.
I bought this at the price of 2C.
So, I was pretty much banging on savings and...
I didn't lose too much money.
So I guess that's a big W.
Right. What makes me pick this controller, however?
Well, a lot of the games are XInput compatible.
So I thought to myself, I don't have to deal with DS4Windows anymore.
And as for the layout, the Xbox layout versus the PlayStation layout,
despite being an Asian who is very used to the PlayStation layout,
I couldn't really care less
because I've actually played with an Xbox controller before,
particularly the Xbox One controller.
The one before the Bluetooth revision
So I think it was like 1709 or something like that.
(I was so god damn off)
17 something.
I don't quite remember.
It is the one before the Bluetooth.
(It is 1537)
So I was pretty accustomed to the Xbox layout regardless, nonetheless.
So I have less of that worry.
But what really sold me is the possible longevity because of these things.
These sticks are Hall effect,
which could mean that there is no friction and no direct contact
to the receivers, which means there is little to no wear on the sticks,
which makes it last far longer.
This is definitely one of the selling points.
However, another one is particularly of it having Bluetooth.
So I'm the kind of person who likes to have things on compatible everything.
So like it has to be compatible with a phone.
It has to be compatible with every other things that supports controller as well.
I don't like it to be single purposed.
Because of the money I paid for.
So there we have it.
And 2.4 is a big plus because this means lesser latency than Bluetooth.
So Yipee, I guess.
Well, USB, uh, I won't be using USB as much anyways,
but it can be good if we're running into radio interference.
Hey, that's a big plus.
Regardless, we got a charging dock.
That's just cool.
And out of the box, it has a Windows mode and Switch mode.
So Windows mode basically just means XInput.
So like A, B, X, Y, instead of what it currently shows on the picture, which is a Nintendo switch mode.
So on the print, it's going to be on switch by default,
but you can switch digitally those inputs through their Ultimate Software.
You can save this key binds into the memory as well.
So you won't have to deal with them ever again on other devices.
So that's a big plus 8BitDo.
So let's get right into it.
Ergh, it's a little hard to open it with gloves.
I gotta be honest.
Okay.
Ooh, it's got that slow release like Apple iPhones.
Ooh, check that out.
It's the controller itself.
What's that?
Oh, it's the dock.
No, my bad.
I'm sorry.
I completely forgot about that.
Let's get the controller out of the way first.
We'll get to you in a moment.
And right here we have a charging dock.
Wha- I wonder what's it's power rating.
I'll figure it out later because this might be a bit of a concern for myself
because I have a USB hub that is powered, but I'm not sure how much power it needs.
Right here we got the owner's manual, a type A to type C cable.
All right, let's open up the manuals real quick.
Oh no.
This is that type of manual that a certain YouTuber hates.
Wade: Oh no.
(The Certain YouTuber)
Wade: Is this a roadmap?
(Credit: DankPods)
Wade: Oh no.
Wade: (Wheeze) Ha, ha ha ha, ha!
Wade: I loathe these manuals! Heheh.
Wade: Where do I begin?!
How am I supposed to read this on camera?
What the heck?
You know what? I'm just going to show you screenshots of that in a PDF.
Switch system needs to be 3.0.0 or above.
NFC scanning, IR camera, HD rumble, notification LED are not supported.
Okay.
Not, not of my concern because I don't have a Nintendo Switch.
[Bluetooth connection.]
Hold the pair button for three seconds to enter its pairing mode.
LED starts to blink rapidly.
This is required for the very first time only.
Then go to your Switch homepage, click on controllers,
then click on change grip/order.
Status LED becomes solid when the connection is successful.
[Wireless connection.]
OTG cable is required for the Switch Lite.
Oh, never heard of something like this for the Switch Lite.
Oh wait, I'm looking at the Switch section.
So if I go down here, there's a, there's a Windows section.
Requires system Windows 10 1903 or above.
Okay.
Connect the receiver.
Turn on the mode.
Press the home button to turn on the controller.
Wait till the controller is successfully recognized by your Windows device to play.
[Turbo function.]
Star button equals the screenshot by default when it's connected to the Switch.
You can change this in the 8BitDo Ultimate software.
Wonder what the turbo of the button really does aside from that on the Windows mode.
[Battery indicator.]
22 hours of play time with 1000 milliamp built-in battery pack.
Rechargeable with two to three hours of charging time.
Low battery - Red LED blinks.
Charging - Red stays solid.
Fully charged - Red turns off.
[Charging dock status.]
White is charging.
White solid is charging.
Fully charged - White is off.
Charging time with the controller on the dock is the same as charging via USB cable.
I see.
[Ultimate software.]
Press the profile switch button to switch between three profiles.
The profile indicator will not light up using default setting.
It gives you elite control over every piece of controller.
Customize button mapping.
Adjust stick and trigger sensitivity.
Vibration control.
And create micros with any button combination.
Please visit support.8BitDo.com for the application.
All right.
I'll look into that in a moment.
First up.
I need to get this out of the way.
This is a nightmare.
Like behind the camera.
I am suffering trying to not ruin this user's manual
because of how difficult it is to try to fold it back up,
especially how large it is.
Let's have a look at the dock.
But first we could get this out of the way.
So we got the dock with its protective film in there.
Okay.
We got three prongs and a USB-C port behind.
There's a little hatch down here.
Let's have a look.
Oh, wow.
That is ingenious.
I like that.
They put the dongle in there
so you don't have to waste another space in the plastic for that.
Except it's a little difficult for someone with a pair of gloves.
I've got to use my fingernail for this.
Oh, this is bad.
There we go.
How adorable.
The thing looks like brick.
So you could not only just plug it to a USB hub.
You could also put it in the dock.
So, it would become a receiver itself.
So that means theoretically there's a USB passthrough in the dock
while it does the charging at the same time, which is kind of awesome.
I got to be honest.
So we're going to keep that in there
or no, we're going to keep it out because I'm not planning to use the dock just yet.
I'm still thinking of a perfect spot to put the dock.
So we'll take care of that later.
Right, let's have a look at the back.
See what I got here.
It may be a little difficult to see, but it says 8BitDo charging dock for Ultimate Controllers.
Input DC 5 volts, 0.5 amps or 500 miliamps.
So it takes half an amp.
So that's interesting.
And in theory, it should not have issues with my charging hub then.
Right.
Let's get that out of the way and enter the big guy.
Right, let's get into this.
Ooh.
Clean looking.
You know, the entire build kind of reminds me the reminiscent to some Xbox controllers,
like a more modern third party Xbox controllers.
And it's pretty much that.
It has the weight of it, the feel of it, just not the stick of it.
The stick feels more like it dimples outwards instead of dips in,
which is what usually Xbox first party controllers are like.
The buttons feel really solid.
If anything, a little more...
thocky than clicky compared to the Xbox One controller.
It's more thocky.
Oh, there's a there's a little more deeper thock on the stick click than the Xbox controller as well.
In case you're wondering what's with the slimy sounds,
that's primarily just because we still got the protective film for the face buttons.
I'm not planning to take that off.
Screw you, Linus.
I'm not a peeler.
I'll, I'll only peel it off when it comes off naturally.
I gotta be honest.
The click of this is a little more.
Well, it still has the high notes of the Xbox controller,
but with a little hint of deep thock, which is interesting.
So there's an LED, there's a USB and this assumes to be a pair button.
But what are these two notches for?
I wonder.
Okay.
The minus, star and the plus button are very solid.
It has this high note of click, clickery.
It feels really satisfying, really solid.
It doesn't feel sluggish.
So, like, even if you try to press on the edge, it feels more center balanced.
I wouldn't call it stabilized because it's not there yet, but it's almost there.
The stick hitting the chassis sounds deep in the sense that it feels like the PlayStation 4 controller.
I've not experienced with the DualSense yet,
so I can't really judge with DualSense in comparison.
Right...
Ooh, I'm constantly pressing these two buttons in the back.
There are two buttons that were called "Pro buttons" or something like that by them.
It feels like a general button, like a low profile button that you would click.
But you might end up accidentally misclicking into it
because of the because of the existence of those buttons.
If you're someone of a gripper like me, that might be a slight problem
and you might want to rebind those somewhere else or maybe just unbind it outright.
But I'll think about it.
Oh, okay.
This is where it kind of fell off a bit.
Let me just let me have you here.
This like this.
This is a little...
Yeah um, the shoulder buttons are a little bit sloppy.
It was fine.
It was solid overall, but the shoulder buttons were a little weird sounding.
But then when you get to the trigger buttons, it feels solid again.
So what went wrong on the shoulder buttons, I wonder?
We'll see.
Okay, let's connect the controller and let's see what we have to deal with.
ERGH!
Right, sitting right here and from a distance,
I could see blue flashing LEDs and I can't really tell what they are.
It looks interesting, though.
We did get a new device indication.
So let's find out what they are.
Okay, so I found absolutely nothing.
Well, it's pretty obvious because the controller is not even on to begin with.
So let's turn it on.
Oh, that sounds interesting to me.
Let's have a double look.
Oh, would you look at that?
An Xbox 360 controller for Windows.
So they are using hardware level emulation?
It seems like it.
It seems like it that it's happening on the hardware level on the USB stick itself.
The adapter or something like that,
especially when you hear a disconnection, then a reconnection immediately after.
I think that might be the case.
Honestly, that sounds interesting.
Oh, surprisingly, it recognizes the name of the controller properly as well.
Okay, let's have a look.
Okay, the axis, stick.
It looks pretty circular.
I got to be honest.
What about this end?
Well, I can't tell about that one.
Then all the buttons.
Wonder what the middle star button actually does.
'Coz it doesn't flash around here.
Point of view hat, okay.
Face buttons.
The rear buttons don't do a thing either.
Okay.
Let's see what else can we get out of this thing?
Okay, so I have went up to Hardware Tester
on this gamepad tester page to see how this is like.
So, interestingly, they have emulated pretty much everything.
And the buttons are pretty much as binaryly digital as they can.
And then a couple of analog.
I did see a little bit of, like if you look at where the dot is at,
it's going in and out, waving in and out a little bit as I was going around the circle.
Same could be said here as well.
So I think there might be a bit of room of error here.
But, yeah.
But we'll see about the errors in a moment.
Okay.
Right, let's do a circularity test.
Spin joystick slowly to test.
Here we go.
I'm gonna make sure that it doesn't slip out of my hand.
Especially I'm wearing a glove.
Let's have a second pass.
Just to make sure that the errors we're seeing are consistent.
Right, let's do the other one.
Woah.
Oh, that's a pretty high number.
Oh, never mind.
It solved itself.
Ah, that looks very consistent.
So guys, if you think this is okay, please let me know in the comments below.
I'm not too familiar with the circularity test and what parameters are the best.
But if you think this is awesome or good, please let me know.
I'm not too sure if 8.1 is a good or a bad just yet.
But I gotta be honest, just looking at the chart alone,
it looks very consistent.
It looked like it's pretty much expected out of factory.
Right.
We got more things to mess around with.
So let's head on to 8BitDo's website.
Oh, hey, it's the Ultimate 2C.
What an irony.
And we head down to support.
And supposedly, according to instructions, we're supposed to get the Ultimate software
right here.
And presumably it wants us to state which controller we're using.
So, in this case, it will be the ultimate Bluetooth controller.
8BitDo Ultimate Software.
Available on Windows, Google Play, and iOS App Store.
Okay, that's pretty cool.
Can I do the configuration for the controller with the 8BitDo Ultimate software on PC when
it's on Bluetooth connection?
No, you can't.
You can only do it for the controller with 8BitDo Ultimate software on PC
when it's on 2.4 wireless or wired.
What does the star button do on a controller?
The star button is for turbo activation button on the default setting.
You can change the function to auto,
Swap buttons or remap it to other buttons on the controller. Huh.
How many groups of custom profiles can be saved in the controller?
It can be saved three groups of custom profile for each connection mode.
Okay, that sounds interesting.
Now I'm going to insert a little bit piece of information here.
I've actually opened this controller beforehand to do some testings for warranty purposes.
And I've also found that
while you can't configure the controller in Bluetooth mode for PC,
you can however do it on the mobile through Bluetooth mode.
So I think they should clarify on that a little bit.
But regardless, let's continue with that.
So I have not experience on the Windows side, the PC side,
but I have experience on the mobile side.
But I'm not going to talk too much about that just yet.
Let's download the software real quick.
And oh boy, what is this 8BitDo Ultimate software?
Oh, oh, that's an interesting sound.
And also it doesn't install.
It just runs portable.
Okay, interesting.
That's actually pretty good for people who want to carry the software around with them.
That's big props for you, 8BitDo.
Holy crap.
Right, so we're going to go to Windows mode, I guess.
So as you can see, I have already set my first profile to be called Xbox.
And that's pretty much it actually.
But you could save way more profiles so you can try to mess around with other profiles
while you're at it.
And you can still do your test right here,
like as in how much you want to set for the dead zones and stuff like that,
followed by the same thing you could do with the triggers as well.
And as for how much in vibration you liked it to be.
So according to the imagery, the big vibrator is on the left
and the smaller ones on the right.
So like the lighter one.
And you can set some macros, which I got to be honest, is a pretty cool idea, but I'll
need a lot more time to actually get used to macros
if I want to set some macros for some other games.
Because I've lived a society of no macro for a very, very long time,
so I can't really say much about that.
But this is where you change the controls and you will see that that B has been set
to A just like an Xbox because naturally it's A, B, X, Y for controller,
whereas it's, it's a Y, X, B, A for, for switch.
So it holds, so it's a whole different story, I guess.
But regardless, I won't really be looking at the, at the face buttons as much anyways.
So I think it's not too big of an issue.
However, I kind of do wish that 8BitDo gives us an option to
probably remove, pop off the front plate-
face plate, and maybe swap the sides, you know, for, for the A, B, X, Y to give it more
Xbox default front facing, especially when it does XInput for PCs.
But I think that's a pretty good touch.
Do you want to change to a different platform?
Yes.
So this is for the switch mode.
And as you can see, I have also preset two different profiles.
So we got the Xbox profile and then we got the switch profile.
So in case you're wondering.
What's with the Xbox profile in switch mode, that's primarily because here's a little downside.
Um, I read this up on an article and I'm going to put it on screen right here.
That XInput only works on wired and 2.4 wireless.
So if you want to play on Bluetooth, it would be in switch mode,
which means the buttons are swapped.
So if you want to bring back the Xbox mapping,
you would have to save it in the profile with those changed back to the usual Xbox.
But it's nothing that we can't do.
As long as the software is still around
and it doesn't rely on being online.
I think it would be perfectly fine.
The same could be said for a very specific motherfucker of my tech household.
Welcome back Galaxy Note 10+.
So before we take care of that, let's gracefully turn off the software and everything,
but we're going to have a good look at this.
Controller firmware v1.0.3.
You can do device tests.
That sounds interesting.
Oh, okay.
So that's how it means. Okay.
So you can see the buttons.
Oh, you can't see.
You can't see if it registers the back buttons.
A bit though.
I think you're missing something a little, you know?
Oh, you need to press the triggers for it to show up.
But even so it's not registering.
Maybe it's because I'm on the switch mode.
So let's swap back to the Xbox mode.
Oh, there we go.
And the face buttons behave correctly as well.
Okay.
Interesting.
Right.
Oh, you can calibrate the device and reset the factory settings,
which I'm not planning to do so.
You can also get beta builds.
That's interesting.
You can do beta firmware updates or something like that.
That sounds interesting, but good to see that 8BitDo has done quite an effort to,
to make it very, very usable.
So I'm proud of you, 8BitDo.
Right.
Let's get onto the Bluetooth part of things.
But first, how do we turn this off?
Do we press and hold this button?
Oh, pressing and holding turns it off.
Good to see.
The same could be said for the PlayStation 4 controller,
but you have to press it for a whole lot longer.
Right.
Let's get onto the Bluetooth mode.
But first we gotta unplug the 2.4 wireless though.
We don't want some accidentals.
Right.
So to switch to Bluetooth mode in the back, you would see two different switches.
One's got a icon of a Bluetooth, another that just says 2.4G.
So what do you have to do is just switch them like this.
Just flick the toggle and now it's on Bluetooth mode.
Now currently it's paired to my daily driving iPhone,
but instead what I would like to do is to re-pair it to this beauty of a phone
that is known as the Galaxy Note 10 Plus.
First up, we get to Bluetooth mode and I'm going to turn the controller on.
By default, it would be searching for a device, but so to, to re-pair it,
we press and hold the pair button.
So it starts flashing like this.
And now we just have to go to pair new device and we'll find a Pro controller.
And once you're done pairing, we're off to the races.
It works out of the box.
Right.
There is one more thing we still have to take care of.
We gotta install the 8BitDo Ultimate Software.
Allow the Ultimate Software to find and connect to relative position of nearby devices.
This would be necessary to get the device into configuration mode of some sort.
Click to use the 8BitDo Ultimate Software.
Well, it's flashing now.
I wonder if it's actually doing the job.
You mean click the screen?
Oh, oh, oh, we're in.
So it's the same as the PC counterpart, it's asking us Windows and switch.
Oh, there's button mapping and more settings.
Yeah, it visually looks more or less the same.
I gotta be honest.
I can't really complain much about that.
It's pretty good, actually.
Yeah, feels more or less the same as the PC counterpart.
But just more.
More portable, I guess.
Well, good to see about that.
Right, let's try out Zenless Zone Zero.
Let's see how well it performs with this controller.
Maybe I have to switch that manually.
Oh, we got controller mode.
There we go.
So as you can see, I'm currently on profile one, which is my self-set Xbox profile.
So it's behaving like an Xbox controller somehow in terms of button mapping wise.
Let's try getting into the battle and see how comfortable it is to play with it.
Alright, so I'm gonna pick this...
Yep, this one.
I'm gonna grind this one.
And away we go.
Let's see.
Well, my phone's a little laggy, but to be fair, it's a really old phone,
so I can't really say much about it.
but hey, at least the phone's playable, right?
Ey, not bad.
I gotta say, it's a pretty pleasant experience so far.
Albeit a little bit sticky because of the protective film I'm intentionally leaving on here.
But I gotta be honest, nice click, nice feel to the touch.
It feels really nice.
And it's got that satisfying tactile feeling that is, if anything,
a little bit better than all the previous controllers in the past, like the Xbox 360 and probably
even the Xbox One controller I currently have.
Even that one as well.
So I think this one's like an upgrade to me at this point.
It feels like an Xbox One controller and the PlayStation 4 controller had a baby,
and then this is what it came up to.
A very decent Bluetooth friendly yet Xbox, or even cross-platform actually,
controller that does everything.
So I think it's kind of a worthwhile upgrade for me
that kind of replaces both my Xbox
and PlayStation controllers.
So yea with that said, I'm just gonna wrap it all up right now.
And by the way, be sure to comment, subscribe, like, and press the notification bell
if you like more of my videos.
And if you wanna financially support me, please support me on Ko-fi.
Or in the coming times, you could probably also super thanks or super chat me as well,
which is kind of awesome.
I'm kind of looking forward to this.
I'm getting really, really close to monetization.
I hope YouTube would approve my application by then.
But for now, fingers crossed.
And I hope for a better future for the channel.
With that said, that's it.
OtsuMelo deshita (It's been ya girl Mel).
メリクリ! (Merry Christmas!)
Have a good day!
Have a good night!
Have a good everything.
Have a good, happy holidays everyone.
See ya~.
[Ko-fi] Thank you for supporting me financially!
Members: Jo, Xandra~, StickTV, Aerostatik, Natalie.
[MeloriTensei 転性メロリ] Thank you for watching!
Check out my other contents!