Something's a little different today.
Kon-Melo, it's ya tech wizardess girl, MeloriTensei!
And today, something's a little different.
Something rolled into my mail.
I got a new pair of gloves!
Let's go!
Well, um…
Something feels a little off.
Something feels like…
Hmm…
Something's a little off.
Like…
Hmm…
It's like I've kinda lost myself.
Somewhere in identity.
It's like…
What am I?
Am I really MeloriTensei?
Is this really me?
What am I?
Not just joking!
There's my actual one right here!
So...
I got this new pair of gloves,
initially with the intent to solve touch issues.
So I have to stop using this bloody thing.
But when it rolled into my mail,
I realized that this was a little extra tight.
It was too tight for me.
And it was really uncomfortable.
It was heavily for winter use.
And guess what?
It barely even cost a dollar.
It's like, what, 70 cents or something like that?
So you would expect terrible quality out of that.
And yes, it does make me feel itchy.
I did wash it multiple times.
It ain't leaving.
It's terrible.
It's such a shit glove.
So I'm going to yeet this.
Oh my god, it's so hard to take it off.
Yeet!
Much better.
Anyways,
if you haven't read the title of this video today,
I'm going back to crDroid again.
Like, if you have seen all the past videos I've got,
I'm going like,
freaking PixelOS, crDroid, PixelOS, crDroid,
freaking hell, we're going back to crDroid again.
And this time, I want to do things a little bit different.
So, here, ask yourself,
would you really want to continue using
your current instance of Android
if it's lagging to living hell?
Here, I even got this guy back to demonstrate.
So let me just open up my phone.
You're paying attention, you're seeing this, right?
Right.
Watch.
Erghh…
*DankPods scream*
Oh, the sheer lag!
Like, loading the page is one thing,
because I've got very, very low reception of Wi-Fi.
This scrolling is another thing!
*more DankPods scream*
Okay.
I've had enough.
I've had fucking enough.
I've installed very little apps,
and I'm still facing this kind of problem.
That's it.
Guess who's getting the boot?
Google Services!
So with that, we're going to crDroid without Google Services.
So we're going to be destroying everything on this phone.
Oh my god.
That lag.
So we're going to be destroying everything on this phone,
and we're going to start fresh.
And as always,
ya girl's prepared.
While I work on that,
I'm going to have my moderator, Natalie,
Nat: Hi~
to check on me every once in a while
while I do my work.
Right!
So, without talking much,
without further ado, let's get straight to working on it.
VO MEL: Heya, voiceover Mel here.
This time, I'm going to be presenting this video a tad bit differently.
Considering how much can go wrong in this video,
I decided not to say the steps during filming,
and leave it to the voiceover to do it for me.
We'll start, of course, to shut down the phone.
And put the phone into Odin mode.
Flash the new crDroid recovery...
Until something went wrong on my PC.
Huh?
So Windows occasionally decides to be a goofball
and reset my drivers.
So to fix that, I got Zadig to overwrite to WinUSB
so Heimdall can detect the device properly.
The occasional problem you'll find is that
your phone might have two gadget serials.
So when it doesn't work...
LIVE MEL: Eh...
Okay, maybe it's the other gadget serial.
There's two gadget serials.
VO: And of fucking course, it works.
And now, we restart Odin mode.
LIVE: You know, recently, umm...
I started listening to Linkin Park's latest album.
It's called From Zero.
And I'm starting to take a liking of
this song in the album called
Up From The Bottom.
(Credit: Linkin Park YT, RIP potential monetization)
Because Emily…
Nat: I've not listened to Linkin Park in a long time.
Hmm.
Because Emily is like
really strong.
She feels like
the next generation of Chester Bennington
(Don't @ me, I'm not saying she REPLACES him.)
to an extent.
Nat: Hm. Cool.
She's got that strength.
And Mike Shinoda's back
to being a rapper again.
VO: That aside, something weird happened.
LIVE: Is this lineage recovery?
Or is this cr...?
Mel: I have a hard time believing.
Nat: Looks like Lineage to me.
Yeah, ah, like…
Huh...
Nat: crDroid has like a reddish hue.
Mel: Huh.
You know what's funny?
I got this recovery image
from the crDroid zip itself.
I was checking through
the official page,
the XDA official page,
and they said,
"My mistake, sorry.
You can actually grab the recovery image from ROM Zip
and install.
Previous recovery link was removed."
So I kind of instinctively went and did that.
LIVE: Right.
VO: So without knowing what went wrong,
I continued.
LIVE: Yaaa, yeet~!
Yaaa, yeet~!
VO: I went on the flash like usual.
Very nice.
(*Humming Up From The Bottom*)
God, I really can't shake that song off of my head.
It's such an addicting song.
Nat: Hm.
VO: Until…
LIVE: What?
Nat: Installation aborted? Huh...
SPL downgrade.
Security patch. Uh-huh...
I see.
Mel: Wow.
Truly unbelievable.
How the hell
did that even happen?
Nat: You might need to flash back to
the stock ROM of the Note 10 first and then try again.
Mel: Oh, god damn.
Nat: Yup, that's gonna be a process.
Mel: Oh my god.
VO: And off we go to fetch the stock ROM.
Just to dial the security date back.
LIVE: It's kind of shocking that I remembered
my model off the top of my head.
VO: Get the phone into Odin mode while we're at it.
LIVE: (Imitating) 2000 years later.
VO: Only to realize that
WinUSB drivers don't work with Odin.
LIVE: And this driver is not friendly with Odin.
VO: Just replace it with whatever stock driver that was.
LIVE: Oh, there we go.
VO: Get all the binaries into Odin.
LIVE: There we go.
In theory, this is all we need.
And we'll have to run through the whole thing again.
VO: I dread for this.
LIV:E Ah, here we go.
Nat: Yay, stock rom.
Mel: Gosh darn it.
VO: Go through the setup like usual.
Make sure the OEM unlocking is present.
Because if it isn't,
that means you've not connected to the internet during setup
and activate the phone for flashing.
I got back to Odin mode once again.
Get the driver swapped back to WinUSB.
Flash like I'm supposed to.
Reboot into recovery.
Only to see the stock recovery.
LIVE: What?
Nat: Oh, I think OneUI might have replaced
the recovery when you booted into it.
Mel: Oh...
Nat: Yeah, that happens on Android phones sometimes.
Mel: Well, Samsung, you suck.
Something just crossed my mind for a second.
Why don't I boot into one UI right now?
If you've seen enough cartoons,
you would understand an analogy
I'm going to be doing right now.
Instead of explaining the analogy,
I'm gonna do the action
and see if you understand the analogy.
Nat: Alright, let's see.
(*Boot into stock recovery*)
(*Yeet the entire ROM*)
(*and it's cache partition for good measure*)
(*Power off the phone*)
(*Boot into Odin mode*)
(*Flash the crDroid Recovery*)
(*Without ROM, it'd guaranteed to boot into recovery*)
Boom
Ladies and gentlemen, we got 'em.
Nat: Hooray!
Actually, I wonder if the Lineage recovery
was overriding the crDroid
and that's what's causing the issue in the first place.
Mel: That might very well be, honestly.
VO: And with that out of the way,
let's format the data and clean up.
And flash the CRDroid for real.
Once done, just reboot
since we aren't installing GApps.
Now that crDroid is working, let's set up like usual.
Just as I was going to complete the setup,
the navigation bar popped out
and interrupted the setup.
Eh.
(LIVE Mel laughing)
LIVE: I just mis-
I just mis-tapped.
(It) took me all the way back.
Ha ha ha.
♫Baby, take my hand.♫
♫I would like to be your wife.♫
♫Cause you're my Iron Man.♫
And "we love you 3000."
(Mel laughing)
VO: So I started installing Droid-ify, Aurora, and MicroG.
Because these will be our replacements to Google services.
But for some reason, MicroG wouldn't install through Droid-ify.
So we just got the APKs and installed it that way.
LIVE: Wow, that took long.
Say hi to us on Telegram.
Nice.
Now that we('ve) set up most of what we need,
there's still a few things left.
Customizing.
VO: So I bought an icon pack for no reason
and activated it through MicroG.
LIVE: Booyah.
VO: Got my launcher of choice,
set up a wallpaper.
(LIVE Mel laughing softly)
Nat: What are we laughing about?
Mel: The fact that I'm actually using
these two little nubbings to pinch and zoom.
Nat: Ah, yes.
Mel: One thing that did jump out to me
is that none of the clocks fit this wallpaper.
Nat: Unfortunate.
Mel: I guess we'll make do with that for now.
Oh, you can set them small again.
That's good.
Nat: Yes.
Mel: That's definitely something.
Nat: (It's there since) uhh I think Android 13...
Mel: Doesn't this make it look like more of a Chinese phone kind of vibe?
Nat: Uhh yeah, it reminds me of like early MIUI days.
Mel: For real.
And there I go.
This is my Android phone for this period.
I'll be testing it out and
I'll be secondary daily driving it
and see whether I need Magisk or not.
But for now, I'm pretty satisfied with it.
So I'm going to continue doing all the rest of the setup and...
There is a few steps that did go wrong, but
I'm glad not too much has gone wrong.
And yeah, with that said,
thank you all so much for watching
and be sure to subscribe.
Be sure to check out my Ko-fi if you would like to support me financially.
There's also Throne if you would like to give me some gifts.
If that's kind of your interest.
And also check out my YouTube memberships.
So Throne, Ko-fi, YouTube. They're all the same tier memberships.
You all will get the same type of access of content.
And yeah.
Also be sure to check out my videos tab
if you want more tech videos
and check out the live tab if you want more gaming
and shenanigans.
And time to tangent towards the sponsor of this video.
If you think I'm not going to take that opportunity to do that,
you'll be damn wrong.
So special thanks to SD Maid SE.
It's currently made by a singular person named Darken
and it is one of the greatest Android junk cleaner out there.
"Welcome! SD Maid SE manages file, apps, and storage.
Gain storage space by cleaning up behind other apps.
Delete expendable files and remove leftover data."
So basically junk.
And let's get through the setup as per usual.
(Fast frowarding...)
There we go.
How simple was that?
So at the moment, the free tier of SD Maid SE
only allows you to clean basic amount of app cleaning.
So if you like to go thorough with your app cleaning,
you would like to get the Pro license.
Right. Let's go through some of the settings because
usually I like doing settings.
So I usually like uninstall watcher because
when I uninstall the application,
it will just take charge and clear up after myself.
I usually don't have much to lose
because I usually take my stuff out first before I uninstall them.
So I'm not really that careless.
And… make sure we clean up ourselves very thoroughly.
Right. System stuff.
Superfluous APKs.
Basically, APKs of apps which you already installed
and are just leftovers.
Trashed...
Screenshots... I like to leave that.
Pretty much most of it.
AppCleaner. One of the highlight features out there.
If you like cache yeeted out of your system apps as well.
You can totally turn that on.
And… if you have include inaccessible caches,
that means you allow yourself to turn on accessibility service
and use accessibility service to tap those buttons for you.
And what I mean by those buttons,
if you go into App Info, you go to Storage and Cache
and you click Clear Cache.
That's simple for one app.
But what if you have tens and maybe even hundred...
A hundred apps.
That's gonna drive you fucking crazy, doesn't it?
And this is what makes SD Maid SE super freaking useful.
It does all of that for you automatically.
Well, I wouldn't say fully automatically,
but on your demand automatically.
So it taps those buttons for you.
So you don't have to go crazy for that.
Bug reporting...
I would like to keep game files
because I do play games like Blue Archive.
Offline Cache... It would be very helpful
if I'm using Google Maps or something else.
Recycle Bin... Yeah, you can go.
And… Other chatting apps that I don't ever use.
Right. That looks fine to me...
That looks fine to me.
Right, let's go through each of them.
So what CorpseSFinder does is
when you've uninstalled an application
and there's bound to be shit left over.
So CorpseFinder is basically it.
And getting into SystemCleaner,
it basically clears out stuff in your system like empty folders
that are just there and it looks kind of an OCD mess to you.
Or maybe log files or other kinds of stuff.
And stuff that you have picked in your settings as well.
Like I said earlier, Superfluous APKs
We'll totally be chucking them out of the window.
And then App Cleaner, just like we said.
So caches that are inaccessible
are those that we click using Clear Cache.
And then those that are accessible are
those that SD Maid can reach through its available file access API,
or (known as) Storage Access Framework (SAF).
So when you press Delete, it will do that
and then it will do all of these for you.
Look at how quickly it does this job.
It's insane.
There are bound to be a few (left),
however those can't really be done.
Because if you go into those applications
they don't really have a Clear Cache button
or they have them grayed out.
Primarily because,
if you have turned on Include System Applications
you're bound to find some of these kinds of apps.
So there's really not much you can do with that.
No app can allow you to do that because this is system locked.
But that's perfectly fine.
You're already doing the most
and that's all that important.
But with that said,
that's done.
Eyyy~
"Spotless."
And once again, huge special thanks
to SD Maid SE for helping me out
and reviving my VTubing career
and check him out in the GitHub
or the Google Play link down in the description below.
And with that said,
OtsuMelo deshita (It's been ya girl, Mel).
Take care y'all!
Eek!
Oh! Oh!
Okay.
[Ko-fi] Thank you for supporting me financially!
Members: StickTV, Xandra, Robi, Natalie, Aerostatik
Sponsor: SD Maid SE
[MeloriTensei 転性メロリ] Thank you for watching!
Check out my other contents!
Kon-Melo, it's ya Tech Wizardes-blblyblbleh
(Fumbling words)
Fuck!
Nat: Keep that at the outro.
Mel: Absolutely.
Nat: Just like a little, you know,
behind the scenes fumble.
Mel: Absolutely.
Fucking hell.
Oh wait, I forgot you haven't spoke in that part.
(More bloopers as a members exclusive!)
Nat: Yeah?
Mel: Fuck!
Nat: I was gonna say- (laughs)
Nat: Yeah, I was gonna say, when do I come in?
Mel: Let's just-
Mel: Sorry!
I have to do a retake then. Fuck it.
Nat: All good, all good.
Mel: Oh god...