You were expecting something a little different?
Huh, who could have thought?
You seriously think something is going to be a little different in this very video?
Well, you may be a little right because…
UGH!
It's time for a devlog!
[MeloriTensei 転性メロリ]
Devlog April 2025 - Returning from Hiatus
Ah~ It's been quite a while.
Welcome!
Kon-Melo, it's ya Tech Wizardess girl, MeloriTensei.
And I gotta be honest, I don't really have much planned for this devlog video.
But there is something a little different.
So let's get straight into it.
But first up, as you can tell I'm very unprepared, let me get my script real quick.
One second.
Alright, um, script number one…
No that's not it, that's not it.
That's certainly not it.
Ah yes.
Oh yes, this might be it.
This might not be it.
Oh shit, this may be it.
No this might not be it.
This may be it.
No this might not be it!
(Mel PANIK)
Are we good yet?
Now I'm gonna start off with answering the question,
why the hell am I standing so freaking far away from the camera?
That's primarily because I kinda wanna show you this full body tracker
that I actually used
as opposed to the one that I made about the Slime VR video.
So this one is a little more fully functional
and I can kinda move my elbows around,
though it is a little laggy because of the wifi environment here.
But it is functional, rest assured.
This is what some bits of my own pocket money went to
since the past devlog.
And I gotta be honest, I may be a little bit proud of that,
I may not be a little bit proud of that
because there's occasional yaw
that you might see back in the Beat Saber stream.
Aside from setup upgrades, what do you think?
Do you think this microphone is so much better?
Do you think it sounds way better?
Because I got myself a new microphone.
And I'm not too sure where I'm gonna put the microphone
because currently it's clipped up to my shirt
but I don't think it's actually picking up the best of my voice.
It sounds a little far away from my own monitoring.
And yeah, I think there's more improvements to be done.
Let me show you how it actually sounds when you put it up close.
So it actually sounds far better when you put it up close.
But yeah, once I think of a better place to put the microphone,
I can assure you that this is going to sound way, way, way better.
Now if you've been observant with some of my videos lately,
things have been a little sloppy here and there.
And it's going up, it's going down.
The editing has been a little lackluster.
And the New Year's Eve video was a little rushed.
So with that said, I'm gonna be announcing
that I'm moving away from scheduled videos.
So videos are no longer on schedule.
And I'm gonna be pushing the videos out
however I like, whenever I like.
Albeit with a bit of delay
so that we have Ko-fi members watching it as early access.
However, there is still one scheduled content you can expect from me,
that is weekly streams.
Streams are still going on a weekly basis.
It's just that videos are not weekly anymore.
So you might expect some videos in probably a week,
some videos in a couple of weeks,
some maybe even a month.
I'm not too sure, but
I'm terribly sorry I can't upkeep a weekly scheduled basis
because it's been really heavy for me.
By the time you watch this video, it might very well be April.
And I'm gonna make it clear, this video is recorded during March.
(2025 March 29th)
So you can tell why I've been very struggling
with my upload schedule these days.
So I hope I can bring the quality back up
to what you guys remember of
when I first popped off during the Pixel OS video.
Right, onto the bigger top news.
But first, let me get over there.
So I've been wanting to make my videos
a whole lot more accessible lately.
And I thought to myself, let's start with closed captions.
So you can probably see most of my videos that are public
are now closed captioned by yours truly.
And I realize something's a little not enough.
You can tell that auto-translate is not doing justice
(I did technically typed "they" in English.)
for some of the languages.
(But Auto Translate can't tell the singular form of "they")
So I'm proud to announce that I'm going to be opening up
a GitHub repo specifically for fans to submit translations
to my subtitles and my titles and descriptions.
So anyone, hopefully, can enjoy my videos the way it's intended to.
Now knowing it's a GitHub repository,
things may be a little shaky and a little bit unstable.
So it may be very well unpolished.
So I hope for more cooperation from fellow translators
and we grow as we go.
As time passes.
(Ding dong)
Oh, hold on. Someone's at the door.
Oh, hi.
Yes, yes, yes.
Yes, it's me.
Thank you so much.
(Grunt)
I'll get to you later.
I'm back.
I'm back with something new in the package in the mail.
So I got myself a brand new capture card
so I can record more HDMI content.
So probably a test device
that I can probably test Linux in or something like that.
Or maybe console games or something like that.
That's primarily because my old capture card is insanely old
to the point that it is just so plain freaking bad.
I have driver issues with it.
I've had OBS issues of it.
I've had straight up capturing issues of it.
And check this out on the screen.
This is the starking difference that you'll find
out of between the two capture cards.
So the new capture card that I'm going to be having
is the Elgato Game Capture Neo.
And my old capture card was the AverMedia Live Gamer Portable.
And if you look at the difference,
(After extended recording, the old AverMedia capture card lags)
the compression and the quality,
(Btw, both cards recorded from a splitter in real time)
it's such a stark difference.
So this is another investment out of my own pocket
that I am going to make for MeloriTensei.
Now with investment comes cost cutting.
So I'm moving away from self hosting
and I'm no longer hosting my own page
on a self hosted server called PinCushion that I came up myself.
Of course the base is Linkstack,
but I did call it PinCushion back then.
However, it comes with great sad news
that PinCushion has to go down
because I've not been able to maintain the 99% uptime
that most outside servers can.
In fact, it may very well be 70% or even 60% or 50% downtime,
which is freaking insane.
There's no way you can keep up a website that little
and expect people to check out your links from there.
So I've decided to move back to Carrd
and be back confined with the 50 element limit.
But hey, I tried and I did it.
What do you guys think of the design?
Let me know in the comments.
And on another great news.
Oh, what's this?
Hold on.
Wow, this world is very packed of features.
What the heck?
I didn't think it would be that useful.
Wow.
Check this out.
This is super cool.
You can go...
(Light switch clicks)
Ah, help!
(Light switch clicks again)
(...)
We're good.
I'm sorry.
Here's a little tissue for you guys.
Anyways, jokes aside, um,
fellow donators of Throne and soon to be YouTube members,
stay tuned for an upcoming stream
because I got something a little different for you guys on that stream.
So be sure to keep an eye on
the very specific stream title that you usually find for VTubers.
So with that, we're going to have basic emotes to start out,
and I'm not sure if there'll be member exclusive content
in the future,
but I can assure you that
there isn't much exclusive content to make
to justify just yet.
So you won't find much exclusive content
aside from early access content at the moment.
But if you support me more of that,
we could probably produce something that
normally is not okay to put out on public YouTube,
or you just want something extra out of me
because it's often you, you, you, you, you, the members
that make it happen.
So thank you all so, so, so, so, so much
for making my content creation life less miserable
and allowing me to pull things off like this.
Now I can't really do things like Filian can.
Let me try jumping.
Uagh!
Whoa.
Did that actually... woah!
Okay.
I think I see a potential.
Speaking of something potential, I got something in my room.
I got to grab it real quick.
Oh my God, this room looks a little adorable.
Holy crap. Look at this.
This room's got this thing.
(Intensely breathing)
Okay. Okay.
We got to put it aside.
This is not part of the announcement.
Oh, that was scary.
Right.
Where is it?
Ah, I found it.
Let me just put that on and put this on.
Tell me if you know something is a little different.
Something's a little different?
That's right.
I got myself a new witch hat.
So streams from now on, you'll be able to see this new witch hat.
Guys, check this out.
There's also a new trans badge on my dress as well.
Now it's far easier for people to know that I'm trans.
Now as for justification to
why I'm adding a witch hat and a trans badge on my dress,
that's primarily because
I've realized I'm starting to have some form of identity crisis.
So you've seen the logo on my channel
and my channel description,
and you might have a second to think to yourself.
"Huh..."
"Tech wizardess, but she's not wearing a witch hat."
That's because for quite a long time,
I have not been able to find a witch hat asset
that suits my needs.
One that is easy to rig into without much effort
because I don't really have much time to do it.
And as you can clearly tell, it doesn't really swing or bounce.
It's just attached to my head.
That's pretty much most of what I need, honestly.
It's kind of like an identity thing.
And I've also had people getting mildly irritated
simply because they don't know I'm trans.
And yes, welcome.
I'm Melori Valentine.
I go by she/her pronouns.
And here, I made it very clear.
Very very clear, in fact.
So hopefully this helps me down in the long run.
But yeah.
And speaking of down the long run,
there are two backlog videos that are due to release
someday in the future after this very video.
And also, a secret video incoming.
Stay tuned for that.
I'm not sure when it's going to come out,
but it will come out in distant future.
Don't hold your breath for a few months,
but it will come out when that time is right.
But yeah, with that said,
thank you all so so so so so much for watching.
I'm so so so sorry for this four months long hiatus.
And I've been gone for way too long than anyone's comfortable with.
And I hope there's far less delays in this.
And I hope to make way more content.
Now with new equipment, with new morale,
hopefully, for the new years.
So with that said, it's been a great honor
for me to today say, OtsuMelo deshita. (It's been ya girl Mel)
See ya in the next stream and video.
See ya!
Woo~
[Ko-fi] Thank you for supporting me financially!
Members: Jo, Xandra~, StickTV, Aerostatik, Natalie.
[MeloriTensei 転性メロリ] Thank you for watching!
Check out my other contents!
You still here?
Cool. Hehehe.
Here's something extra.
I screwed up the rigging a little bit.
So my face now makes faces when I point that stuff here,
which is why I don't make hand gestures in this hand on this model.
I made all my hand gestures here because of this reason.
Or I just opened my hands like the Mr. Beast meme.
Announcer: Mr. Beast!!!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry guys. Heheheh
This might be another jankily recorded session,
but I hope you guys don't mind.
See you guys.
Pat pat pat pat pat pat.