Ain't it old?
KonMelo, it's ya Tech Wizardess Girl, MeloriTensei.
And this is a very, very old device.
So let's ask ourselves this old question.
Is this an iPhone?
No, it's not.
So this right here is an iPod Touch 4th generation.
So iPod Touch 4G as we call it in short.
And I had great fond memories with this device,
primarily because this was what introduced me to iOS.
So a little backstory here,
but I don't think you guys will be that interested,
even though you clicked into this video
wanting to know about my history.
Imagine this, PapaMel and MamaMel
wanted to get me a birthday present.
(MamaMel: Honey, what do you think should be our kid's gift this year?)
And they have this very weird (thing)
(PapaMel: Well, he* is very into technology.)
of wanting to get me the coolest thing at the time.
(PapaMel: So, let's get the coolest thing at this time)
However, instead of getting me an iPhone,
they chose to get me an iPod Touch because
it was cheaper than an iPhone.
See, I told you it was quite an unimpressive story.
But nonetheless, the good part about having an iPod Touch is
it's got more or less
the same things that you get out of an iPhone,
just without cellular.
And it does pretty much a lot of stuff that iPhones can,
but without the ability to call
because there's no cellular in there.
Oh, does it start?
Oh, it's dead.
Well, this is what happens when
you don't film a video for four months straight.
Let's get it charged up.
I got myself this really, really old cable.
I got this back when I used to have an iPhone 4S
and surprisingly, it's still with me
and it has yellowed.
God, that was terrible.
Oh, look.
Look, guys.
It's very, very faint, but you can, you guys can see it's charging.
So surprisingly, this thing is alive.
Oh, my God, it turned on that quick.
I'm not even done talking yet.
Hello?
What?
What?!
What the fuck???
I have never seen something like this happen.
Oh, oh, oh, we're going again.
Is it going to turn on? Come on.
I feel like I'm learning from DankPods, just...
clicking my fingers on the, on the device.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Wade.
You influenced me.
Come on.
Wake up.
Wake up!
Okay, let's try not be harsh.
This device is a fa-
What?
No-, NOT AGAIN!
NOT AGAIN!
WHY!!
Okay, let's keep it this way for now.
Who knows it'll turn back on in a-
WE JUST TALKED ABOUT IT!
Okay, let's just continue yapping.
So, a few years after, I also learned about
this very interesting thing called jailbreaking.
It was also when I discovered that tinkering
was very much my favorite thing to do at the time,
and it was fun to solve problems...
Are you dead again?
Yep, you're dead again.
When will you wake up anyways?
Oh, here we go again.
God damn it.
So anyways, I discovered that I love solving problems
that existed either because of limitations
or people just don't feel like programming it into.
So one of my favorite things was,
was I want to play a game that had local network multiplayer.
So I thought maybe I should host my own mini hotspot from this iPod.
But if you think about it, you can only host a hotspot in iOS
when you have cellular connection,
which this iPod does not, but the iPhone does.
So how do I get around solving this problem?
So I found out that there's a tweak that you can use in Cydia,
which is the biggest package manager for jailbreaking in the old days.
Shout out to you guys who remember Cydia.
Also, o7 to Saurik, great work.
You may rest.
Also this thing has been going on and off.
What are you doing?
Okay, I plugged into somewhere better.
Hopefully this boots up this time.
I don't know what's happening with my power supply.
But anyways, I realized that by jailbreaking,
it allows me to install this tweak
and I can do whatever the heck I want.
And that was kind of a weird sense of freedom
to an extent, if you ask me.
And it kind of feels like I've never turned back.
Well, not really.
I did restore multiple times and then I come back to it every time.
And jailbreaking on and off was kind of fun in my opinion.
(iOS 6 charging sound)
Oh...
Oh, it booted!
I heard the charging sound.
Hell yeah, let's go.
(FREEDOM INTENSIFIES, EAGLES, GUNSHOTS)
Ah~
Oh, that felt satisfying.
(Mel processing: ...)
Eyyy, Cydia~.
I will never forget about you, fuck.
Although the servers are dead, but...
(Correction: Not the servers, rather the billing system.)
Who knows? Maybe it will work again.
Let's see.
Well, it's serviceable, I guess.
Well, there may be some, maybe some repos are still up.
Who knows?
Yeah, I would pretty much expect it from the death of Cydia.
(Correction: It ain't dead. What's wrong with you, Past Mel?)
But there seems to be a lot of things that you can still do
on this iPod with Cydia installed.
So truth be told, I don't really regret jailbreaking the old iPod.
Although it is a little stressful
when you're jailbreaking modern phones,
especially with my bank
whom we're going to be calling Omnibus Bank A.
Curse you, Bank A.
If you want more context, check out my Razer phone video.
But that aside, this iPod has been still a very well capable device.
So if you guys want me to do experiment video
for a video idea, please let me know in the comments below
because I will look forward to trying out some stuff,
but make sure it better be interesting,
not just something simple as, oh, changing a theme.
And speaking of changing the theme,
that's my second favorite thing to do after jailbreaking.
So changing themes kind of gave out that new weird sense of vibes.
So for you Android people, imagine changing launchers
and imagine changing icon packs.
That was literally something new,
at least for iOS users back in iOS 4, 5, 6, so forth.
It was kind of a game changer to the iPhones
because iOS was and still is a very restrictive platform.
So, figuring out some of the tweaks and hacks kind of fascinated me,
and it makes me want to do more tweaking to this.
Unfortunately, nowadays, I don't really do that
because my daily driver, iPhone 12 Pro Max,
unfortunately is also my bank mobile,
which means jailbreaking is not really the answer for me anymore.
However, I do sideload, but not for many apps,
just like small things that changes small things.
I don't really want to sideload something massive
that could become catastrophic emotionally
when I accidentally change from Sideloadly to AltStore
to SideStore to Sideloadly again.
But that aside, tangents aside,
this iPod Touch has been very important to me in the past,
primarily because it was my primary entertainment device
before I had those phones that I have mentioned in the past.
And it does pretty much everything.
At the time, if you're wondering what phone I was using,
I was using a Sony Ericsson.
I don't remember which model it is, but..
I'll stick some of the images of some of the Sony Ericsson phones
(W200i, W705, Xperia X10 Mini)
that I used in the past
that I can probably to an extent confirm
that I have indeed used by my memory.
But I was using a Sony Ericsson phone in the past
as my daily driver mobile phone.
That was before the smartphone era, at least for myself.
But the iPod was sort of a transition to smartphones for me,
(Technically the X10Mini is a "smartphone" as it ran Android 2.1)
where I learned to familiarize with a smartphone operating system
(but sentimentally, I didn't think of it as one.)
and understand how smartphones do things differently
from old Java mobile phones.
Like, you interact with what's called applications.
Sure, applications do exist back in Sony Ericsson, Nokia phones,
but the things that it can do on iOS was a lot more than those.
So that was what fascinated me and wanted to discover more,
hence why I wanted to jailbreak at that time.
And the next thing that I wanted to discover was kind of...
sort of weird and interesting. Umm...
So fast forward to a couple of years later,
I got myself an iPad mini,
and you might have seen it in the Slime VR video,
that particular iPad.
So in that iPad, I've done jailbreaking again because
I don't really see the reason why not to.
It was sort of a fun thing for me to play around
and burn my free time and just learning about iOS in general
without restrictions.
And I kind of hit a mini mental roadblock
where I was playing this game called Terraria,
and I thought to myself,
how do I make this experience a whole lot better to myself?
And it turns out some games at the time do support controllers,
but it was kind of a very weird sense of a driver support.
(Credit: ImperfectLion)
It was very half-baked. It was terrible.
It's like it works with Xbox controllers,
and then it doesn't work with any other kinds of controllers.
And that's where jailbreaking kicks in again.
So I've installed a tweak that supported DualShock controllers,
(Not my vid, but the exact illustration. Credit: Co0per)
because at the time, I had a DualShock 3.
So I connected my DualShock 3, and...
and the tweak just kicked in
and pretended to be an Xbox controller.
And boom, I'm off to the races.
Terraria.
I can play with a controller now.
I can just grab a small elastic band and
stick the iPad to the headrest of a car
and just play Terraria there.
Oh, God.
If you have not done that in your past,
what are you doing in your life?
Okay, in all seriousness, well, we live in the age
of people using phone clamps and stuff
and tablet clamps for the headrest
instead of using janky things like using elastics
and just tie it on the headrest like I did.
But to be fair, to be fair, it was something of a fun experience,
especially when you have Asian parents
who refuses to upgrade their car in no matter what circumstances.
Imagine driving a Lada.
Well, not really a Lada.
I'm just putting this as an illustrative purposes.
But you get the analogy.
It's kind of hilarious.
So this iPad and the iPod
had been my source of entertainment that way.
And I gotta be honest,
I had a lot of fun messing around with jailbreaking
and stuff like that.
Another thing that got me discovering the iPod is FaceTime.
Sure, there isn't many Apple users at the time,
but when you do finally FaceTime someone,
it's sort of magical to an extent.
I wouldn't call it magical at a greater scale
because at the time, Skype exists,
RIP Skype, o7.
God... Microsoft.
And we still do call people over Skype at the time,
but FaceTime was sort of...
The hardwareis already there, the software is already there.
You just need to have a friend that have the same set of things
in one package.
And I know I'm doing a little way too much
Apple shilling here and there,
but let's not forget about one interesting thing
that got me to being interested in doing YouTube videos,
the included YouTube app in iOS.
Too bad you don't see them here because they're gone-zo.
So, um, the agreement between YouTube and Apple
kind of died somewhere and the app is no longer included.
And I'm just like, what the hell are they doing?
But nonetheless, I did figure it out that
you can go to the App Store to get the YouTube app.
So, there's that.
Happy ending for me, I guess.
But nonetheless, I was watching YouTube
and, um, as you can tell, I was an iPad kid,
but I could probably even call myself the iPod kid
because I started out on this iPod and
the iPad came way late, way, way, way late.
So this iPod was very much the gateway to the internet for me
because you got Safari, you got App Store, you got the YouTube app
and well, to be fair, nobody uses iMessage
and I mean nobody in my, in my vincity.
I did not get to use iMessage a lot, but hey, at least Skype exists.
I don't remember if Skype...
the Skype app existed during the iPod era,
but I still think of this as like my multimedia entertainment device
because I do use iTunes to stick movies in there.
At least that's what I do in the past.
I don't anymore because there's such things like Files app and VLC.
So things have changed a lot
as opposed to that time of the era
where you do not have access to your own files in the system
or not even have a sandbox of it.
So you do have to put it in the videos section.
Well, currently there's no videos.
Oh well.
But I also do put music in there
and it was kind of an all-in-one thing for me
and I will never forget the great history that the iPod has given me
that led to me taking a liking to tweaking mobile devices
to solve problems.
So if you're new to this channel, hi, I'm Melori Valentine.
I go by she/her,
and I love tweaking stuff to solve problems,
primarily to solve problems.
Not exactly to discover things,
but it does let me discover things at times.
But nonetheless,
if you guys have any interesting stories about the iPod,
please let me know in the comments below
or maybe I don't know,
share some stuff that you do with the iPod back in your days
because I've just talked about what I've done
with my iPod back in my days.
So why don't you?
Otherwise, be sure to like, subscribe, and...
I hope you enjoyed this little story time about this iPod.
And I'm terribly sorry that this video is a very simple video.
I initially had a very big project for a video,
but unfortunately that went catastrophically terrible
and I had to change course.
So hopefully this buys me time to...
solve some of the issues before I...
actually come back and make a video about it.
But yeah, with that said, thank you all so much for watching.
OtsuMelo deshita (It's been ya girl, Mel).
I've got more story times.
So see ya.
Yeet!
[Ko-fi] Thank you for supporting me financially!
Members: Aerostatik, Natalie, Robi, Jo, Xandra~, StickTV
[MeloriTensei 転性メロリ] Thank you for watching!
Check out my other contents!
How the hell are you still alive?
Oh.
Oh~
Oh, that's satisfying.
Holy crap.