This is going to be an ASMR audio and I'll explain in a moment.
Kon-Melo, welcome to the single most riskiest video
that I have ever been wanting to produce.
So I'm gonna put on the screen below when I'm recording this today
and you'll see why it took me stupid long to release this video.
So a little backstory here,
but without revealing too much personal information or
any parts of Mel's private life, the best way I can describe myself is
I got extremely lucky.
So I was able to not ever touch the donators' money on Ko-fi,
check out the links below, and purchase this one thing.
This right here, if you know by the dimensions and by the shape, you
would immediately know
what this is.
But in case you don't know what this is, I'm gonna open it up right now.
This fucking mic.
You're absolutely not mistaken, I got a Steam Deck.
So obviously, out of a Steam Deck,
I would expect the Steam Deck console itself
and the charger because I've watched way too many people unbox this shit.
So it has become really stupid obvious to me.
So let's get into the least impressive one, which is the charger.
Fuck.
It's got this partition thingymajig.
If you're wondering why I'm trying to not speak so loud,
that's primarily because this Steam Deck
is a secret as of the time of recording.
By the time you see this video,
I have pretty much integrated the Steam Deck into my life,
and no one would know that I bought this in a flash.
Now, if you've watched multiple streams of mine,
I have constantly told you that I am Asian.
And I'm not shitting you...
But I still ended up with a European plug.
You know what, I guess I'll have to use an adapter for that.
But to be fair, I live in a country
that does not have a proper official seller for Steam Deck,
so obviously I had to import one from the EU.
Shoutout to European gang.
Gosh darn, there's a sticker.
What the hell am I supposed to open this with?
For legal reasons, I can't whip up my utility knife,
so I got a pair of scissors instead.
(snip snip snip)
If you're wondering why I'm not peeling it off,
that's primarily because I'm wearing a fucking glove.
Fuck.
This is gonna be the most painful unboxing of a Steam Deck
a creator has ever done.
Fuck...
Fucking hell.
Open it up!
Here, here, here, listen to this.
Oh, the sticker finally gave in.
Nice.
Please, I just wanna open.
Fuck it, gloves off.
I'm opening it up instead.
Damn it.
God, using scissors properly is a whole lot easier.
I'm sorry for rage baiting, guys.
All right.
What the hell?
Good day, mate.
Welcome to England.
Well, I guess I really do need an adapter for that.
Fuck.
All right, let's get the console out.
"To avoid danger of suffocation,
keep this plastic bag away from the babies and children.
Do not use this bag in cribs, beds, carriages, or playpens.
This is not a toy."
I wonder where that warning came from.
Oh, they're stuck that way, huh?
Well, that's unique.
(Homelab server ramping up)
Can my Homelab server shut the fuck up.
It's so loud, what the fuck?
Okay, now what do I do?
I should probably slide this off.
Oh.
Oh, it got stuck.
Oh, that's why.
Fuck.
Please.
I beg you.
Door's stuck.
Here it is, the Steam Deck OLED.
Usually, when you watch from other creators,
they always show a top-down view,
making it look like this was printed on.
I kid you not.
It's a little elevated.
It's like it's stamped on or something.
It's kind of textured.
So, pretty cool, I guess.
I've seen a lot of people,
when they first opened their Valve Steam Deck,
they never show the tag.
I don't know what's up with it.
Maybe Valve bans showing it or something.
I don't know.
But there's this security tag that proves that
this Valve Steam Deck has not been tampered with,
which is pretty fucking awesome.
You don't really see that a lot from other boxes or something.
Now begs the question, how do you open it?
Oh, it was that easy.
Security tag's off.
I should probably put the mic in front again.
("Aural bliss")
Oh.
It's the wrong way up.
Wow, would you look at that?
This feels surreal.
Oh, hello.
Hey, camera gang.
So, the volume buttons are here.
Headphone jack.
Type-C.
Power button.
We got the R1, L1.
Oh, the analogs feel...
really nice.
Really, really fucking nice.
So, I gotta be honest with you.
It pretty much feels like...
8BitDo controller when it comes to buttons.
So, I would say A for effort, Valve.
Right, let's boot it up.
Oh.
I felt some vibration.
Woah.
Come on, camera, fucking focus, bruv.
Oh, satisfying.
Damn.
Pacific Standard Time.
Where the fuck am I, California?
You know what?
I guess I'll do the setup off-camera. But...
But there you have it.
That's pretty much the most I can show you at the moment.
Until I finally publish this video,
and then I'll make another video after that.
But nonetheless, thank you so, so, so much for watching.
And I hope you understand what took so long
to publish this very video.
And I guess I'm pretty much enjoying my Steam Deck, I guess.
If you got any questions about how the Steam Deck feels
or whatever that is,
let me know in the comments below.
And as always,
OtsuMelo (Mel-vellous work/Good bye).
Jan ne (See you again).
See ya.
Boom.
[Ko-fi] Thank you for supporting me financially!
Members: StickTV, Xandra~, Robi, Natalie, Aerostatik
[MeloriTensei 転性メロリ] Thank you for watching!
Check out my other contents!