This right here is a HTC Vive controller, completely dismantled.
And this right here is a battery, a brand new one.
KonMelo, it's ya Tech Wizardess girl, MeloriTensei.
And this right here is me trying to reassemble my HTC Vive controller.
So if you haven't read my community post, I had to suspend all of my VR streams,
primarily because the battery was bloating and it was just flat out not safe anymore to work with.
So I had to dispose of that battery and start an emergency funding for the battery.
And thanks to y'all in Ko-fi, check out in the description below, you guys are great and really really awesome.
And by the way, yes, I did fund for both batteries, rest assured guys.
So we're gonna reassemble the entire controller and hopefully they'll all work in one piece and that should be fine.
Fine and dandy.
We're gonna follow the iFixit Toolkit Guide in reverse.
So hopefully we get this done really really quickly and let's just get on with it.
It's gonna be a really short off-the-cuff recording session,
primarily because there is only a single block of battery out of the third that is remaining on this camera.
So I gotta get this job done really really quickly.
But hopefully you guys can enjoy this short little run-and-gun content while I'm still away on hiatus as of the time of recording.
And let's get on with it.
So we got right here an iFixit tray that has already been sorted out by where the position in the controller they are at.
So like the saucers are all on the top and then I don't quite remember, I've already dismantled the controller some time ago.
It's been like probably two weeks at this point.
But hopefully I can still follow the instructions backwards nonetheless.
So let's get on with it.
So we got right here a battery holder and all we have to do is just put it on but I don't remember the order of that.
So I'm just gonna take a look at the image and see how that goes.
Okay, about that.
So what we do is we have them like this.
It's a little hard handling with gloves, huh?
In it goes and we can now rest it on.
We'll reconnect the power later but first we're gonna screw it on.
So they use Torx 5.
Okay.
These guys might need a little bit more force albeit a little bit scary because some of which have thread lockers so they might be a little bit on the tighter end.
Alright, next step.
Phillips.
Okay, this got a little confusing because the instruction says Phillips but unfortunately mine seems to be Torx.
I don't know if I'm in the wrong or something but I'm gonna stick with what I have for layouts.
And according to the guide there was a little metal frame here that was supposed to be protecting the battery connectors but unfortunately for both of my controllers I don't seem to have something like that.
So I'm just gonna screw it down the traditional way with these Torx right here because they're right here according to my own tray map it does seem like they're using Torx instead.
So I'm not too sure if it was the generational difference or something's a little different with my unit but I'm just gonna go vibe with it because in the end of the day as long as you're not breaking anything they kind of still works.
Right, now we're reaching to a point where we need to reattach the battery so because I'm gloved up it might be a little hard to use your fingers to put it down so I'm gonna use my trusty little tool to slide it in and click it in place just like that.
There, it's now resting in place just fine and…
Oh right right right, so this little sticker right here that has been sitting on top of this thing this is what's been holding on the connector this whole time so I'm just gonna reuse it for now just like so.
There isn't really any importance with the tape it's just I don't know it's there because it's there like you can see that there's even those tapes right here.
I don't know what's up with my unit somebody's gotten lazy or something but eh we're gonna vibe with it anyways.
And looking at the instructions now we're gonna need to get the front panel which is this guy right here reconnected so we got one connector down here and then we got one connector up no wait two connectors up here one right here and one right here so we're gonna need to get it connected just as so.
And click that baby right in but just before we click it in let's have a test on the battery power.
Oh we got the sound very nice now let's shut it back down.
Okay good to see that it's functional so let's click it in.
Right now so we click that in we're gonna try to reassemble the saucers.
These guys right here let's put the other battery out of the way and let's get to work.
And there you have it.
We got ourselves a functioning controller.
Well I'm gonna do more tests with the controller in the coming time so we're gonna jump into that time once I'm done with it.
Right we're in SteamVR now and I'm just here to record a very very short clip of that hey it works as you can see.
So like the grip buttons are working the touch are also working the menus are working as you can see, even the menu buttons are working for both devices.
So yeah they're both fully functional, very nice.
Now there is one standing problem however, um, while everything's working like the touchpad everything is working the vibration for this controller somehow stopped working.
So I'm probably gonna work on that and investigate what's going on off camera off video in a future time.
But nonetheless I hope you enjoyed this video and back to the past Mel.
Thanks Mel from VR.
Anyways if you like this video be sure to check out the other type of tech videos that I'll be working.
And be sure to like, comment, subscribe all the yada yada algorithm bada bada stuff.
And if you want more tech videos check out on the videos tab.
If you want to see me play games check out the live tab because I mostly do live streams for games.
So yeah as of the time I'm recording I am currently on hiatus so I'm not sure when I'll be coming back to edit this video.
So this video might be a little extra late and outdated so yeah with that said thank you all so much for watching.
See you guys next time.
OtsuMelo deshita (it's been ya girl, Mel)!
See ya take care.
Weee.
Woo.
[Ko-fi] Thank you for supporting me financially!
Members: Jo, Xandra~, StickTV, Aerostatik, Natalie.
[MeloriTensei 転性メロリ] Thank you for watching!
Check out my other contents!
Wow autofocus please chill.
There's a single block of battery left.
Oh my god.
Okay, let's try to get on with it very quickly.
If that dies I have to bring a phone in to record this.
Hey to those sticking to the end of the video.
I still got one more controller to work with.